<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1210774</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-15T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-01-25T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>TERMS OF REFERENCE FOR AN SHORT TERM CONSULTANT
MULTI-DONOR PROGRAMMATIC TRUST FUND 
FOR EUROPE AND CENTRAL ASIA PUBLIC FINANCE MANAGEMENT (TF071577) 
TERMS OF REFERENCES FOR 
RESULTS ORIENTED MONITORING (ROM) REPORT
Background 
The Multi Donor Programmatic Trust Fund has been initiated by the Ministry of Finance of the Russian Federation (the Donor), as a joint Russia - World Bank program under Russia Public Financial Management Aid for Development Memorandum of Understanding to support strengthening Public Finance Management (PFM) reforms in the Europe and Central Asia (ECA) Region. The main objective of the ECA Programmatic Trust Fund for Public Finance Management (the Trust Fund) is to support improvements in various dimensions of public finance management in ECA countries. The Trust Fund has been designed as a flexible source of financing for technical support to individual countries or groups of countries.  
The MDTF allowed support for activities that contribute to demonstrable improvements in various dimensions of PFM performance through institutional capacity building in an individual country or group of countries under the following thematic areas:
a)	PFM performance assessments,  strategy development, evaluation of strategy implementation;
b)	Improvements in PFM legislation and regulations;
c)	Improvements in methodologies and systems for budget planning and budget preparation (including introduction of MTEFs, program and performance based budgeting, etc.);
d)	Improvements in methodologies and systems for budget execution, accounting and reporting;
e)	Enhancing the efficiency of public spending (including in specific sectors or sub-sectors);
f)	Strengthening efficiency and transparency in public procurement 
g)	Strengthening internal financial control and internal audit; 
h)	Improving external audit and parliamentary oversight;
i)	Improving public investment management;
j)	Developing information systems for public finance management;
k)	Developing sustainable institutional capacity for provision of PFM-related training;
l)	Enhancing revenue collection and administration reforms (including tax and Customs);
m)	Design, implementation and evaluation of fiscal decentralization and sub-national finance reforms;
n)	Management of contingent liabilities.
o)	Treasury systems development and modernization.
The Trust Fund has supported these thematic areas through two windows, a World Bank executed and a recipient executed window. Country level activities were to be recipient executed, but there was a possibility for Bank execution of recipient activities in exceptional circumstances at the request of the government .  Selection of proposals for funding was competitive, based on the extent to which they satisfied the selection criteria established for the two windows and the funds available. 
As of December 2015, US$17,030,534 out of US$18 million has been allocated through five Rounds of Calls for Proposals to 46 activities covering 14 countries in ECA. These include US$ 8.37 million for Bank-executed activities and US $8.66 million for recipient-executed grants and their supervision. By December 2015 seven activities have been fully completed and three activities are substantially complete. 

Objective and Clients
The objective of the assignment is to assess the performance of the Trust Fund, applying the following criteria: effectiveness, relevance, efficiency and sustainability. The assignment will follow the approach of summarizing and validating monitoring data of the project in order to provide evidence for reporting on the progress of the trust fund. The report should provide an overall assessment of the Trust Fund performance, along with relevant explanations and recommendations for quality improvements. 
The work will be performed for the World Bank as Trustee and for the Ministry of Finance of the Russian Federation as the donor responsible for financing the Trust Fund. The final report will be submitted to the World Bank and the Russian MoF.
Scope
The report will cover all active and completed projects funded under ECA PFM TF (TF071577) from the first four rounds of grant approvals. Activities approved in round five (June 2015) will not be included because these are mostly in the start-up phase.  Desk-based evaluation will be undertaken for both active and completed projects. For the projects in-progress potential outcomes and intermediary results will be considered. In addition to the desk based review, results will be confirmed through face to face meetings with beneficiaries in three countries with large concentrations of investment by the Trust Fund. 
Methodology
The review methodology will be based on the ROM Handbook, April 2012 edition, adapted as necessary for a mainly desk based review. The ROM methodology is based on the collection of supporting information about the performance of programs through document research, interviews and site visits. The information is analyzed and conclusions on the performance of the program are made under the five OECD DAC criteria. Specific attention will be given to the points listed in the criteria table produced by the World Bank team in the Annex 1 to this ToR. The methodology may be extended to address other specific performance issues as required by the Donor. 
The ROM assessment will consider the performance of the individual projects. This will be reported in a separate Background Conclusion Sheet (BCS) for each project. A consolidated BCS will be prepared to make an overall assessment at Trust Fund level with a special prioritization on relevance and effectiveness based on the criteria agreed with the Donor. The overall assessment takes into account both the projects visited and those covered through the desk review. The ROM report will focus on Trust Fund level issues and make reference to individual projects in support of its findings.
Under the impact and sustainability criteria, the ROM assessment will specifically consider how useful have these projects been for preparing the ground for bilateral projects (funded by the Donor or World Bank).   
Description of the Assignment
The assignment will comprise the following components:
1.	Desk review of  35 projects funded under the first four rounds of the Trust Fund 
2.	Verification of results by means of interviews and site visits to three countries in the ECA region 
3.	Report development and presentation to World Bank and donors
Desk Review
The Consultant shall obtain an overall understanding of the Trust Fund and of the projects supported from the review of the Rules of Operations, trust fund annual reports, monitoring reports submitted by team leaders, and review of project outputs. Information about the overall program will also be obtained from discussions with the Trust Fund Manager and the Donor (Russian MoF).  
Verification of Results
Results and findings will be verified through interviews with task-teams and field visits to selected countries/projects. Field visits are proposed to the Kyrgyz Republic, Tajikistan and Belarus.  These three countries represent include the two highest priority countries for assistance (Krygyzstan and Tajikistan) and of the largest beneficiaries of the TF (Belarus). The projects will include activities supported through both Window 1 (Bank-executed) and Window 2 (recipient-executed). The field work will consist of the following tasks:
	A review of the available relevant documents for each project to gain an understanding of the wider context and of the intervention logic and indicators for the project and guide preparation of the list of interview questions.  
	In country interviews with key project personnel, and with Project beneficiaries in-country, supplemented by VC, telephone interview or email correspondence as required. 

The projects financed by the Trust Fund in Kyrgyzstan and Belarus are as follows:

Kyrgyzstan

Peer-assisted Learning through TABPAL (P130288)
Improving Management of State Assets (P132920) , including a grant for project supervision
Building Procurement Capacity to achieve development effectiveness (P148998)   
Building Capacity of Local Experts for PTP learning in Budget Practice  (P146809)
Scaling-Up Peer to Peer Learning in Public Finance at the Local Level (P148471)

Tajikistan

Parliamentary Oversight of Public Finance in Tajikistan (P124741)
Improving Public Procurement Outcomes (P133191)
Review of the Government Payroll &amp; HRM (P148130)

Belarus

Fiscal Governance Technical Assistance Program (P143355)
Improving Efficiency and Transparency of the PFM (P147073)

If, for practical reasons, it is not possible to organize visits to all of these countries, a preferred alternative would be Moldova, which is also a low income country with a high concentration of activity and investment. Organization of meetings with officials will be facilitated by the World Bank task teams responsible for the relevant projects.

Report Development

Separate Background Conclusion Sheet (BCS) will be prepared for each project reviewed, after completion of desk based review, interviews and field visits. A consolidated BCS will be prepared to make an overall assessment at Trust Fund level with a special focus on relevance and effectiveness. Note that the BCS does not include recommendations. A separate list of recommendations will be included in the ROM report.

Outputs

The output is a ROM report which will be provided to the Donor and the World Bank. The report will consist of:

	A ROM report summarizing the findings of the fieldwork and the wider comments on the program as a whole. The report includes a grading assessment for the program, overall conclusions and recommendations
	Separate Background Conclusions Sheets (standard pdf documents) for each of the projects for which fieldwork was made. 

Schedule

The assignment will commence in February 2016 with the desk review.

The fieldwork is expected to take place in March-April 2016.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-01-25T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1210774</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>RESULTS ORIENTED MONITORING (ROM) REPORT</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">RU</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Russian Federation</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">412228</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210774</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">412229</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210774</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF099284</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">ECA Programmatic PFM - TF Program Management &amp; Administration Costs</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>