<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1210317</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-14T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-10T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1210317 - STC profiles required for Payments and Digital Finance Projects in EAP &amp; South Asia

Assignment Countries:
  - South East Asian Countries

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The World Bank Group (WBG) provides support to public and private sector institutions to develop payments and related financial infrastructure. Within the context of support for payment systems development in selected south east Asian countries, WBG is assisting banks, payment service providers to improve their offers to individuals and small retailers, corporates and government functions. WBG is also supporting billers such as utilities to improve their organization to benefit from digitization of billing and collection processes.

The main objective of this assignment is to assist selected clients in the assessment of client/user needs, to improve product design, pricing and marketing and contribute thereby to an expansion in the uptake and usage of new payment services.

KEY TASKS OF ASSIGNMENTS:
- Assessment of customer behavior, needs and impact or current usage of payment and financial products; sizing and qualitative categorization of opportunities
- Review, documentation and evaluation of payment providers or billers current products, from the perspective of payer and payee
- Design of short and longer term service improvements, including product features, communications, sales approach, user interface, pricing, et.
- Identification of sector constraints, disincentives or challenges to payment service adoption, including infrastructure, pricing, regulations, competition, etc.
- Support hands-on implementation and training of bank or payment service staff of marketing action plans and product improvements

The WBG is now looking for a pool of candidates who have relevant experience in the field to submit their CVs for upcoming assignments below of the project.
- Client Banks bill payment improvement
- Payroll benefits program, working with payroll banks as well as employers and employees to assess and improve services
- Support Distribution Chain Finance solution implementations 


FUNDING SOURCE

  - TBA

QUALIFICATION CRITERIA
* Experience:
- Minimum 8 years professional experience
- BA in relevant field
- Field experience in / with retail banks in a marketing, sales or product development role; some channel management or payment service provider experience
- Exposure to merchant/retailer or biller processes and organisation

* Skills:
- Communication: ability to communicate concisely to clients and help in the design of effective end user communications and product marketing
- Hands on product, process design and implementation
- Ability to document analysis of requirements
- Ability to evaluate business case and budget for specific marketing and product initiatives

* Countries exposure:
- Middle income market experience (min 2 yrs)
- Minimum 1 year experience in South East Asia
- Based in Asia region


SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS

The World Bank now invites qualified consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must submit a letter of interest and a CV indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Expressions of Interest and CVs should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-10T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1210317</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>STC profiles required for Payment service needs assessment, product design and marketing improvement of the Payments and Digital Finance Projects in EAP &amp; South Asia.</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">411467</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210317</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>