<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1210430</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-14T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-10T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1210430 - STC profiles required for Billing and Accounts Receivable Process Manager - Payments and Digital Finance Projects in EAP &amp; South Asia

Assignment Countries:
  - South East Asia 
ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The World Bank Group (WBG) provides support to public and private sector institutions to develop payments and related financial infrastructure. Within the context of support for the development of payment systems in selected south east Asian countries, WBG is assisting banks and payment service providers to improve their services for supply chain payments and finance operations in retail distribution.

The main objective of this assignment is to assist selected clients to improve their internal processes for billing, supply chain management and client receivables management and assist banks and payment providers in simplifying, minimizing the effort required to implement new services for credit and payment collection.

KEY TASKS OF ASSIGNMENTS:
- Identify operational and process improvements for distributors or other billers to streamline their order to billing to collections &amp; reconciliation process
- Identify key challenges and integration points for implementing Distribution Chain Finance solutions with banking partners
- Support evaluation selection and implementation of solutions with sales, finance and operations departments of distributors and wholesalers
- Design target organisation (roles, processes, controls, systems reqs., metrics, etc.) for credit management operations of distributors in on-to-offline

The WBG is now looking for a pool of candidates who have relevant experience in the field to submit their CVs for potential projects below.
- Support implementation of Distribution Chain Finance solution
- Consumer credit management review and operations design

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - To be advised.

QUALIFICATION CRITERIA
* Areas of expertise:
- a/c receivable exposure management
- Evaluation of client creditworthiness 
- Cash flow management

* Product knowledge:
- Invoice to reconciliation process 
- Creditor exposure management
- Collections

* Business and users expertise:
- Distribution or wholesale industry
- Utilities / large scale billers
- Some consumer / vendor finance experience desirable

* Experience:
- Minimum 8 years professional experience
- BA in relevant field
- Manager in a finance or ops department of distribution company
- Exposure to merchant/retailer or biller processes and organization

* Skills:
- Process design and management
- Accounting and exposure/overdue payment analysis
- Hands on treasury and back office product, process design and implementation
- Ability to document analysis of requirements
- Ability to evaluate business case and budget for process improvements

* Countries exposure:
- Middle income market experience (min 2 years)
- Min 1 year experience in South East Asia
- Based in Asia region

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must submit a letter of interest and a CV indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  
Expressions of Interest and CVs should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2(https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-10T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1210430</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>STC profiles required for Billing and Accounts Receivable Process Manager - Payments and Digital Finance Projects in EAP &amp; South Asia</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">411671</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210430</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>