<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1210195</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-10T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-01-31T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Request for an Expression of Interest by Qualified Firms 
General Information: 
Country: Bangladesh 
Notice: Firms with experience on sanitation marketing mainly on capacity development of small scale private sector on product development and promotion, capacity building of field workers on sanitation marketing, local market promotion and awareness building regarding water and sanitation services in rural Bangladesh.  
Publication date:	
Deadline:	
Buyer:	World Bank Trust Funds
Eligibility of Bidders:	Firms/institutes will be selected in accordance with the procedures set out in the current edition of the World Banks Guidelines: Selection and Employment of Consultants by the World Bank 
Short lists will be established on the basis of previous experience on capacity development of small scale private sector and field workers, community mobilization regarding water and sanitation services, marketing support to small scale entrepreneurs and networking with local leaders. 
Language:	English
Assignment:
The Water and Sanitation Program of the World Bank is seeking to hire a consulting firm with experience on rural sanitation particularly on sanitation marketing  to support a large scale MFI, ASA (a Bengali word, means hope)   for the capacity development of local sanitation entrepreneurs, market promotion and also demand creation among poorer households.  ASA will provide microfinance sanitation loans to local sanitation entrepreneurs to produce and marketing multiple sanitary products and also households to construct hygienic latrines . The firm will also support ASA to orient their field staff on sanitation marketing. 
Recently, WSP has started a new project (Programmatic Technical Assistance) entitled Scaling Up Microfinance Institutions Lending for Improved Rural Sanitation in Bangladesh (MILIS) to assist MFIs in developing a market in improved sanitation products by mainstreaming loans to local sanitation entrepreneurs to expanded commercial operations, as well as to poor rural households to purchase hygienic latrines.
The ultimate objective of this project is to accelerate the movement of rural households from the practice of basic sanitation, to the use of improved sanitation or hygienic sanitation products sold by small-scale private entrepreneurs. The target beneficiaries will be the bottom 40 percent of poor households, particularly in rural communities.  
Interested firms/institutes should provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services.  Skills and experience required as follows:
	Interested firm should provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of capacity development and community mobilization regarding water and sanitation services with special focus on market development.  
	Interested firm should provide information on their core experience and years of relevant experience.
	Interested firm should provide information on the qualifications of key staff 
	Interested firms should have prior work experience in rural Bangladesh with special focus on poor.  
	Interested firms are requested to submit a sample summary report from previous work that demonstrates the capacity to undertake the assignment.

Interested qualified consulting firms are invited to submit their Expressions of Interest in English, by 31 January 2016 by 17:00 hours (Washington time). 
Consulting firms interested in this assignment respond to the Expression of Interest posted through the World Banks E-Consultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html), via External website of the World Bank (www.worldbank.org) and should not contact WB staff members directly. Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-01-31T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1210195</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Technical Assistance (TA) to Scaling Up Microfinance  Institutions Lending for Improved Rural Sanitation in Bangladesh (MILIS)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">BD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Bangladesh</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">411264</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210195</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">411265</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210195</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF093816</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SA CHILD TF FOR WSP GLOBAL CORE MDTF</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50065</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50066</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50067</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50068</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>