<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1210794</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-25T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-11T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

Assignment Title: 1210794 - STC for PPIAF Nairobi Office

Background/General Information

The Public-Private Infrastructure Advisory Facility (PPIAF) is a multi-donor trust fund that provides technical assistance (TA) to governments in developing countries in support of the enabling environment conducive to private investment, including the necessary policies, laws, regulations, institutions, and capacity. It supports governments and sub-national entities in priority infrastructure sectors energy, transport and water. PPIAF mobilizes annually US$20 million in technical assistance with a strong focus on low income countries and Sub-Saharan Africa. 

PPIAF is staffed (currently approximately 20 people) and managed by the World Bank on behalf of its 15 Donors who provide all of the funding. It is part of the World Banks Public Private Partnership Cross Cutting Solution Area (PPP CCSA) and the facilitys Program Management Unit (PMU) is based in Washington, DC. For more information about PPIAF, please visit www.ppiaf.org  

The STC works in support of the PPIAF office based in in Nairobi that covers the following countries in East &amp; southern Africa and Middle East and North Africa.  The STC will be supervised by the Regional Program Leader based in Nairobi and is expected to interact with the PPIAF team, in particular, the Regional Program Coordinator, on a day-to-day basis in performing the tasks below.  

The STC will interact with WB and IFC colleagues and external contacts such as donor agencies, private sector, government counterparts and other development partners. 


Objective of the Assignment:

Primary responsibilities of the STC include: (a) developing and originating projects eligible for PPIAF funding; (b) contributing to the monitoring, evaluation, and learning system (ME&amp;L) for PPIAF activities; (c) contributing to the production of communication material and dissemination of PPIAF knowledge products


Duties and Responsibilities

I.Development and origination of projects eligible for PPIAF funding
 Develop dialogue and identify opportunities for PPIAF support to infrastructure and sub-national clients for projects eligible and meeting PPIAF strategic priorities.
 Analyze requests for PPIAF interventions, and tailor assistance strategies to regional/country priorities and conditions.
 Coordinate with task team, CMU and other World Bank units to ensure strategic fit of the proposed activities
 Work with the task teams on completing the concept and application packages for presentation at the PPIAF technical review panel and donors
 As needed, present applications to the technical review panel

II. Contributing to the monitoring, evaluation, and learning system (ME&amp;L) for PPIAF activities
 Work in the preparation, production and maintenance of various documents for review and reporting purpose
 Ensure the outputs, outcomes, and impacts of PPIAFs activities are correctly recorded in the PATS activity database, in coordination with other team members in the implementation and on-going recording of results in the ME&amp;L system
 Prepare for, participate in and on request lead, the regional inputs to the quarterly portfolio implementation review
 Ensure the quality and consistency of the measurement and evaluation approaches.
 Produce reports of results achieved by PPIAF and promote effective utilization of ME&amp;L outputs and awareness on lessons learned on ME&amp;L related issues.
 Work with task team leaders and implementing agencies in the supervision of PPIAF activities. 
 Serve as key information resource on progress on PPIAF activities, projects, products, technical assistance assignments, etc.
 Provide inputs to the regional sections of annual and other periodic PPIAF reporting
 Participate in regional and global PPIAF team meetings as necessary

III. Contribution to the production and dissemination of communication material and PPIAF knowledge products.
 Serve as technical resource for PPIAF clients and donors on international best practices on PPP and sub-national financing issues in infrastructure.
 Interact with governments at various levels (regional/intergovernmental, national, provincial, municipal), private sector, NGOs, research institutions, and donor agencies, to promote effective coordination across donor programs and technical assistance activities.
 Represent PPIAF in public forums and events. 
 Disseminate PPIAFs products.
 Contribute to the implementation of PPIAFs communication strategy.
 Preparation of marketing materials demonstrating PPIAFs results, including Impact Stories, Regional Updates, etc. 


Selection Criteria
 Masters degree in relevant technical discipline (e.g. economics, public policy, finance or accounting) with 5 years of experience or equivalent combination of education and experience.
 Experience in research, planning, development, or financing infrastructure projects
 Knowledge of infrastructure issues (energy, water supply, sanitation, transport, irrigation, and telecommunications) in developing countries
 Experience working with multilateral institutions and/or ODA agencies
 Ability to work independently, seeking guidance on complex projects/issues from more senior staff
 Strong client service orientation with an openness to feedback and new ideas;
 Proficiency in Word, Excel, Power Point and statistical data management programs
 Excellent oral and written communication and presentation skills in English. 
 Language skills in Arabic and other relevant countries is a plus.
 Ability to work effectively in a team-oriented, multi-cultural environment


Miscellaneous
 The job will require frequent travel in the relevant countries.
 Qualified and shortlisted candidates will be contacted.
 The consultant will be selected from a shortlist, subject to availability of funding.


How to apply 
Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

Submission requirements
The World Bank invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (CV, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills, etc.). Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-11T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1210794</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>STC for PPIAF Nairobi Office</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">412271</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210794</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">412272</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210794</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF057597</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">PPIAF MDTF II - PROGRAM MGMT UNIT (PMU)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>