<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1210400</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-05T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The World Bank, together with other MDBs, has recently launched the PPP Knowledge Lab website in an effort to increase awareness of the issues around PPPs as well as provide governments and practitioners with knowledge resources to better implement PPP transactions. 
Our goal is for the PPP Lab to become the go to site for all knowledge in the PPP area. To ensure success, our aim is to get the website ranked as high as possible on search engines as well as promoted using Google Adwords. Although much has been done to ensure user friendly and search engine friendly content on the site, we believe the site could benefit from further optimization of metadata. 
The PPP in Infrastructure Resource Center for Laws, Contracts and Regulation (PPPIRC) is a well-established and highly trafficked site of the World Bank and is a leading resource for legal and contractual issues related to PPPs.  With the launch of the PPP Lab, some general content from PPPIRC will be moved to the PPP Lab, although PPPIRC will continue to be the go-to site for legal and contractual issues. It is intended that there will be cross-linking between PPPIRC and the Knowledge Lab on relevant issues and that each will promote the other site.  The PPPIRC has benefited in the past from search optimization campaigns and a significant proportion of its visitors are referred by search engines.  As it is currently undergoing an upgrade and some content reorganization, we would like to ensure that the PPPIRC maintains its strong performance (taking into account the upgrade), that its legal and contractual content is well-promoted using Google Adwords and that there is further optimization of metadata as well as effective cross-linking with the PPP Knowledge Lab.
The teams at the World Bank who manage these two sites are seeking the services of an experienced search engine optimization firm or individual to increase organic search traffic.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-05T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1210400</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Search Engine Optimization Consulting Services for the PPP Knowledge Lab and PPPIRC Websites</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414558</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210400</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>