<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1210571</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-12T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-01-30T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1210571 - SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT AND SAFEGUARDS CONSULTANTS SHORT TERM CONSULTANCY TO BE BASED IN CAMEROON, GABON AND ANGOLA

Assignment Countries:
  - Angola
  - Cameroon
  - Gabon

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The World Banks Urban, Rural and Resilience  (GSURR) seeks to recruit Short Term Consultants (STCs) as Social Development and Safeguards Consultants for the Cameroon, Gabon and Angola Country Offices. The Consultants will assist Urban, Rural and Resilience  Social Global Practice (GSURR) to provide consistent and timely support to the Country Management Unit (CMU) and sector staff on social safeguard issues in the countries listed above. The Consultants will provide support to the project team for projects under both preparation and implementation in a variety of sectors and will provide the following key functions: technical support to project teams during preparation, technical inputs for project documents, technical review of various social safeguard related documents, timely identification of risks and mitigation measures, propose citizen engagement mechanisms, project monitoring during implementation support missions, training for project counterparts and any other support.

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

The successful candidate will be the holder of at least a Masters or its equivalent in a social science, anthropology, law or interdisciplinary field with at least 7 years or more demonstrated experience in social development or safeguard compliance. Some knowledge of the World Bank social safeguard policies with a particular focus on OP 4.12 (Involuntary Resettlement) is required. S/he will also have proven technical, analytical, writing and communication skills as well as some knowledge of the work of the Bank including fiduciary and administrative procedures. Working fluency in both English and French is required (For Cameroon and Gabon) and English and Portuguese (for Angola). 


INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB. The World Bank invites qualified individuals to view the full position description, complete selection criteria, required competencies and indicate their interest in being considered by submitting and online application and expression of interest. The expression of interest and CV must include academic qualifications, experience and a description of similar assignments or work performed. Closing date is January 30, 2016. The World Bank Group is committed to achieving diversity in terms of gender, nationality, culture and educational background. Only shortlisted candidates will be contacted.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist, subject to availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-01-30T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1210571</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>SOCIAL DEVELOPMENT AND SAFEGUARDS CONSULTANTS SHORT TERM CONSULTANCY TO BE BASED IN CAMEROON, GABON AND ANGOLA</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">AO</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Angola</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">CM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Cameroon</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">GA</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Gabon</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">411913</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1210571</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>