<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1211729</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-02T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-10T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSION OF INTEREST- CONSULTING FIRM


PROJECT ID:  PA-P147083        

Selection Information:

Assignment Tittle:  Assessing the Potential for Electronics Manufacturing Industry in Ethiopia
Publication Date:   1/26/2016
Expression of interest Deadline: 2/03/2016

Selection Notice:
Assignment Country: Ethiopia

Funding Sources: The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment/services under: 

1.	BB - BANK BUDGET (Ethiopia Programmatic Knowledge Services  PA-P147083-IMPL-BB
2.	
Individual/Firm: Firm

Assignment Description

The Government of Ethiopia (GoE) aims to transform the Country from an agrarian to an industrial-led economy with a target to reach middle-income status by 2025. The Governments Vision 2025 seeks to enable Ethiopia to be the light manufacturing hub of Africa with the manufacturing sector growing by 22 percent/year and creating 200,000 jobs annually. In its medium-term development strategy, the Growth and Transformation Plan 2015/2016-2020/2021, the government identifies electronics suppliers, information and communications equipment manufacturing as one of the future potential growth industries. In this regard, the GoE will conduct a study to access the potential to develop the electronics industry for products classified under Division 26 and 27 of the International Standards Industrial Classification (ISIC) of economic activities. In support of GoEs initiative, the World Bank Group is soliciting for highly qualified firms to undertake this study which will require an assessment of the global electronics production value chain in order to identify the potential for Ethiopia's participation in the global production and distribution networks. The study will identify the potential of the sector, Ethiopia competitive as well as comparative endowments in specific segments and sub-segments and provide strategic direction for the development of the sector/sub sector both in the short term and the long terms. It will also identify the challenges and shortcomings, including risks that need to be addressed to foster the growth of the segment and sub-segments.

The scope of work of consultants will include but is not limited to the following:
1.	Conducting a detailed analysis of the global electrical equipment and electronic supplies, information and communication equipment manufacturing industries as classified under Division 26 and 27 of International Standards Industrial Classification (ISIC) of economic activities.
2.	Conducting a detailed competitiveness analysis of the segments and sub-segments which offer the greatest opportunity for Ethiopia to develop vis-&#224;-vis relevant regional and global comparators.
3.	Recommending a short-medium-long term investment and growth strategy for Ethiopia to develop the priority segments and sub-segments of the electronics sector (as defined under Division 26 and 27 of International Standards Industrial Classification (ISIC)).  
4.	Identifying quick wins and medium- to long-term interventions for developing the electronics sector in general and priority interventions for the niche segments and sub-segments.
5.	Formulating plan of action for the sector in general and for each of the priority sub-categories in detail.

Interested firms are requested to submit a statement of qualifications including description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, brief CVs of key team members, etc. Firms that have been determined to be qualified through the evaluated results of this first stage will be invited to submit proposals for the Request for Proposals (RFP)

Qualification Criteria
Interested Consulting Firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified and experienced to perform the service: This will include:  
1.	Global expertise and qualified experience in sector analysis and studies, and formulation of sector development strategies
2.	Expertise or access to in-depth expertise in electronic supplies, electrical equipment and ICT hardware industries 
3.	Knowledge of and experience in Ethiopia, preferably the manufacturing sector
4.	Qualifications of key staff to do the assignment.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-10T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1211729</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Assessing the Potential for Electronics Manufacturing Industry in Ethiopia</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">ET</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Ethiopia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415096</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211729</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50545</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1. Global expertise and qualified experience in sector analysis and studies, and formulation of sector development strategies</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50546</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2. Expertise or access to in-depth expertise in electronic supplies, electrical equipment and ICT hardware industries</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50547</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3. Knowledge of and experience in Ethiopia, preferably the manufacturing sector</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50548</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4. Qualifications of key staff to do the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>