<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1211450</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-25T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-08T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1211450 - KEPSIE-HUMAN RESOURCES, GOODS &amp; SERVICES FOR CONDUCTION OF INSPECTIONS

Assignment Countries:
  - Kenya

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The recruitment is for a logistics and manpower firm that will be responsible for hiring inspectors and procuring any goods and services needed for the conduction of inspections for the Kenya Patient Safety Impact Evaluation (KePSIE). 

The selected Logistics and manpower firm will be expected to hire inspectors and procure any goods and services needed for the conduction of inspections. It shall report directly to the WBG Core Team, but work in close collaboration with the MoH Coordinator and the WBG Coordinators. The Logistics firm will be selected through an open competitive process according to WBG procurement policies.The full process and requirements are detailed below and the broad requirements are as follows:
1.	The firm will provide 16 highly qualified and motivated individuals who, together with 8 candidates nominated by the Boards and Councils, will be fully trained and certified to act as inspectors representing the Ministry of Health and the Boards and Councils.
2.	The 24 candidates will be trained for a month and ultimately, one-year employment contracts will be extended to the 12 best candidates.
3.	These candidates will be deployed to the 3 study counties (Kilifi, Kakamega and Meru) for the duration of 12 months from the start of their contract. Their duties in these counties are detailed below. During this time, they will report to the MOH Coordinator.
4.	At the end of their term, a performance evaluation will be completed for each inspector and these evaluations will be made available to the Ministries of Health and Boards and Councils for potential future employment. 

The detailed responsibilities are as follows.

Responsibilities
1.	Advertising the opening for inspector training and a full-time inspector position. Please note the qualifications requirements as detailed below.
2.	Supporting the shortlisting of inspector candidates to undertake training. 
3.	Providing a training allowance to the group of 24 candidates that will be trained. This will include reimbursing transport costs for those traveling from outside Nairobi.
4.	Offering one year employment contracts to the 12 gazetted inspectors recommended for appointment as inspectors.
5.	Providing assistance to inspectors in identifying and making logistical arrangements for inspections based on the visits plans developed by the MoH coordinator and WBG coordinators. 
6.	Procuring any goods and services required for the deployment of inspectors and the conduction of inspections, including but not limited to: car rentals; overnight accommodation when appropriate; communication services including telephone cards or monthly allowance for phone usage, and internet; office space and equipment; security; insurances; and tablets. 
7.	Disbursing payments to inspectors in a timely manner, including: salaries, benefits, and reimbursements. Salaries will be pegged on government scales for equivalent cadres working for the MOH. Reimbursements include (but are not limited to) public transport expenses, and unexpected overnight accommodation. May request presentation of receipts and confirmation that the right arrangement was used for reimbursement.
8.	Collecting expenses data and preparing a monthly expenses report. These are all expenses associated with the conduction of inspections in the field  including the inspectors monthly salaries
9.	Enforcing and documenting in a monthly report any sanctions or honorable mentions based on inspector performance, following the procedures described in this manual; including the termination of contracts and hiring replacement inspectors when necessary. 
10.	Bearing responsibility for any inspector actions and following appropriate procedures to solve any issues according to this manual and in collaboration with the MoH and WBG Coordinators.
Additionally, the Logistics firm must comply with all the protocols and responsibilities described in the implementation manual and will be subject to WBG policies and procedures. Any breach of these may result in contract termination. Termination of contract between the WBG and the Logistics firm must result in termination of contract with Inspectors.

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - BANK BUDGET
  - African Health Market for Equity Program (AHME)

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-08T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1211450</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>KEPSIE-HUMAN RESOURCES, GOODS &amp; SERVICES FOR CONDUCTION OF INSPECTIONS</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">KE</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kenya</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">413478</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211450</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">413479</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211450</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF015121</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">African Health Market for Equity Program (AHME)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50329</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information the firm has a dedicated Human Resources department and experience hiring and managing personnel.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50333</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that the firm has an established, fast payment disbursement mechanisms.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50334</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that the firm has demonstrated experience in logistics management e.g. ability to procure goods and services quickly.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50330</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50331</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50332</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>