<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1211537</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-21T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-01-28T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2

https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

Assignment Title: 1211537 - Senior Digital Financial Services Specialist

Assignment Countries: LAC Region

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

In the LAC region, there are 37 mobile money services totaling approximately 14.9 million mobile money accounts across 19 countries. Although the region has seen a real and sustained increase in financial inclusion, half the adult population in LAC lacks access to a bank account. As such, digital financial services can play an important role in expanding access to basic financial services and serve as a critical pillar sustaining the financial sector eco-system in LAC. This region has many distinguishing factors which differentiate it from the rest of the developing world. The banking sector is more developed and has greater outreach both geographically and numerically. The regulatory framework favors banks as the natural providers of financial services; at the same time, it has encouraged experimentation with agent banking models and promoted simplified bank accounts in an attempt to foster financial inclusion. Governments have also supported the development of digital payments by mandating that conditional cash transfers must be made via electronic means or through a bank account.   

Some key trends which can be observed in this market are: 

	The Move to Enabling Regulatory Frameworks: Although regulatory reform in a region with a well-entrenched banking system has taken place only over time, policymakers have recognized the role that digital finance can play in improving financial inclusion. The correspondent agent banking model has allowed financial institutions to offer financial services to a greater number of people and to remote areas through third party entities called agents. The promulgation of simplified bank accounts with lower due diligence norms has enabled financial institutions to reach out to low-income segments. 

	Development and Consolidation of Agent Networks: Colombia, Brazil and Peru have been pioneers in the region in creating a strong and extensive network of banking agents.  Third party players are playing an important role, building agent networks that have become a channel for a wide range of financial services targeting the poor.

	Introduction of New Services over the DFS Infrastructure: Financial Institutions are experimenting with additional services such as micro-savings, micro-insurance and microcredit services targeting low income masses and leveraging the digital channel to collect/disburse payments and premiums.  Increasingly, G2P programs will use the digital channel and agent networks to facilitate disbursement of social benefits to low income masses.  Business to business cash management services has a strong potential in environments with high cash transportation costs and security risks. 
 
Project Objective

IFC is seeking to recruit a Senior Digital Financial Services Specialist who will play a key role in implementing its digital financial services strategy in LAC.

Scope of Work

The Senior Digital Financial Services Specialist will support LAC FIG Advisory Services to take its projects with financial institutions and other DFS service providers to scale through the use of technology and alternate delivery channels. Specially, the Consultant will support the FIG team to partner with relevant financial intermediaries to: (i) Conduct New Business Development in the region to expand the number of current projects (ii) Support the implementation of advisory projects as a DFS technical specialist. 
Develop FIGs expanding business operations for Digital Finance; and (ii) support in the delivery of advisory projects as a DFS technical specialist. 
Key responsibilities: 
1)	Business Development
o	Support of Regions, particularly LAC, in Client Facing Work functioning as an Internal IFC Expert, Resource and Consultant to the operational staff and clients. 
o	Assist in building the business, i.e. identifying potential IFC Advisory services clients that seek to reach un- and underserved customers through the development of products and innovative channels.
o	Work with advisory services regional staff to develop opportunities with key partners in the region; including developing project proposals/client pitches; leading meetings with potential clients and other market stakeholders to discuss business opportunities 
o	Conduct assessments and/or workshops as part of business development or advisory project design
o	Design projects that address key clients needs, in a sustainable way, aiming for capacity building and leveraging existing client resources;
o	Lead and / or support the implementation of tasks to strengthen business development efforts. 
o	Conduct country/ company assessments in order to identify opportunities for developing advisory services projects. 
o	Work/ interact closely with IFCs advisory staff to build their technical capacity for the delivery of DFS advisory projects

2)	Supporting Implementation of DFS projects
Support to Regional Implementation
o	Support regional client work, functioning as an Internal IFC technical resource to the Regions
o	Develop strategies to enable financial / microfinance institutions to utilize electronic channels and support the implementation of such strategies
o	Provide long-term (multi-month) embedded technical support to IFC clients 
The Senior Digital Financial Services Specialist will be expected to have expertise in the following domains, amongst others: 
Customer Uptake
o	Oversee and support the develop customer uptake strategies developing customer communication on new products developed as well as building on financial awareness for these products
o	Identify constraints in up-take and develop strategies to increase product uptake
o	Identify, build and train clients in customer uptake strategies.

Market Research &amp; Product Development
o	Research global trends in product evolution and value added services deployed through electronic channels synthesizing learning for IFC clients
o	Research successful consumer uptake strategies and translate into recommendations for IFC clients
o	Develop new product/ solutions to clients including  appropriate tools (partnership development, network development, amongst others)
o	Design products (savings, insurance, loans, supply chain finance, cash management, G2P, etc.) based on results of market surveys and client priorities

Agent Network Management
o	Provide support to clients on developing and implementing strategies for agent network build-out, training, recruitment, and monitoring. 

Deliverables
The Senior Digital Financial Services Specialist will be expected to submit the following deliverables: 
	Proposals to clients in PowerPoint and/or Word format. 
	Client assessment reports detailing concrete advisory recommendations and findings of client DFS operations
	Specific project deliverables as they relate to project implementation plans, including but not limited to feasibility studies, business plans, financial models,  market and customer research, strategy. 

All deliverables will be presented in Spanish and/or English and will be reviewed by IFC. Specific deliverables will depend on the task and responsibility. 
Criteria
The Senior DFS Specialist should have the following qualifications:
	MBA, Master of Finance, Master of Public Policy or other relevant qualification;
	Solid track record of experience related to development and implementation of digital financial services strategies
	At least ten years of operational experience in digital financial services and technology solutions for financial services in emerging markets, preferably with at least 5 years of direct experience in the use of technology to expand reach of financial services to low-income populations 
	Experience working with financial institutions in Latin America is desired
	Demonstrated ability to identify problems and propose solutions to clients. 
	Deep understanding of global e-payments industry trends and of emerging best practices and innovations
	Knowledge of policy and legal/regulatory issues related to mobile banking and payments systems development 
	Substantial business experience in retail payments, including mobile banking, financial systems interoperability, technology systems
	Extensive practical experience in the development of mobile banking and other transformational electronic payments solutions. Experience in developing pilot environments, measuring success and learning lessons from them for future roll-out plans, in at least one project
	Strong business development, market development, networking and partnership management.
	Fluent written and spoken English and Spanish. Ability to work in Portuguese and/or French would be an advantage
	A keen interest in development finance and in working in a multicultural environment; experience in a multilateral finance institution would be an advantage
	Willingness and ability to travel extensively
The consultants daily fee will be determined based on his qualifications and prior experience. The consultant will be reimbursed for travel expenses according to IFCs Travel Policy.
SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/i</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-01-28T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1211537</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Senior Digital Financial Services Specialist</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">413640</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211537</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">413641</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211537</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0539</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">42</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">FIG - LAC - FMTAAS</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">413642</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211537</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF015093</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">58</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Mobile Financial Services</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>