<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1211753</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-27T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-12T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The WBG Finance and Markets Global Practice, Azerbaijan and Central Asia Financial Infrastructure Advisory Services (ACAFI) Project has supported secured transaction reform in Uzbekistan to promote development of modern movable financing in the country (hereinafter  Project country). Eventually this reform will increase affordability of finance to SMEs and population in Project country. In this regard, it is necessary to train financial institutions on how to expand on operations via Movable Asset-Based Lending (MABL). So the Project seeks for a Consultant that will be able to, conduct the special training program for local appraisers on how to assess movables in accordance with the best international practices and international standards. The Consultant should be primary responsible for all the deliverables while it may be needed to attract additional consultant to support his activity under this assignment. 
The work to be undertaken is broken into the following tasks as outlined below: 
	based on the initial report and findings, prepared by the International consultants collect  necessary data and analyze the current legislative/regulatory/methodological materials  to evaluate the gaps and discrepancies with the international practices. The collected information is needed is needed to understand the way how to prepare and implement the local methodology for assessing movable assets. This data is also needed to develop training/certification materials to train local appraisers to evaluate movable assets. In case a survey is needed for additional data, the Consultant will be responsible for developing questioners, analyzing collected data and preparing the report with findings;
	develop the assessment methodology for evaluation of movable assets (accounts receivable, inventory, stored goods, equipment and all other types of movables), lead the discussion with the Government agencies, private stakeholders, professional associations to prepare the methodology, which responds all market needs. The Consultant will be responsible for supporting the dialogue  for the methodology adoption;
	based on the adopted assessment methodology, the Consultant should develop full package of training materials including: assessment of the targeted audience, development of the training program for trainers of appraisers (TOT) and trainers of appraisers (TOT) and training plan. The training program should include key aspects for assessing main types of movable assets (account receivables, inventory, stored goods, equipment, fertilizers, crops, agricultural machinery, warehouse receipts etc.);
	develop certification exam materials and the evaluation methodology.

Throughout the engagement, the Consultant will work under the supervision and guidance of the IFC Global Secured transaction specialist and local project officers. 

All materials mentioned in this assignment should be presented to IFC in Russian.

The Consultant should deliver the final report with the detailed description of the works, done and the results achieved, which should be accompanies with the full package of the materials developed.

 
The consultant will be working out of office (no office space is provided for the Consultant), with the Contract duration 130 work days.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-12T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1211753</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Consultant on improving capacity on assessment of movables</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">UZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Uzbekistan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414048</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211753</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414049</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211753</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1492</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Eastern Europe and Central Asia Financial Infrastructure</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>