<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1211759</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-28T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-05T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>TERMS OF REFERENCE 

Regional Project Consultant on Legal Aspects for Secured Transaction and Credit reporting Systems

Azerbaijan-Central Asia Financial Infrastructure Project (ACAFI) &amp; Balkan and Armenia Financial Infrastructure Project (BAFI)


A.	Objectives/Purpose of Assignment 

	Background of the Project:

(1) to improve the legal and regulatory framework for credit information sharing that governs credit bureaus operations and assist in their implementation; (2) to build the capacity of financial intermediaries to improve credit underwriting policies and practices through in-depth advisory services to selected financial institutions; (3) to build capacity of credit bureaus to better serve financial intermediaries; (4) to enhance professional risk management certification for staff in financial intermediaries by developing and introducing formal risk management education and certification; (5) to improve the legal and regulatory framework in the field of secured transactions; (6) to raise awareness about the role of credit bureaus and professional risk certification through public education campaigns and outreach work.

B.	Scope of Work 

The Consultant shall in ACAFI and BAFI countries (Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan) guide, advice and supervise other Project Consultants and provide knowledge support to Project staff on ad-hoc basis regarding:  
-	analyzing the best international practice and corresponding national practices (Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan) on secured transactions and credit reporting;
-	improving the practices of evaluation of the movable assets in Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan accordingly to international practice and requirements of Movable assets based lending (MABL);
-	developing materials to align the local legislation in Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan with the best international practice on secured transactions and credit reporting system, including but not limiting to: 1) on secured transactions  the functional approach, priorities of the secured creditors, seizing procedures; 2) on credit reporting  licensing private credit bureaus, supervision over credit bureaus, improvement of supervision over financial sector based on public credit registry data;
-	connecting state agencies and other data sources to the collateral registry and the private credit bureaus, collection the necessary data and processing it in order to develop the state-of-the-art entities;
-	developing draft of regulations and other legislative acts needed to implement MABL in Project countries (Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan);
-	developing draft of regulations and other legislative acts needed to implement financial products based on credit reports and other value added services of the private credit bureaus in Project countries (Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan);
-	developing training and other knowledge materials (factsheets, guides etc.) on usage of private credit bureaus products in the banks, microfinance institutions and other financial entities in Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan
-	lobbying in cooperation with local stakeholders for improvement in the legislation and regulations related to credit reporting and secured transactions, and further monitor legislation and regulations of financial markets infrastructure to prevent any adverse legislative changes;
-	writing comments to laws On Collateral register, On credit information sharing and other laws and regulations and instructions, developed with support of the Project;
-	providing assistance to the Project on legal aspects of secured transactions and credit reporting issues, including writing respective articles, reference data and provision of respective consultations;
-	creation the second credit bureau with an international reputable credit bureau partner in Project countries (Azerbaijan, Kosovo, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan);
-	drafting articles on credit bureaus, secured translations, collateral registry, evaluation activity and financial literacy.

Total timeframe for Consultant engagement  till June 30, 2016. Total number of payable days  not more than 150.

C.	Deliverables / Specific Outputs Expected from Consultant

1.	Deliverables  support is provided to Consultants/Project staff on:
-	developing respective materials  within timeframes agreed with the respective staff/consultant;
-	consultations - as agreed with the respective staff/consultant;
-	comprehensive reports are provided to the supervisors  at the request of respective supervisor but at least once in a month.

D.	Specific Inputs to be provided by the Client:  
  
The Client will provide the Consultant with:
a)	The WBG profile, including e-mail account. The Consultant will have an access to WBG internal website. 
b)	Equipment ( PC) .
c)	Templates produced by the Project.
d)	Secure access to the staff of the Project counterparts.
e)	All other documentation in possession of the Client, which may be necessary to perform tasks described in the section B, unless a document is protected by confidentiality status or intellectual property rights.

E.	Special Terms &amp; Conditions / Specific Criteria

The Consultant shall have:
	Master degree in Law;
	Strong knowledge of the best international practice and standards of modern financial infrastructure (secured transactions and credit bureaus);
	Not less than 8 years of experience (in ECA region in at least in one of the Project countries) in banking and financial infrastructure;
	Proven experience in successful reforming the financial infrastructure matters in at least in one of the Project countries (not less than 5 years);
	Strong knowledge of practice and regulatory barriers in the Project countries regarding secured transaction system and credit reporting;
	A good understanding of WBG operational policies, practices and procedures will be an advantage;
	Ability to work flexibly and under deadline pressure at times on a range of assignments, and adjust to and prioritize a variety of complex evolving tasks;
	Ability to provide professional support to senior staff;
	Ability to work effectively in a team-oriented, multi-cultural environment;
	Strong analytical and conceptual skills;
	High degree of self-motivation and proven ability to work independently under limited supervision. Ability to multitask and work effectively in multidisciplinary teams
	Strong interpersonal skills; 
	Excellent written/communication skills in Russian and English.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-05T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1211759</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Regional Project Consultant on Legal Aspects for Secured Transaction and Credit Reporting Systems</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">AZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Azerbaijan</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">XK</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kosovo</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">KG</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kyrgyz Republic</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Moldova</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TJ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Tajikistan</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">UZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Uzbekistan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414062</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211759</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414063</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211759</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1492</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">80</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Eastern Europe and Central Asia Financial Infrastructure</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414064</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211759</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF012330</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">20</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Global Credit Reporting Program-ECA</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>