<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1211299</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-01-22T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-22T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSION OF INTEREST 

SELECTION INFORMATION
Assignment Title: Survey Implementation - Socio-Economic Assessment of the Impact of Syrians under Temporary Protection on Turkish Hosting Communities
Publication Date: January 22. 2016
Expression of Interest Deadline: February 22, 2016 
Language of Notice: English

SELECTION NOTICE
Assignment Country: Turkey
Funding Sources: Trust Fund
Individual/Firm: The consultant will be a firm or academic institution. 

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
Background
The conflict in Syria, the worlds largest humanitarian crisis since World War II, started in March 2011 and has resulted in the displacement of millions of Syrians within Syria and to neighboring countries. The conflict is in its fourth year with no resolution in sight; a total of 3,977,211 citizens from Syria now live in neighboring countries, and as of May 2015, there are 1,759,846 Syrians under Temporary Protection SuTPs) in Turkey. In February 2015, the United Nations declared that Turkey had become the largest refugee host country in the world. In Turkey, 85 percent of the refugee population lives in urban areas, while the remaining are residing in the 25 refugee camps constructed and managed by the Disaster and Emergency Management Authority  (AFAD). Furthermore, the majority of SuTPs in Turkey are women and children under 18 years of age (76 percent).  Men 18 years and older are 24 percent of the SuTP population.

The World Bank Group is partnering with the Government of Turkey to undertake analysis that strengthens the identification and quantification of the developmental impacts of the Syrian crisis on host communities in Turkey. The overall goal of this initiative is to identify policy and program responses that can: (i) mitigate the potential negative socio-economic impact of refugee presence on host communities (ii) maximize the social-economic benefits of the refugee presence for host communities and the Turkish economy as a whole, (iii) support SuTPs to be self-reliant until the time they are able to return. 

Over the past two years, several surveys of refugees and host communities have been carried out in Turkey. However the data collected from these surveys is limited by several factors: (i) small scale and non-representative sampling, (ii) focus on single issues or single populations (i.e. either refugees or hosts and not the relationship between them), (iii) the survey design was not guided by the need to inform government-level policy responses but more focused on needs assessments for humanitarian provision. The proposed survey and analysis is designed to address these large data gaps, through new qualitative and quantitative household survey efforts. 

The objectives, design, and approach for the overall initiative and for the survey effort has been guided by a Steering Committee that includes representatives from the Turkish government, international and non-governmental organizations.  

Objective 
The primary objective of the consultancy is to implement the proposed quantitative household survey to assess the socio-economic impacts of the influx of SuTPs in order to guide evidence based policy dialogue. The central focus of the proposed data collection in Turkey is to identify the impact on host communities. However, the extent of the impact of refugees on host communities can only be fully known when the dynamics of refugee coping and choices are explored. Therefore attention will be given to data collection within both Turkish population and the refugee population itself.

Note: Since the survey design, including survey goals, content, methods, sampling and questionnaire have reached an advanced level, the firm selected for the task will focus on successful implementation of the survey.

The survey, as developed by the Government and WB sector specialists, will include the following modules: (1) demographic information; (2) welfare (collection of information financial aspects like income sources, income levels and frequency, and non-financial aspects such as goals in life, psycho-social problems, health, social relations, safety networks and mechanisms to cope with negative situations); (3) labor (collection of information on access to employment, informality, type of vocation and other labor market outcomes); (4) access to education and other services (collection of information on access to education, housing and other public services; unmet demand for education and other services, educational levels and skills of SuTP and Turkish population); (5) identification of the capacities, financial and physical gaps, possibilities, needs and burdens of host communities and local institutions and organizations concerning SuTP population. 
    
These modules have been designed to provide information on challenges faced by the SuTP population, impacts of SuTP influx on host communities and the linkages between access to services, housing and employment, and welfare. A draft version of questionnaire will be submitted to the consultant for pilot implementation and identification of potential improvements.  

Methods and Sampling:  In order to capture the range of living situations of the SuTP population living in Turkey and their host communities, the following sample design is proposed:
1.	Camp Sample. For the estimated 15 percent of the SuTP population living in camps in Turkey, a clustered sample design will be used in which the camps are clusters.  Using the camp administrative lists held by AFAD as a sampling frame, camps will be selected as the primary sampling unit, and households in the second stage. The camp sample will be determined through random sampling, taking as a basis the camp lists/layout plans and populations provided by AFAD only.      
2.	Dwelling Sample. The largest component of the sample will be a stratified cluster sample of SuTP and non-SuTP populations living in standard dwellings.  The stratification will be based on the geographic distribution of refugees.  A minimum of four strata are expected:
i 	Istanbul, with a focus on the areas with high numbers of SuTPs.  
ii. 	Areas with high densities of SuTPs, particularly in the southeast of the country.  
iii.	Areas with low predicted numbers of SuTPs
iv.	Remaining areas of the country.  

Sample size is estimated as approximately 4,000 households across Turkey. The sampling strategy is being devised with the Government of Turkey and the consultant should expect a detailed set of guidelines for the sampling approach.

Note: The GoT has requested that AFAD enumerators conduct the survey in camp settings.  Therefore, the selected consultant will need to coordinate closely on enumerator training, survey piloting, data collection and aggregation of data into one database to ensure consistent results and coding in camp/non-camp environments. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank invites eligible consultants to submit their Expressions of Interest (EOI) in English, electronically through World Bank Group econsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index/html). Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services based on the description of the task and qualification criteria below  e.g. demonstration of description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, and availability of appropriate skills among staff.  The EOI should focus on how the firm would propose to successfully implement the survey, in close coordination with the GoT, WBG, and local actors, including on issues such as training/overseeing enumerators (including those speaking Arabic), ensuring quality control and reliable sampling, and timing/sequencing of survey delivery.  EOIs should be no more than 1500 words/4 pages; anything written beyond 4 pages will not be considered. 

The consultant and/or firm will work in cooperation with the team set up by the Government of Turkey, WB and AFAD in relation to this survey, throughout all stages, and shall provide any requested information. 

Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit technical &amp; financial proposals based on an expanded Request for Proposals (RFP).</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-22T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1211299</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Consultancy for Survey Implementation - Socio-Economic Assessment of the Impact of Syrians under Temporary Protection on Turkish Hosting Communities</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TR</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Turkey</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">413498</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1211299</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50361</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Strong and proven experience in research design, quantitative research methods, surveying and analysis; research experience in Turkey/with diverse Turkish populations/regions preferred.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50362</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Established networks/the ability to mobilize Turkish academic institutions, civil society and other local expertise in implementation of the surveys.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50363</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Established knowledge/experience in refugee, migration and displacement issues.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50364</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in design/implementation of surveys of displaced/migrant populations, particularly in the region, is a plus.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50365</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Proven experience in training/mobilizing high quality enumerators, for survey implementation. Prior experience with working with Arabic-speaking enumerators is a plus.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50366</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Previous experience in working with government departments, international organizations and donors and evidence of report writing for an international audience are required.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>