<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1212178</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-16T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1212178 - SIB - INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY STRATEGY AND TRANSFORMATION SPECIALIST

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

IFC, a member of the World Bank Group, is the largest development institution focused on the private sector in developing countries. We create opportunity for people to escape poverty and improve their livesby providing financing to help businesses employ more people and provide essential services, mobilizing capital from others, and delivering advisory and risk-management (RM) services to ensure sustainable development.

IFC Advisory Services in South Asia has been supporting regional efforts to promote financial inclusion across the sub-continent including India, Bangladesh, Sri lanka, Nepal, Bhutan and the Maldives. We partner with financial institutions to help build their capacity to provide financial services to key underserved parts of the market such as microfinance, SME, women, and agriculture

We are now recruiting for a IT specialist to support a large business transformation project in India, and will be responsible for leading all IT transformation related activity on the program.

The Consultant will be review the current Information Technology and Systems landscape of the client bank and develop a strategy and detailed roadmap for modernizing the IT infrastructure and Systems to achieve the business objectives and implement the business strategies

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - Facilitating Financial Inclusion among MSMEs and Low-Income Households in India
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

A minimum of:
	1. MBA or equivalent and senior operational experience in banking in both developed and emerging markets, and above 12 years strong demonstrated experience in a financial services environment
	2. Proven track record in the assessment and development of a comprehensive IT strategy and Systems implementation plan for large banks with a network of at least 200+ branches. 
	3. Proven experience in implementation of IT systems in commercial banks including  core banking, alternate delivery channels, customer help desk systems, trade finance, treasury, CRM, etc. 
	4. Experience in similar assignments with developing IT strategy and implementation roadmaps for large commercial banks in developing countries (200+ branches) in the last 5 years, preferably in the South Asia region. 
	5. Experience in BPR and change management related to IT implementation in large financial institutions. Previous experience of working with public sector banks will be desirable. 
	6. Thorough understanding of the local IT, and banking industries including various service providers will be a plus. 
	7. Experience in developing IT Enterprise Architecture 
	8. Strong leadership, organizational, and communications skills, including the ability to represent IFC and work credibly at the senior executive and boardroom level.
	9. Team player with good problem solving and analytical skills, with an ability to collaborate with large teams in the field
	10. Ability to read, analyze, and interpret common business, scientific and technical journals.
	11. Excellent communication skills and personnel management.
	12. Proficiency in English language

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist, subject to availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-16T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1212178</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>SIB - INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY STRATEGY AND TRANSFORMATION SPECIALIST</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414790</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212178</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017293</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Facilitating Financial Inclusion among MSMEs and Low-Income Households in India</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">414789</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212178</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>