<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1212893</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-19T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-04T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Background

Kenya taking steps to diversify the generation mix by accelerating development of renewable energy resources to enhance energy security and lower electricity cost to consumers in order to make the country competitive in the region.  Geothermal is one of the most promising indigenous resources for power development in Kenya, with an estimated potential between 7,000 and 10,000 MW.  It is also the countrys least cost base load option.   The current Least Cost Power Development Plan (LCPDP) has set ambitious target for development of over 5,000 MW by 2030, as it strives to fuel the necessary economic transformations towards achievement of the countrys Vision 2030.
Kenya is the leader on geothermal development in the East Africa Region. However, although geothermal development in the country dates back to 1956 and the Government of Kenya (GoK) has made strong policy and budgetary commitment to geothermal, less than 10% of the countrys estimated geothermal resources have been developed to date. There has been significant progress in the last three years, with geothermal installed capacity having more than doubled, from 240 MW in 2013 to 600 MW in 2015. The upward trend in development of geothermal capacity is expected to continue as the country has set ambitious goals for expansion.  However, the GoK recognizes the need to address bottlenecks, especially to further encourage private sector participation and as a result accelerate the current pace of development.
With this objective in mind, the Ministry of Energy and Petroleum (MoEP) has requested support from the World Bank to prepare a National Geothermal Strategy. The Strategy will build on the current sector structure and development models and seek to improve the enabling environment to facilitate accelerated development.

Scope of work

The World Bank will hire a consultant firm to support MoEP in the preparation of the Geothermal Strategy. The consultant responsibilities are expected to include:

a)	Review  of the adequacy of existing arrangements for geothermal development with particular focus on the following key areas: 
(i)	policy, legal and regulatory framework including licensing and procurement; 
(ii)	models and delivery mechanisms for the development of the geothermal sub-sector including institutional roles of relevant stakeholders;
(iii)	pricing and incentives, including feed-in tariffs, levies and taxes 
(iv)	relevance and availability of different risk mitigation instruments;
(v)	framework to address environmental, social and land issues in the context of geothermal;
(vi)	capacity needs and better use of local expertise;  and
(vii)	framework for the promotion of direct uses of geothermal resources.

b)	Development of specific objectives on geothermal development, deliverable targets, and plans including actions that adequately address the challenges in (a) above.

c)	Prepare the Geothermal Strategy document for MoEP, including implementation plan. 

d)	Present the results in a workshop of stakeholders, potentially including investors conference. 

Timeline

It is expected that completion of the assignment will be required within seven months of contract signature.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-04T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1212893</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Kenya Geothermal Strategy</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">KE</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kenya</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416069</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212893</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416070</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212893</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF013201</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Global Geothermal Development Plan</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50846</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Proven and significant experience in the geothermal energy sector, preferably in developing countries and specifically in Kenya</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50962</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Strong understanding of the legal, technical, financial, and regulatory aspects of geothermal power development</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50847</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Strong familiarity with a range of geothermal development models, as well as experience evaluating technical options for geothermal power development and developing strategies for the sector</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50848</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">The Consultant will have to interact and involve all the relevant stakeholders in developing and taking ownership of the Strategy- experience in managing such a process is thus critical</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50849</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in developing priority sector strategies for the Government of Kenya, either within our outside the energy sector</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50963</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>