<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1212960</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-15T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-25T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1212960 - Technical Support for Natural Capital Accounts in Guatemala

Assignment Countries:
  - Guatemala

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Guatemala is one of the eight CICs. WAVES is assisting the Government of Guatemala (GoG) to consolidate the ongoing institutional efforts to ensure the medium/long term sustainability of NCA, as well as to update the accounts that have already been compiled for the period 2001-2010 using the UN System of Environmental-Economic Accounts (SEEA). Despite significant efforts, there are still major gaps to improve the compilation and institutionalization of NCA, aligning it to policy demands.  WAVES Guatemala will focus on supporting the production of information for prioritized accounts, institutional strengthening of key institutions in particular, aiming to use the accounts and related indicators for policy relevant decision-making.
Based on the results from a scoping study that informed the policy priorities and entry points, the WAVES Guatemala program will focus in four broad thematic areas: (i) Inclusive green growth and poverty reduction, (ii) Food Security, (iii) Climate change, risk and economic growth, and, (iv) Economic and environmental sustainability. These areas are related to the overarching countrys national development plan, Katun: Our Guatemala 2032.  Work on these policy areas will involve updating the SEEA Central Framework (SEEA-CF) accounts developed for 2001-2010, and include new developments in the area of SEEA Experimental Ecosystem Accounts (SEEA-EEA), SEEA Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries Accounts (SEEA-AFF) and Wealth Accounts as per World Bank methodologies.

WAVES would like to request expressions of interest for the provision of technical support service for NCA implementation in Guatemala.

Assignment Description

The work program for WAVES Guatemala is divided into several consecutive phases, each of approximately a year. Firms who have a satisfactory performance in the first phase will be invited to continue the next phase of the work.  

This Request for Expression of Interest refers to activities in the first phase of the program. The activities within the first phase are grouped in three (3) work elements:

-	Work Element 1: Review, improve and update the existing SEEA-CF accounts
-	Work Element 2: Develop a first presentation of the SEEA-EEA, SEEA-AFF and Wealth Accounts 
-	Work Element 3: Capacity building, communication and dissemination

The tasks associated with each work element are described below in broad terms:

Work Element 1: Review, improve and update the existing SEEA-CF accounts for Guatemala.  The consulting firm will lead technical work -in close cooperation with all agencies to ensure long term institutionalization- for the review and update of all accounts of the SEEA Central Framework published by Guatemala for the 2001-2010 period, including: (i) Improved data for physical asset and flow accounts (ii) Estimation of monetary asset and flow accounts, (iii) Addressing conceptual issues, (iv) Improved database management, including web based application to process data and communicate results, (v) Policy analysis using the updated accounts in the areas of special interest for WAVES Guatemala.

Work Element 2: Develop a first iteration of the SEEA-EEA, SEEA-AFF and Wealth Accounts 
Under this work element, the firm will produce develop work and produce a first report for ecosystem accounts, agriculture accounts and wealth indicators based on the UN and World Bank methodologies. Four broad activities will be carried on, which will include in all of the three accounts: (i) reviewing the methodology and concepts, (ii) preparing a first data set with all available data and, (iii) identifying data gaps and institutional challenges, including how to tackle those gaps and challenges, (iv) develop policy analysis that using the first iterations of the three accounts. 

Work Element 3: Capacity building, communication and dissemination.  A communications strategy was previously developed and the firm will have to review, refine and implement it. The strategy should be implemented in close coordination with the Global WAVES communication team. Audiences and messages should be clearly identified, as well as the different tools and activities to be developed.  Within this component, the firm should design and implement a training and capacity building strategy that can reach both users and producers of the accounts.  This strategy will include preparation of and publication of materials suitable for training of a wide variety of WAVES stakeholders (statisticians, senior level decision makers, politicians at the national and local level, and others) in the uses of natural capital accounts and its analytical applications for the purposes of development planning.  The strategy should also include the organization of workshops, video conferences, webinars or other related activities.  All of these activities and tools should be supported and systematized in a virtual platform.  This platform should facilitate knowledge exchange and help develop a national learning network and should integrate to the existing WAVES web based platform, especially the Knowledge Center.


Funding Source

The World Bank intends to finance the services under a World Bank trust fund. 

Individual / Firm Profile

The consultant will be a firm. Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications. 

Submission requirements

The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, description of similar assignments, etc.). Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5 MB. 

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest. 

Expressions of interest should be submitted in English through World Bank Group eConsultant2 https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html


Qualification criteria

1.	Provide information showing that the firm is qualified in the field of the assignment, with demonstrated professional experience working in Guatemala on issues related to economic development, natural resources and the environment
2.	Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm
3.	Provide information on their core business and years in business
4.	Provide information on the qualifications of key staff to be assigned, all with proficiency in Spanish and some fluent English speakers.
5.	Provide information of prior experience working at or in close coordination with the government of Guatemala in areas of environmental statistics or accounting. 


FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - BANK BUDGET
  - WAVES Guatemala

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-25T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1212960</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Technical Support for Natural Capital Accounts in Guatemala</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">GT</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Guatemala</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416181</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212960</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416182</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212960</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF016043</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">WAVES Guatemala</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50755</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50756</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50757</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50758</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50767</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information of prior experience working at or in close coordination with the government of Guatemala in areas of environmental statistics or accounting.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>