<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1212460</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-03T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-16T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The International Finance Corporation (IFC), a member of the World Bank Group, promotes sustainable private sector investment in developing countries as a way to reduce poverty and improve peoples lives. In addition to its investment work, IFC provides a number of advisory services funded projects through different donors, as well as its own income-generating activities, by developing targeted programs and projects to strengthen financial institutions and markets. 

About FIG Advisory Services  in Sub Saharan Africa

The scope of the Financial Institutions Group (FIG) advisory program in Sub-Saharan Africa (SSA) is concentrated on offering tailor-made advisory services and technical assistance to financial institutions and other organisations operating in the areas of:
 
Small and medium enterprises (SME) finance
Microfinance
Digital financial services
Risk management
Sustainable energy finance

IFCs FIG Advisory Services department is seeking to recruit a highly motivated professional for the position of a Resource Management Consultant to build, maintain and administer a roster of consultants and to provide support to the middle office which supports the efficient running of the FIG Africa Advisory services business in the SSA region.  The Resource Management Consultant needs to have experience in a Consulting firm or within the financial sector. The detailed Terms of Reference are attached.

SELECTION CRITERIA

Bachelors or equivalent, or at least 5 years experience managing the back office in a consulting firm particularly in resource management, interviewing of candidates and maintaining database. 
Ability to work effectively with MS Office in particular with excel &amp;  power point
Detail-oriented with background and hands-on experience in quantitative / statistical analysis, budgeting and forecasting. 
Excellent research and report writing skills
Team player with good interpersonal, problem solving and analytical skills, with an ability to execute the tasks to high standards in a timely and effective manner
He/she must be able to work effectively at all levels of the organization, be results oriented, have strong analytical and decision-making abilities, and a creative problem solver. 
Ability to work remotely with limited daily supervision
Fluency in English is required, knowledge of French will be an advantage.

It is anticipated that the consultant will be required for 120 working days over FY16, starting from March 1, 2016 till June 30, 2016. Additional days may be added at the discretion of IFC.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-16T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1212460</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Resource Management Consultant</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415281</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212460</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415282</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212460</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0540</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">FIG - AFRICA - FMTAAS</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>