<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1212406</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-03T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-19T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1212406 - MOBILE CREDIT FOR MSMEs IN LIBERIA

Assignment Countries:
  - Liberia

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The firm will be responsible for the following specific tasks in the context of Liberia:

1.	Conduct analysis of the feasibility for the use of MNO data for credit scoring, with special focus on MSMEs. 
Often banks/MFIs lack the necessary data to assess the creditworthiness of MSMEs and the latter have challenges to get access to credit. Banks in Liberia are reluctant to extend credit, particularly to MSMEs, given weaknesses in the legal framework, weak property rights, limited collateral and credit reference systems, and their own limited capacity to appraise MSMEs and rural finance. The World Economic Forum's 2013 Global Competitiveness Index indicates access to finance was the business obstacle most frequently cited by Liberian enterprises. Similarly, the World Bank's BEEP Survey of enterprises 2009, showed access to finance as the main business environment constraint. In the 2015 Doing Business survey, Liberia ranked 160th for getting credit, down from 157th in 2014. Based on international experience, credit scoring models using MNO data can result in lower numbers of non-performing loans. The contracted firm should assess the potential of MNO data for MSME credit scoring both, from the supply side, as well as the demand side (focusing on MSMEs as customers).  

2.	Conduct analysis of the feasibility of and make recommendations for the use of the mobile as access channel for credit and the digitization of loan disbursements and repayments. 
Banks/MFIs can allow MSMEs to access the credit account via the mobile phone, either by offering on their own or in cooperation with MNOs a mobile banking channel. In addition they can use mobile money to disburse credits and/or allow for their repayment, again via their own or a third party mobile money solution. Finally, banks/MFIs can enable agents to accept loan applications on behalf of a bank or traditional MFI. The possibility of direct debit deductions of a portion of mobile payments received by a borrower for debt service might be explored. In all cases the efficiency is supposed to increase sufficiently, not only for the bank/MFI, but especially for the MSME, whose opportunity cost are often very high (especially if they have to close their business in order to travel to physical access points). The contracted firm should assess the potential of the mobile channel for MSME credit both, from the supply side, as well as the demand side (focusing on MSMEs as customers).  

3.	Conduct an analysis of the market potential for pay-as-you go financing for MSMEs.  
Especially in the utility sector there are an increasing number of companies who provide end-users (including MSMEs) financing of equipment (e.g. a solar panel), by linking the availability of the equipment to periodical repayments using mobile payments. If the end user fails to repay, the asset can be locked remotely. MSMEs, who might not be able to afford the initial investment, could offer their customers for example mobile phone charging services and repay for the equipment in small installments. By doing so, they build a credit history with the lender and the latter can base the decision to offer additional loans or financing of additional equipment on this data. The contracted firm should assess the potential of pay-as-you go financing both, from the supply side, as well as the demand side (focusing on MSMEs as customers).  

The assessment should address at least the following aspects for each of the tasks above: 
	Legal and regulatory framework
	Financial and ICT infrastructure
	Product design and market potential
	Available access channels and points 
	Financial capability of MSMEs


FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - Establishment of payment mechanisms for payments for Health Care Workers (HCWs) and Ebola Survivors and resumption of critical payment systems and services
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:

To be considered for this project, the firm must demonstrate capacity and capabilities in the following:
a.	Have expertise in MSME finance, payment systems in general and mobile money in specific.
b.	Be able to demonstrate a proven track-record of conducting assessments/studies and develop recommendations how to use innovative technologies to improve MSME access to finance and MSME access to transaction accounts and use of electronic payments 
c.	Demonstrate skills in project management.
d.	Ability to report to the World Bank effectively on progress of the work, including the submission of interim reports and the identification of noticeable difficulties.
e.	Have prior experience working in West Africa.
f.	Be ready to assume work as soon as possible.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-19T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1212406</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>MOBILE CREDIT FOR MSMEs IN LIBERIA</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">LR</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Liberia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415323</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212406</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0148</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Establishment of payment mechanisms for payments for Health Care Workers (HCWs) and Ebola Survivors and resumption of critical payment systems and services</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415322</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212406</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50595</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50596</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50597</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50598</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>