<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1212611</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-04T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-18T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1212611 - EGYPT ADR PROJECT - Publications

Assignment Countries:
  - Egypt, Arab Republic of

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Terms of Reference:  STC - Designer for The Credit Infrastructures Insolvency &amp; Debt Resolution Program Publications

A. Objectives/Purpose of Assignment 
The objective of this consultancy is to assist in the production of 2 publications on mediation that were developed as part of the Egypt ADR project. Since the Egypt ADR project is expected to close in June 2016, the publication and dissemination of these materials will be essential to ensuring the sustainability of results achieved by the Egypt ADR project. The publications will serve as a key reference material for continued education on mediation processes, ADR benefits and dispute systems design, and is expected to be used by ADR service providers, users and policy-makers in Egypt. 

Purpose of Assignment

The Credit Infrastructures Insolvency &amp; Debt Resolution Program is looking to hire a short term consultant to provide design, layout, and production of 2 publications.
	Mediation Essentials - in English
	Making Mediation Law &amp; Policy - in English

C. Scope of Work

The consultant is to provide design/layout/production of fresh and aesthetically appealing  reports: Mediation Essentials (94+ pages, 8.5 X 11 inches, 4-color cover and interior pages), and Making Mediation Law &amp; Policy (53+ pages, 8.5 X 11 inches, 4-color cover and interior pages), following the resident WBG Visual and Branding guidelines. The consultant must incorporate client updates, address placement issues, and ensure quality control. Specific deliverables and tasks include but are not limited to:

 Front and back cover production
 Format front matter materials and interior pages
 Enhance and incorporate 8 side boxes and 12 tables
 1st round of proofs/comps for review
 2nd round of proofs/comps for review/approval
 Final print ready files for web posting and printing


D. SPECIFIC INPUTS TO BE PRESENTED BY THE WORLD BANK GROUPS PROJECT TEAM

The World Bank Groups Project team will translate consultants reports and any necessary background material into Arabic/English as applicable.

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - BANK BUDGET
  - Alternate Dispute Resolution

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
 
The consultant should demonstrate the following: 

 Graduate degree in Graphic Designing, publications, Media or related fields;
 Prior work experience in international development, including with KM projects;
 Good knowledge of the WBG internal publication processes and policies;
 Excellent communication skills, both in oral presentation and in writing;
 Capacity to work simultaneously on a variety of issues and tasks, independently adjusting to priorities and achieving results with agreed objectives and deadlines;
 Strong interpersonal skills and ability to work effectively with internal/external partners;
 Fluency in English. 

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist, subject to availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-18T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1212611</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>EGYPT ADR PROJECT - Publications</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">EG</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Egypt, Arab Republic of</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415535</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212611</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415536</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212611</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF014693</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Alternate Dispute Resolution</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>