<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1212394</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-02T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-02-18T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1212394 - Global Landscaping Study on Interoperability

Assignment Countries:
  - (countries have not yet been selected)

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

CGAP is an independent policy and research center dedicated to advancing financial access for the world's poor.  It is supported by over 33 development agencies and private foundations who share a common mission to alleviate poverty.  Housed at the World Bank, CGAP  provides market intelligence, promotes standards, develops innovative solutions and advises governments, financial service providers, donors, and investors.
CGAP works toward a world in which poor people have full access to the financial services they need and are considered valued clients of their countrys financial system. We aim to help build efficient and equitable local financial markets that serve all poor people with convenient and affordable financial services, by helping to identify and build viable business models that leverage technology and existing infrastructure to reach poor people with a variety of financial services at scalewhat is sometimes referred to as digital financial services (DFS).

About the Project											
The financial inclusion community is betting on the building evidence that the shift towards digital financial inclusion will bring a range of tangible potential benefits . However in order for these benefits to be realized, digital payments need to compete with and ultimately become indistinguishable from cash as a means of payment. At the heart of this, digital payments must be accepted as a means of exchange by all, irrespective of the parties banked status, financial service provider or mobile phone operator . Interoperability in retail payments is critical for this vision, and for the digital payment rails to be leveraged towards a situation where households and businesses have access to and can effectively use a broad range of financial services.  
However at present the vast majority of emerging payment products that are suitable for low income people are not interoperable; and where progress has been made towards interoperability it is often limited to a specific use case (such as a person-to-person transfer between two mobile wallets) or type of institution (banks only or MNOs only); implemented in an inefficient manner which may limit affordability; or with business rules that fail to incentivize off-network transactions for all parties (including the sending provider and customer, and the receiving provider and customer).
While there are at least 15 active projects  working towards some form of interoperability in a range of countries, there is little consensus on some key issues including, for example the optimal process to work towards interoperability and the priority use cases from a financial inclusion perspective.
One result of these disconnected efforts is the creation of technical and commercial rules and systems that are isolated, with no clear sense of if / how they might converge over time. Furthermore, the various experiences of working towards interoperability have not been well documented and shared. What is lacking is an in-depth analysis of global interoperability initiatives, what various pathways have been followed and what evidence we have so far on what has succeeded and what has failed.
Therefore, CGAP is embarking on a project to provide a global landscaping of existing initiatives to achieve inclusion-effective interoperability. This project will collect global evidence about the current range of initiatives to achieve interoperability, a categorization of these initiatives (both for interoperability process as well as interoperability scheme or outcome), lessons on determinants of success and failure and an analysis of any best practices that emerge on effective interoperability to achieve financial inclusion.

PLEASE SEE THE ATTACHED DETAILED TOR.

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - BANK BUDGET
  - Inclusive Payments Ecosystems

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-02-18T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1212394</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Global Landscaping Study on Interoperability</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415159</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212394</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">415160</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1212394</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0194</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Inclusive Payments Ecosystems</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50565</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Prior experience working on global landscaping studies.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50566</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Deep understanding of the digital financial services and payments industry writ large, including a proven track record in research or consulting related to interoperability and/or payments architecture.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50567</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience working (consulting, research or direct employment) at a high level with regulators and financial service providers in emerging markets.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50568</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience drafting high-quality, accessible knowledge products around technical topics for a lay audience in the development space.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50569</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Strong understanding of the financial inclusion agenda and how interoperability fits into this.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50570</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Availability of key staff within the stipulated time frames for this work. Specific names and resumes of the team should be included.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>