<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1213878</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-24T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-03T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1213878 - Agricultural Specialist

Assignment Countries:
  - Uzbekistan

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Background:


Finance &amp; Market Global Practice

The Finance &amp; Markets Global Practice (F&amp;MGP) aims to help countries build deep, diversified, inclusive, efficient and stable financial systems, which are essential to promoting economic growth and reducing poverty and increasing shared prosperity. The practice is committed to delivering public and private sector tailored solutions to development challenges by leveraging the whole range of the Bank Group's financial, knowledge/advisory and convening services for clients. In doing so, the practice not only partners with the broader World Bank finance team (IFC, WB, MIGA and WB/IFC Treasuries) but also acts as an enabler for all of the other GPs and Cross-Cutting Groups. 

As a joint World Bank -IFC practice, the F&amp;MGP brings together the World Bank's knowledge, finance (loans, credits, guarantees, risk management products), and convening services, and IFC advisory in private-sector firms into a single suite of development solutions for our clients and the global community to support reaching the twin goals of eliminating extreme poverty and promoting shared prosperity. 

Today, this suite of financial solutions is in excess of US$10 billion in current and pipeline engagement commitments. We also have an ongoing portfolio of about 400 knowledge activities (with costs up to $73 million) and 98 IFC advisory services (valued at $136 million) 

Led by a Senior Director and two Directors, the practice is managed by a cadre of 14 Practice Managers who oversee its regional teams and global solutions groups, and CGAP, which has a dedicated Director. Thematically, the practice is organized into three global solutions groups. The first groups activities aimed at Strengthening the foundations of stable financial systems and markets by supporting global financial sector oversight frameworks and policies; strengthening banking regulation and restructuring regimes; improving financial sector integrity efforts and deepening capital markets, insurance, pensions and investment funds; the second Improving financial infrastructure and access through its work on credit infrastructures; payment and market infrastructures; responsible financial access: and SME finance, and the third on partnering with other practices on frontier development finance initiatives such as climate change finance, disaster risk finance and insurance, infrastructure finance, agriculture finance and housing finance.




The Project

The aim of the overall Project is to improve (a) access to finance and (b) access to markets for producers in 2 to 4 agricultural supply chains/products in the Kyrgyz Republic, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan. 

The goal will be met through work in two main areas which will form two key components of the Project: 
-	To increase access to finance for farmers and other agri supply chain participants by improving the capacity of Fls. 
-	To improve the bankability of farmers and other participants of supply chains (aggregators) by improving their capacity and access to markets. 
The Project will look at limited access to finance for farmers/producers from 2 perspectives: lack of skills/knowledge (of risks in agriculture and availability of relevant tools) in financial institutions (FIs) and low bankability of farmers/producers due to lack of capacity and lack of avenues to improve this capacity. To address this failure, the Project will provide advisory services to partner FIs to identify potential clients that match their criteria and provide assistance in preparing loan documentation. For this purpose, the Project has developed an web-based Cash-flow Linked Agri-Risk Assessment toolkit (CLARA).  

Objective of the Assignment

The Project is hiring an Agricultural Specialist (the Consultant) whose tasks will be to support the Project staff in developing detailed crop plans and coding in a special format that is used in CLARA. The Consultant will also engage with expert agronomists and collaborate with the Project teams specialists. 

Scope of Work and Activities

The Agricultural Specialist will compile relevant information regarding the specifications, analysis of agro-techniques and processing of agricultural products, calculations concerning application of fertilizers norms, detail labor types and costs for targeted crops and will have to account for the following factors of crop production according to PFIs needs:
k)	Countrys agri-climatic zones/ soil types;
l)	Irrigated/ non-irrigated land;
m)	Common land tillage types;
n)	Seasonality in production e.g. annual dry- and wet-season period;
o)	Typical crop plan for each crop, showing dependence on agri-climatic zone, soil type, season, tillage type, irrigation, yield level, and listing all field operations and operations at the farm to grow the crop, and their normal start and end dates;
p)	Details on each operation, in particular manual or mechanized, productivity per shift, number of workers needed, type of equipment used;
q)	Labor cost data based on categories of workers;
r)	Equipment data with types of equipment, its productivity and fuel consumption;
s)	Inputs usage plan for each crop, showing volume of seeds, fertilizers and plant protection agents needed to grow the crop depending on agri-climatic zone, soil type, season, tillage type, irrigation, and target yield level;
t)	Other tasks and duties as required: The TOR may be adjusted to meet the Projects requirements. 

Deliverables: The following deliverables are expected from the Consultant:

d)	Detailed crop plans for targeted 14 horticultural crops in Uzbekistan; 
e)	Coding of agri-technology cards to be uploaded in CLARA 
f)	Report on work completed covering above-mentioned tasks.


Special Terms &amp; Conditions / Specific Requirements

During the proposed engagement, the Consultant will be supported by and will report to the Project Manager. 

The WBG will provide office space, communications and other resources required for smooth implementation of the assignment in the Uzbekistan. 


Length and Duration of the Assignment

The length of this assignment is estimated at 45 working days between March 14, 2016  June 30, 2016.

H.	Qualification and Experience Requirements:

-	M.Sc. degree in agricultural field; 
-	Practical expertise in agronomy and agri-economics relevant to the whole country and multiple crops;
-	Substantial data management expertise: using MS Excel and relational databases;
-	Experience in agricultural data collection and analysis
-	Strong analytical and problem-solving skills;
-	Demonstrated ability to set priorities and to work with minimum supervision in order to meet changing deadlines;
-	Fluent in Uzbek and Russian, English is preferential.

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - BANK BUDGET
  - Austria: Central Asia Agrifinance Project (CAAP)

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist, subject to availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-03T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1213878</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Agricultural Specialist</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">UZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Uzbekistan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">417985</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213878</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">417986</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213878</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF015740</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Austria: Central Asia Agrifinance Project (CAAP)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>