<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1213191</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-14T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-01T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST (EOI)
CONSULTANT SERVICES
2016
THE WORLD BANK
AFGHANISTAN RECONSTRUCTION TRUST FUND (ARTF)
Request for Expressions of Interest
 MONITORING AGENT
Background
  The $ 8.6 billion Afghanistan Reconstruction Trust Fund (ARTF) is financed by more than 33 donors and administered by the World Bank.  Projects funded by the Trust Fund are approved by a Management Committee comprised of the: Asian Development Bank, Islamic Development Bank, United Nations Development Programme, and World Bank.  As Administrator of the ARTF, the World Bank is responsible for ensuring that satisfactory fiduciary controls are in place to manage the funds disbursed from the ARTF to the Government.  
Overall, the ARTF finances two major types of eligible expenditures:
	Recurrent Costs: This component finances civil service salaries, operations and maintenance costs for government agencies and departments, non-project technical assistance, and other recurrent and capital expenditures in the ordinary government budget.  

	Investments and Programs:  This component finances high-priority studies and investment activities under the national development budget deemed to be essential to support the overall investment portfolio in Afghanistan.  

Purpose
The World Bank is seeking to put in place an arrangement for third party monitoring of the Recur-rent Cost Component of the ARTF for a period beyond June 15, 2016 as a Monitoring Agent (MA) has been contracted by the Bank to monitor these recurrent costs until June 15, 2016.  The monitor-ing agent will be an agent of the Bank, reporting directly to the Bank, but will work closely with the line ministries and line departments responsible for recurrent cost budget implementation. 

 The assignment is both an agreed upon procedures engagement and a compilation engagement in which an auditing firm will for the former carry out procedures of an audit nature to which firm and the World Bank have agreed and to report on factual findings and for the latter to collect, clas-sify and summarize financial information from the Governments accounting records on the recur-rent cost budget operations. The audit firm will comply with the Code of Ethics for Professional Accountants, issued by IFAC and conduct the agreed upon procedures engagement in accordance with International Standards on Related Services 4400  and the terms of the reference of the con-tract and prepare the financial reports in accordance with International Standards on Related Ser-vices 4410 and the terms of the contract. 

The precise agreed upon procedures and required reports will be set out in the Terms of Reference at the Request for Proposal stage but selecting test samples basis on the assessment of the control framework relating to the recurrent cost expenditures payments made both in Kabul and the prov-inces and carrying out the verification on the basis of this assessment in proportion to the expendi-tures incurred in those locations and the assessment of control risk and reporting. 



Scope 
Major responsibilities of the Monitoring Agent will include, but not be limited to:
	Expedite and monitor payment applications to the World Bank related to eligible expendi-tures
	Review compliance with government and ARTF requirements in expenditure approvals and processing
	Review compliance with government and ARTF procurement guidelines in notifying and selecting bidders, and in awarding  contract 
	Verify payrolls against the civil service headcount database
	Inform the Ministry of Finance and the specific entities monitored on the nature of excep-tions and advise on steps to improve compliance with eligibility rules
	Prepare monthly and quarterly financial  reports which indicate the entities and locations subjected to testing,  size of transaction samples tested, results of testing and inferences on the overall compliance with eligibility rates of the civilian recurrent costs for payroll and non-payroll costs separately
	Periodically brief the Bank team on progress and outstanding issues
	Report on emerging issues and actions needed; flag critical issues to the Bank
	Make presentations on the approach to monitoring and results of monitoring to the Man-agement Committee at quarterly donors meeting if required.
	Maintain the civil service headcount database at the Ministry of Finance, supervise data en-try, perform consistency checks with other sources of information, ensure production of timely reports to satisfy the fiduciary standards.
(there is team of 17 locally engaged staff who do this work at present)

The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing Monitoring Agent services for the Afghanistan Reconstruction Trust Fund, as administered by the World Bank.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).
Mandatory Qualification Criteria
	Demonstrated monitoring expertise: Provide information showing the firms extensive re-cent experience in undertaking auditing engagements of public sector donor funded spend-ing with at least five years experience in auditing and two years of experience in fragile countries. Candidates should also be able to draw on experience in other developing coun-tries bringing best practices perspective to this work. 
	Project team qualifications: Provide information demonstrating availability of a team of accountants and national deputies to be based or stationed in Kabul and with capacity to travel to provinces in Afghanistan and communicate in the local language. Accountants and national deputies to be fielded should be certified accountants or possess relevant pro-fessional certification); have at least 5 years experience in auditing or monitoring person-nel/payroll expenditures and procurement in largely decentralized operations.
	Ability to mobilize rapidly in Afghanistan: Demonstrate the firms capacity to mobilize teams rapidly and begin monitoring in all 34 provinces in Afghanistan as of the start date through local presence and/or network in the country, among others.. 

Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications. If consultants intend to associate with other firms, they are invited to state in their EoI the composition and form of the association and indicate a lead firm.
The main part of the EoI must be submitted electronically in eConsultant. All attachments to the submission should be limited to PDF files not larger than 10MB.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-01T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1213191</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>AFGHANISTAN RECONSTRUCTION TRUST FUND (ARTF)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">AF</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Afghanistan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416610</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213191</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416611</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213191</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF050578</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">AFGHANISTAN RECONSTRUCTION TRUST FUND (ARTF) - MONITORING AGENT FEES TF.</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50860</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">	Demonstrated monitoring expertise: Provide information showing the firms extensive re-cent experience in undertaking auditing engagements of public sector donor funded spend-ing with at least five years experience in auditing and two years of experience in fragile countries. Candidates should also be able to draw on experience in other developing coun-tries bringing best practices perspective to this work.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50861</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">	Project team qualifications: Provide information demonstrating availability of a team of accountants and national deputies to be based or stationed in Kabul and with capacity to travel to provinces in Afghanistan and communicate in the local language. Accountants and national deputies to be fielded should be certified accountants or possess relevant pro-fessional certification); have at least 5 years experience in auditing or monitoring person-nel/payroll expenditures and procurement in l</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50862</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Ability to mobilize rapidly in Afghanistan: Demonstrate the firms capacity to mobilize teams rapidly and begin monitoring in all 34 provinces in Afghanistan as of the start date through local presence and/or network in the country, among others..</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50863</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>