<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1213305</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-19T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-06T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1213305 - PROGRAM SUPPORT OFFICER - FIG Advisory Bangladesh

Assignment Countries:
  - Bangladesh

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

We are now recruiting for a Program Support Officer to support FIG's ongoing and new projects in Bangladesh. The consultant will work with the IFC Project team in the implementation of the project(s).  Specifically the consultant will serve as the point person based in Dhaka, working with the Project team, and supporting the project client(s)/partner(s) in building and maintaining relationships with the Insurance Companies, Banks/MFIs, and NBFCs that will be involved in the Program. The Consultant will be responsible for assisting and co-leading all project related activities on the program and providing technical advisory on discreet project components.
The indicative but not exhaustive details including the scope of work could be as:
	Support the Project Leader (PL) in the management of the project - closely communicate with IFC managing team/PL, clients, consultants, FIs of any issues in need of follow-up during course of project implementation; provide advice and initiative in the solving of issues/problems that arise during project implementation.
	Under supervision of PL, work with client in preparing project reports on a semi-annual basis &amp; co-ordinate amongst various internal IFC teams; monitor and track project expenditures as per project plan on a monthly basis, work with Finance department/accounts to adjust as necessary budget allocations on semi-annual basis, submit monthly expenditure reports to PL.
	Take the lead as the IFC focal point between IFC client(s), and partners of the project in organizing meetings and insurance/business continuity plan (BCP) trainings for the identified and interested financial institutions (FIs) and distribution channel partners.
	Support (as required) the IFC team in identification, selection &amp; coordination of External Experts/Consultant firms whose services might be required, for undertaking specific deliverables of the overall Project.
	Lead the planning and tracking of the individual projects in design and implementation for cost effectiveness, communication, risk analysis, quality assurance, team and vendor management.
	Identify and resolves issues related to the individual work streams and activities within. 
	Provide technical assistance to clients on MSME Banking/ Women focused financial products/ Insurance/ Risk Management/ Digital Financial Services, as and when required.
	Create and evaluate project related newsletters, project tools, and reporting format. 
	Support project success through management and deployment of work stream leaders.
	Sustain strong ongoing relationships with client middle and senior management during project delivery.
	Other tasks related to clients and IFC team support as needs arise.    

3.	Deliverables / Specific outputs


The Consultant shall be able to assist in the development and deliver the following:
	Program plan covering all work streams
	Monitoring tools and dashboard 
	Status reporting formats
	Day-to-day client meetings 
	Periodical project updates for internal reporting
	Support in business development
	Any other project / program related deliverables 

4.	Qualifications 

The potential candidates will be reviewed based on the following selection criteria:
	Masters-level degree in Business, Economics, Management, or related required.
	At least 5 to 8 years of professional working experience.
	Experience working with Insurance companies or financial institutions, knowledge of the Bangladesh banking/MFI sector, Insurance sector and key stakeholders, and experience working with both public and private sector clients is strongly desired.
	Experience of providing technical advisory in areas like MSME Banking/ Women focused Banking/ Insurance/ Risk Management/ Digital Financial Services, etc.
	Familiarity with Project Management, including identification, appraisal, implementation and supervision of advisory services projects.
	Ability to work as a team, and with people of diverse backgrounds from different parts of the world.
	Must be a self-starter, willing to take initiative and be resourceful and imaginative in providing solutions to clients.
	Experience with monitoring and evaluation concepts and reporting templates a distinct advantage.
	Familiarity with donor funding and reporting processes.
	Experience working in developing countries.
	Readiness to travel to rural / interior areas across Bangladesh.
	Excellent communication skills, including written/detailed report writing and oral presentation skills.
	Fluency in Bangla and English is mandatory.  

5.	Location:  Dhaka, Bangladesh

The consultant would be appointed for a maximum of 150 working days in one Financial Year (July to June). Based upon satisfactory review of performance, budget availability and project progress the contract may be renewed for another term, solely in accordance with IFCs policies and procedures. 

6.	Reporting Line

The consultant will report to Project Leader(s) based in New Delhi/ Mumbai/ Dhaka offices.



FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services.

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist, subject to availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-06T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1213305</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>PROGRAM SUPPORT OFFICER - FIG Advisory Bangladesh</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">BD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Bangladesh</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">417200</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213305</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF013253</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">25</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TA To CITY Bank</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">417201</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213305</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017648</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">25</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TA TO IDLC</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">417199</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213305</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">417202</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213305</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF018183</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">25</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SCF PPCR Agri Bangladesh</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">417203</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213305</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0474</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">25</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Bangladesh Phase II</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>