<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1213073</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-16T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-01T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW: 
Qualitative/Interview Data Collection for Sunaula Hazar Din Community Action for Nutrition Project in Nepal

Assignment Title: 1213073 - Qualitative/Interview Data Collection for Sunaula Hazar Din Community Action for Nutrition Project in Nepal

Assignment Countries:  Nepal

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The objective of this assignment is to collect high quality qualitative data on situations, activities, and perceptions of SHD stakeholders, including participating community members and project staff including coaches (facilitators). The collected qualitative/interview data will be the foundation for a qualitative assessment to be conducted by the World Bank team which aims at further drawing lessons and implications for the on-going SHD project design and implementation.

The selected firm is required to organize several small research teams to conduct a series of field visits in selected communities across 6 districts of Nepal, covering both Terai and Hill regions. The qualitative data collection instruments (including focus group discussions, key informant interviews, etc.) will be drafted by the World Bank, to which the selected firm will provide inputs. It is particularly important that the firm will be able to pay attention to cultural and social dynamics of the target communities while collecting the data.  

At the end of the assignment, the firm is required to provide: 
-Full transcription/translation of the qualitative/interview data collected (final output in English) 
-A short summary report on the data collection process and observations from the field research teams



FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s): QUALITATIVE STUDY FOR NEPAL SHD-CANP

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply: The attention of interested Consultants is drawn to paragraph 1.9 of the World Banks Guidelines: Selection and Employment of Consultants under IBRD Loans and IDA Credits &amp; Grants by World Bank Borrowers, January 2001 (Consultant Guidelines), setting forth the World Banks policy on conflict of interest.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm or academic institution.

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services by submitting their Expressions of Interest (EOI) in English, electronically through World Bank Group econsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index/html). 
Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (description of similar assignments in implementation of qualitative studies, experience in similar conditions and context, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals to comprise the team). EOIs should be no more than 20 pages including all annexes (but excluding CVs). 
The EOI would be reviewed on the basis of the following to prepare a short list:   
-	Registration of the Firm
-	Availability of the key professionals (see the suggested team composition) 
-	Availability of resources in the firm
-	Experience of the Firm in similar tasks (i.e., qualitative/interview data collection and management) 
-	Experience and knowledge of the Firm in related areas of development projects (rural development, health and nutrition improvement, community-based approaches in Nepal and other countries, participatory approaches)
-	Understanding and experience in nutrition situations and challenges especially in the context of Nepal
-	Experience of the Firm in other tasks
-	Support services of the Firm (ICT and logistics)
-	Proven record in delivering tasks under tight deadlines

The Firm is suggested to build a research team consisting of: a Team Leader with extensive experience in designing and implementing similar qualitative data collection, who will be responsible for the overall management and delivery of the assignment; a Logistics officer with extensive experience and knowledge in Nepal (and ideally in the survey areas) as well as in supporting training/field data collection preparation and organization, and; field researchers (including field supervisor and enumerators): with demonstrable skills, experience and performances in collecting qualitative data (e.g., conducting focus group discussions, structured interviews and field observations). Each team must comprise of at least one female researcher. 

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

QUALIFICATION CRITERIA
	1. Strong and proven experience of the firm in research design, qualitative research methods, surveying and analysis; research experience in Nepal/targeted regions in Nepal preferred. (30%)
	2.  Experience in design/implementation of qualitative surveys/data collection of rural development, participatory approach, community-based nutrition activities, particularly in the country, is a plus. This will be based on the CVs of key professionals. (40%)
	3.  Proven experience in training/mobilizing high quality enumerators, for field survey/data collection implementation, especially in the local language and the use of ICT. (20%)
	4. Previous experience in working with government departments, international organizations and donors and evidence of report writing for an international audience are required. (10%)


CONTACT INFORMATION:
Kaori Oshima: (koshima@worldbank.org)
Manav Bhattarai (mbhattarai@worldbank.org) 

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-01T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1213073</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Qualitative/Interview Data Collection for Sunaula Hazar Din Community Action for Nutrition Project in Nepal</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">NP</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Nepal</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416381</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213073</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">416382</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213073</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1374</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">QUALITATIVE STUDY FOR NEPAL SHD-CANP</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50796</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50797</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50798</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">50799</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>