<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1213957</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-02-25T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-04T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Chronic malnutrition in Ecuador is a prominent development challenge with irreversible consequences on physical, neurological and emotional development of future generations. In 2010, 22.6% of children in Ecuador were affected by chronic malnutrition. Qualitative and quantitative research in recent years has identified a lack of parental knowledge of good nutritional practices, and behavioral barriers as key determinants of malnutrition.

The Texting for Nutrition is an innovative intervention that uses mobile technology to disseminate tailored messages to promote good nutrition practices among parents in rural and urban mostly poor households in Chimborazo, Ecuador. Caregivers of children between the ages of 0-3 registered for the program in the last quarter of 2014. Throughout 2015, registered caregivers received text messages sharing new information and encouraging behavior change along several key areas: 1) Regular visits to health centers, 2) micronutrients, 3) water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH), 4) diet diversity and complementary feeding, and 5) exclusive breast feeding during the first six months of life.

The Texting for Nutrition project is currently on-going and set to conclude in March 2016. Both the program and an accompanying impact evaluation have been implemented through collaboration between the World Bank, the Province Council of Chimborazo (HCPCH), and Ecuadorian Ministries of Health, Coordination (MCDS), and Social and Economic Inclusion (MIES). 

The impact evaluation will estimate the effects of the Texting for Nutrition program on (i) knowledge of good health and nutrition practices, (ii) influencing parental behavior (iii) social customs &amp; descriptive norms towards health/nutrition practices for their children and (iv) the nutritional status of the children.

The selected data collection firm will complete tasks within two primary objectives: 
1) Collect high quality household and individual data, and 
2) Train the local TDI survey team in data collection best practices, building local capacity. 

To satisfy objective one, the survey firm will work in collaboration with the World Bank to conduct all components of data collection including field work planning, hiring enumerators, supervisors, and field managers, enumerator training, overseeing data collection field work, transportation of survey team, and data entry.


The task team is seeking a survey firm that has the following types of previous experience and expertise:
1)	At least five years of experience conducting panel studies with sample sizes of over 2,000 individuals.  
2)	Experience conducting household quantitative data collection in Ecuador, preferably with experience conducting field work in the province of Chimborazo, Ecuador.
3)	Highly trained staff including statistician with sampling expertise, data entry team, field coordinators with experience implementing large N quantitative studies in the field of health and nutrition or comparable social sciences.
4)	Experience working on research of mobile phone interventions and their impacts on social outcomes is an additional factor that is highly desirable.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-04T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1213957</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Texting for Nutrition: Impact Evaluation Data Collection</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">EC</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Ecuador</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">418153</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213957</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">418154</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1213957</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0918</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Country WASH Poverty Diagnostic - Ecuador</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">51070</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment. The firm should have at least five years of experience conducting panel studies with sample sizes of over 2,000 individuals. The firm should demonstrate experience conducting household quantitative data collection in Ecuador, preferably with experience conducting field work in the province of Chimborazo, Ecuador. Experience working on research of mobile phone interventions and their impacts on social outcomes is</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">51073</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff. Highly trained staff including statistician with sampling expertise, data entry team, field coordinators with experience implementing large N quantitative studies in the field of health and nutrition or comparable social sciences.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">51072</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>