<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1214304</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-03-02T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-17T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>PURPOSE OF ASSIGNMENT
The World Bank Group is implementing a five year Local Content Development Project linked to investments in Kenyas nascent oil and gas (O&amp;G) sector. The objective of the project is to enhance the development impact of the O&amp;G sector through improving the ability of the local private sector to supply goods and services to the O&amp;G sector, thereby increasing domestic income and employment. This is part of a wider World Bank project to strengthen the capacity of the Government of Kenya to manage its petroleum sector and wealth for sustainable development impacts. 

The WBG is hiring an individual consultant as a project coordinator and technical lead with experience in developing and managing SME capacity development and local content projects.  This individual will manage the project from the start, setting up a public-private oversight committee, undertaking stakeholder outreach, as well as designing, running, and monitoring the projects technical work. 

PROJECT BACKGROUND
Large O&amp;G investment projects can and often do create business opportunities for local companies up and down supply and distribution chains. The Kenya Local Content Development Project is focused on increasing the development impact of the O&amp;G sector by maximizing business opportunities for the Kenyan private sector during the development and operation phases of Kenyas O&amp;G sector. 

This typically involves assessments of large firms supply chains, including their demand for goods and services, followed by assessments of the capacity of local firms to supply what is needed. Local content projects subsequently focus on:
- identifying opportunities for local enterprises to compete for contracts with large O&amp;G firms and their lead contractors; 
- capacity building and support to local enterprises to develop a pool of competitive suppliers/enterprises;
- integrating participating local firms into O&amp;G firms supply chains.

CORE ACTIVITIES
The project coordinator will be required to:
- Work with O&amp;G companies to understand internal local procurement needs and procedures  
- Conduct in-depth analysis of Kenyan supply sectors 
- Oversee SME mapping exercises to categorize SMEs by industry, location, experience
- Create an SME database with this information
- Analyze capacity-building needs of SMEs and identify appropriate service providers
- Understand other barriers to SME growth, such as access to finance, and develop means of addressing them
- Identify and facilitate hiring processes for consultants/firms necessary to build SME capacity
- Supervise day-to-day activities of consultants and ensure successful completion of high quality deliverables
- Act as liaison for the project between Government of Kenya ministries, the private sector and other key strategic partners
- Undertake stakeholder outreach through a mix of media
- Oversee project staff and contractors, ensuring high quality, on-time delivery 
- Manage project budget.

DELIVERABLES
The consultant will be required to complete the following deliverables, among others:
- Develop 6-12 month project implementation plans 
- Ensure successful completion of diagnostic and analytical work
- Manage implementation and completion of initiatives undertaken by the project
- Ensure successful completion and internal sign-off on deliverables undertaken by contracted consulting firms 
- Provide progress update briefs, monitoring implementation and flagging issues
- Undertake analytics on key topics, developing memos for senior level counterparts
- Develop content for and hold stakeholder workshops
- Other deliverables as agreed with project leads over the course of the consulting engagement.

REQUIRED EXPERIENCE &amp; SKILLS
- Minimum 8 years of professional experience in relevant areas
- Minimum 3 years of experience in coordinating/implementing economic development projects, including SME development projects, preferably in extractive industries
- Economics, business or comparable degree
- Strong analytical, technical writing and public presentation skills  
- Proven project management skills, including planning, coordinating, monitoring and reporting
- Experience working with procurement departments or with large commercial firms, preferably in extractive industries
- Strong stakeholder communication skills
- Proven ability to work with partners (donors, bi-lateral organizations, governments)
- Proven ability to operate effectively and independently with remote supervision.

REPORTING
The position reports to Aref Adamali (Regional Economist) and a secondary WBG staff member (depending on the specific activity).</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-17T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1214304</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Kenya Local Content Development Project</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">KE</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kenya</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">418830</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1214304</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>