<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1214313</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-03-03T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-03-14T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1214313 - Short Term Consultants for IFC Public Private Partnership Advisory Services- Vientiane , Laos

The International Finance Corporation (IFC), a member of the World Bank Group, is the largest global development institution focused on the private sector in developing countries. It is committed to financing private sector businesses in emerging markets, mobilizing capital in the international financial markets, helping clients improve social and environmental sustainability and providing advisory services to businesses and governments.

The Cross-Cutting Advisory Solutions (CAS) Department is managing and delivering expertise and programs which are cross-cutting in nature and have application across the Corporation. These include public-private partnership transactions, clean energy and resources efficiency, SME development, corporate finance, gender and multidisciplinary business solutions. The Department also provides administrative and financial management support to all advisory units in IFC and in the joint World Bank Group Global Practices. 

IFCs Public-Private Partnership (PPP) Advisory Services Division advises governments in designing and bringing to market commercially robust PPP projects that provide high quality, affordable and efficient infrastructure and social services to the public. Drawing on more than 25 years of experience in implementing 360 projects in 102 countries, the Division currently has over 100 staff across the globe, with technical, financial, contractual and procurement expertise. The team is managing around 100 active client engagements to help national and municipal governments partner with the private sector to improve basic services such as electricity, health, education, sanitation, and roads. IFCs PPP unit also draws on the World Banks expertise in institutional reforms, sector structuring, legal and regulatory frameworks, tariff structures and regulation, and international best practice to strengthen and complement IFCs transaction-oriented approach.

The Asia-Pacific region of the IFC PPP Division encompassed the whole of Asia and Pacific, including the Indian Subcontinent, China and the ASEAN region but excluding Central Asia and the Middle East.

Please see the following website for more information: http://www.ifc.org/wps/wcm/connect/Industry_EXT_Content/IFC_External_Corporate_Site/PPP



Assignment Countries:
  - Lao People's Democratic Republic

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

IFC Seeks to hire Short Term Consultants (STCs) to help originate and execute Public Private Partnership (PPP) projects across the Asia pacific Region. These consultants will work as core team members in IFC Business Develop Initiatives and PPP Project Execution related activities. The consultants will be based in:

1. Vientiane , Laos

It must be noted that the STCs may be required to travel and work on projects across the Asia Pacific region or even globally and may not be restricted to their base locations.

SCOPE OF WORK

The work will be equivalent to that of a financial analyst in investment banks and is to be undertaken is broken into the following phases as outlined below: 

 The Consultants will be expected to work with the IFC Public Private Partnership (PPP) Advisory Team 
 Conduct industry, market and regulatory research particularly in the infrastructure and social sectors (e.g. power, transportation, water, health, etc.) and prepare financial analysis reports and presentations in PowerPoint, MS Word and MS Excel format
 Extract information from relevant financial databases 
 Develop and Review financial models and  reports


FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following trust fund(s):
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Selection and contracting will normally be made from responses to this notification.  The consultant will be selected from a shortlist, subject to availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-03-14T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1214313</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Short Term Consultants for IFC Public Private Partnership Advisory Services- Vientiane , Laos</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">LA</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Lao People's Democratic Republic</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">419002</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1214313</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>