<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1230292</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-20T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-20T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1230292 - Development of curriculum and training materials for a Ph.D. program in Educational Measurement and Evaluation

Assignment Countries:
  - Russian Federation

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The goal of the assignment is to develop an international level capacity for training of professionals at a Ph.D. level in Russia in Educational Measurement and Evaluation area. Specific objectives of the assignment are to establish a Ph.D. (Philosophy Doctor) program in Educational Measurement and Evaluation. Specific activities of the assignment include:
1.	Development of a detailed concept for the program based on an analysis of best international experiences. The concept should include:
a.	Demand evaluation for Ph.D. program graduates;
b.	A list of courses (both mandatory and elective) with the description of the content and learning outcomes;
c.	Training materials for the delivery of the courses;
d.	Detailed description of the modality(ies) of delivery and teaching methods;
e.	A list of staff qualifications to deliver the program;
f.	A list of proposed research topics for the students to include the topics that are relevant for development aid recipient countries;
g.	Detailed admission requirements for applicants.
2.	Conduct an international workshop to present and validate the concept.
3.	Develop a detailed action plan for concept implementation.
4.	Complete selection of staff for delivery of the program courses. 
5.	Develop a staff training plan for course delivery, and deliver the first stage of the training plan.
6.	Complete design of the courses materials to include also an international review of course materials.
7.	Draft action plan for placement of Ph.D. graduates. 

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment/services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
The contract award will be based on (i) academic qualifications and experience of key staff, their research record in the area of educational measurement and evaluation and the academic credentials of invited faculty; (ii) the quality of the Programs proposal presented to the selection committee; and (iii) existing record of international partnerships of participating universities. The proposal should demonstrate sustainability regarding the ability to generate financial support for program delivery and placement of program graduates. 

The World Bank will accept applications for this assignment from Russian University as a lead partner, together with correspondence from a proposed International University confirming its commitment to participate in the program, allocate necessary faculty and staff and offer its program validation procedures for the programs to be developed. Given that Russia is a Bologna signatory country a partner institution grounded in another Bologna country will be an advantage. Using ECTS, agreed learning outcomes, Diploma supplement, joint modalities for recognition are expected. Previous experience in the partnering in the joint delivery of graduate programs would be considered as an advantage. 

The eligibility requirement for Russian University to participate in the partnership for this assignment includes the existence of accredited graduate program(s) in educational measurement and evaluation area. 

Possibility of making a joint degree (double degree or dual degree or, at least, degree validated by partnering University) Ph.D. program with granting a Ph.D. diploma of partnering international university will be considered as an advantage as well.

INDIVIDUAL / ORGANIZATION PROFILE
The consultant will be an organization. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible organizations to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested organizations must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested organizations are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified organizations will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those organizations which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief would be provided to organizations which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-20T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1230292</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Development of curriculum and training materials for a PhD program in Educational Measurement and Evaluation</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">RU</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Russian Federation</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">449685</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1230292</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">55865</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">55864</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">55866</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">55867</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>