<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1230699</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-10-26T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-11-17T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSON OF INTEREST

The Common Wealth of Dominica

Consultancy Services for Developing a Risk-based Road Infrastructure Asset Management System

The Government of the Commonwealth of Dominica (GoCD) has received grant funding from the Government of Italy through the World Bank to build the capacity of the Ministry of Public Works and Ports (MoPWP) and put in place appropriate infrastructure management tools, following damages caused by Tropical Storm Erika, which occurred on August 27. 2015, and intends to apply part of the proceeds of this grant to payments under the contract for provision of consultancy services for setting up a computerized risk-based road infrastructure Asset Management System (AMS) in the MoPWP.

The objective of the Consultancy assignment is to implement a sustainable computerized risk-based AMS that will support effective decision making in prioritizing road infrastructure investment options at strategic, tactical and operations levels of asset management. The scope of the consultancy services shall include but not be limited to the following:

-Implementing a AMS that is user friendly and tailored to the needs of the GoCD and other stakeholders, incorporates a central database with a Geographical Information System (GIS) interface for storage and management of asset data and provides decision making functions for prioritizing investment needs based on multi-objective criteria such as asset criticality, vulnerability to landslide and flood risks, budgets and cost benefit analysis amongst others. The system should be an adaptation of an existing AMS, using open source applications or components as much as is practicable.

-In addition to standard pavement and structure management, the AMS will need to incorporate landslide and flood risks to roads and bridges using a well-established methodology.

-Collecting (i) standard pavement and structural conditions, and (ii) landslide and flood hazard/vulnerability data along 321 kms of primary roads, 74 kms of secondary roads, 158 kms of urban roads and 338 kms of feeder roads.

-Testing the AMS with the data collected on GoCD roads and bridges.

-Developing a plan and/or procedures for the MoPWP for data collection and using the AMS for prioritizing road asset investment options at network, program, and project levels and for project monitoring and evaluation.

-Developing a 5-year road infrastructure rehabilitation and maintenance investment plan using the collected data and the AMS.

-Transferring and embedding knowledge to MoPWP through close working collaboration, ensuring counterpart staff are actively involved in all key activities including data collection and analysis, as well as system implementation amongst others.

The consultancy contract period is expected to be about 10 months.

The Commonwealth of Dominica through the World Bank now invites eligible consulting firms (Consultants) to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested Consultants should provide information demonstrating that they have the required qualifications and relevant experience to perform the services. The short list criteria are:

-Specific experience in road infrastructure Asset Management Systems;
-Experience with successfully institutionalizing a road Asset Management System in an emerging or developing country would be an advantage;
-Experience in highways, rural roads and bridges in the last 5 years;
-Experience in landslide and flood hazard assessment in the last 5 years;
-Experience in vulnerability/impact analysis of roads and bridges to landslide and flood risks in the last 5 years;
-Experience in preparing road investment plans in the last 5 years;
-Experience in working in Caribbean region or similar developing country context is an added advantage

Consultants should provide information such as their roles in executing the above services whether as a sole provider or a partner in a joint venture indicating percentage by value of its share of services provided; provide details of scope of services of each assignment to demonstrate suitability for this assignment. Statements of related assignments completed in the last five years. Consultants may associate with other firms in the form of a joint venture or a sub-consultancy to enhance their qualifications.

The attention of interested Consultants is drawn to the World Banks policy on conflict of interest as set out in paragraph 1.9 of the Consultant Guidelines: Selection and Employment of Consultants under IBRD Loans and IDA Credits &amp; Grants by World Bank Borrowers, January 2011.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-11-17T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1230699</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Developing a Risk-Based Asset Management System to Improve the Resilience and Affordability of Roads and Bridges in the Common Wealth of Dominica</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">DM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Dominica</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">450685</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1230699</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">450686</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1230699</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A2069</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Improving the Resilience and Affordability of Roads and Bridges</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56017</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Specific experience in road infrastructure Asset Management Systems.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56018</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience with successfully institutionalizing a road Asset Management System in an emerging or developing country would be an advantage.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56019</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in highways, rural roads and bridges in the last 5 years.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56020</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in landslide and flood hazard assessment in the last 5 years.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56033</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in vulnerability/impact analysis of roads and bridges to landslide and flood risks in the last 5 years.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56034</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in preparing road investment plans in the last 5 years.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56035</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in working in Caribbean region or similar developing country context is an added advantage.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">7</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>