<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231617</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-09T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-11-21T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1231617 - Ethiopia Scaling Solar Tax Consultant

Assignment Countries:
  - Ethiopia

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

IFC has been appointed as lead advisor to advise Ethiopian Electric Power to procure up to 500MW of solar PV on an IPP basis.  

IFC is seeking a consultant to provide tax advice on the transaction.  The engagement will be split into two phases: Phase I - a due diligence and transaction structuring phase and Phase II - implementation and tendering.

Phase 1 Objective: review and advise on applicable tax and accounting regimes and provide recommendations for the selected transaction structure

Phase 2 Objective: respond to tax and accounting clarification questions of the potential bidders by providing technical input or answering queries of prospective bidders as required.

Specifically, the envisioned tasks would include 
Phase 1  Due diligence and transaction structuring
1.	Analyse applicable tax laws, providing a summary of the applicable tax regime, including a list of all taxes which would, under the laws of Ethiopia (without taking into account the effects of any international taxation treaties), typically be required to be paid, collected or levied by a limited liability company established under the laws of Ethiopia to: 

-	engage all necessary domestic or expatriate employees;
-	be owned by one or more domestic or international investors who expect to remit dividends and/or shareholder loan repayments;
-	raise finance from international banks and/or financial institutions;
-	design, insure, construct, own, operate and maintain a generation facility which is similar to the proposed solar PV plants at the proposed sites;
-	benefit from rights under agreements relating to the acquisition, grant or other provision of land for the project sites;
-	engage contractors (whether domestic or international) employing such employees as such contractor considers necessary or appropriate; 
-	use imported materials and equipment; and
-	connect to the grid system and sell electricity.

2.	Propose options for the structuring / shareholding of the project company for each project, based on the Consultants previous PPP experience and tax and accounting analysis, as well as the reports from the other consultants, recognising that for this project EEP is proposing to form the project companies itself and to sell / issue a majority shareholding in each company to the relevant winning bidder, with a view to retaining a minority shareholding (approximately 20%) in each company itself.

3.	Provide details of any incentives potentially available to the projects, including but not limited to accelerate tax depreciation allowances or corporate income tax holidays.
The output will be shared with all bidders in a competitive process to tender the project and will allow bidders to build their financial models to determine their bid tariff and for bidders/lenders to understand the tax and accounting implications of the Project.


Phase 2  Implementation and tendering:

1.	Provide relevant tax and accounting information for the Project to be included in the data room.

2.	Assist IFC in reviewing and responding to questions and information requests regarding the tax and accounting documents uploaded in the data room.  

3.	Assist IFC in reviewing the financial qualifications of Prospective Bidders during the initial prequalification process.

4.	Assist IFC in reviewing the forecast equity amounts and maximum equity submitted by Prequalified Bidders, in accordance with the RFP requirements.  For those Prequalified Bidders who are proposing to enter into Financing Agreements (as defined in the PPA), the submission will be verified by reference to the relevant lenders base case financial model (as certified in the Direct Agreement).  For all other Prequalified Bidders, the projections will be verified by way of an audit by the Consultant of such Prequalified Bidders own financial models.


ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-11-21T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231617</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Ethiopia Scaling Solar Tax Consultant</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">ET</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Ethiopia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452374</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231617</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452375</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231617</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0434</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SSA Solar Scale Up</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56335</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56337</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56338</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>