<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231437</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-08T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-11-15T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1231437 - Assistance to Business Correspondent Federation of India (BCFI) for Standardization of Business Correspondent/Agent Networks Technology Interface

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Agent networks in India play a critical role in promoting financial access, by helping financial service providers reach out to under banked areas. In the wake of recent financial inclusion initiatives by Government of India and other stakeholders, there has been a rapid growth in agent networks, with greater focus on building the infrastructure and increasing access points.  This has led to a significant increase in the number of BC service providers, technologies, as well as technology service providers in the country.

In order to enhance viability, Institutional Business Correspondent Network Managers (BCNMs) have adopted diversified business models, customized processes, technologies as well as monitoring and control mechanisms, leading to multiple standards and technologies. As a result of limited support and coordination between various stakeholders and the pressure on BCNMs to remain viable, the level of standardization and coordination among services provided by BCs are minimal. In the present context, the extent of dependence of Corporate BCs on sponsor banks is high. This has also led to the development of BC channels as parallel systems having limited integration with mainstream banking and inter-operability across banks/agents etc. This has huge impact on consumer inconvenience, consumer protection issues, higher costs, scalability challenges and difficulties in monitoring and compliance. 

Recognizing the impact of these challenges on the drive to promote financial inclusion, there has been positive regulatory initiatives in the country. RBIs Committee headed by Dr. Nachiket Mor on Comprehensive Financial Services for Small Business and Low Income Households and Report on Medium-term Path on Financial Inclusion, highlights the need for white label BCs with greater operational flexibility and complete inter-operability. There is a need for a concerted effort from all the stakeholders in developing a standards based approach for BC network.

Business Correspondent Federation of India (BCFI) is working with key stakeholders for the development of an integrated and inter-operable technology solution/platform, facilitating greater standardization among the BC network and create standards based framework for White label BC implementation.

In this background, IFC in partnership with BCFI, supported by DFID and SIDBI is hiring a consultant/firm to develop a standardized technology framework for the BC infrastructure with proper risk management aspects. The project will facilitate the BC network to emerge as high quality White label BCs with direct access to payment and settlement systems. The consultant should focus on:
 Understanding and mapping protocols and technology guidelines of National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) for the integration of Aadhar Enabled Payment System (AEPS), Immediate Payment Service (IMPS), Unified Payment Interface (UPI) &amp; RuPay/Visa/Mastercard based Cash-Out/Cash@PoS transactions/Bharat Bill Payments/Merchant Payments/e-KYC with Corporate BC platform under regulatory framework of RBI/IRDA/DoT/SEBI/PFRDA to make BC Agents business self-sustainable.
 Review of the existing proprietary technology platforms/interface used by Corporate BCs and identification of issues related to interoperability
 Develop the technology framework required for the integration of Corporate BCs interface with NPCIs payment and settlement system using AEPS/IMPS/NFS infrastructure
 Interact with stakeholders and gain agreement on the proposed standardization and technology framework.
 Develop standard Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) for BC agents (independent of devices and access technologies (PC/Tablet/PoS/MobileApp/USSD))- Corporate BC interface, so as to be compatible with NPCI requirements.



INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB, and between 5-7 pages.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-11-15T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231437</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>BCFI for Standardization of Business Correspondent/Agent Networks Technology Interface</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452016</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231437</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452017</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231437</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017293</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Facilitating Financial Inclusion among MSMEs and Low-Income Households in India</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56280</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56281</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56282</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56283</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>