<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231171</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-08T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-05T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1231171 - Portfolio Analyst Consultant FIG AS - Mexico

Assignment Countries:
  
Work will cover LAC Region, STC will be based in Mexico City, Mexico. 

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The International Finance Corporation (IFC), a member of the World Bank Group, promotes sustainable private sector investment in developing countries as a way to reduce poverty and improve peoples lives. IFC also provides advisory services (AS) to promote the development of the private sector, strengthen local companies and financial intermediaries, and to improve the business enabling environment. To increase financial inclusion in the region, the Financial Institutions Group (FIG) provides AS to the financial services industry.

IFC is seeking an experienced analyst to support the FIG AS program operations in Latin America and the Caribbean (LAC). The analyst will work in close collaboration with the Portfolio Officer and Management for FIG AS, while interacting with Project Leaders and Senior Specialists. He/ she will report to the Financial Institutions Group Advisory Regional Leader and will be based in Bogota, Colombia. Some travel may be required. 

The successful candidate will demonstrate an exceptional ability to acquire and process knowledge, to function in a fast-paced high-performance environment, to manage multiple tasks while paying attention to details, and to deliver quality under tight deadlines. He/ she will be a natural team player who also demonstrates autonomy and initiative.


SCOPE OF WORK  DELIVERABLES

Overall, the analyst will support the FIG AS program operations in LAC, primarily in the areas of financial management, performance measurement and knowledge management. His/ her tasks will include:

	Generating periodic reports on financials and key performance indicators to inform management on program results against targets
	Coordinating responses to requests related to the program by collecting, validating and consolidating inputs from different sub-regions and sources to adequately represent the business line panorama (eg: donor reports, internal newsletters communications, quarterly reports)
	Capturing and disseminating knowledge derived and lessons learned from the projects of the FIG AS 
	Assisting FIG AS Project Leaders and Specialists in complying with changing governance and corporate best practices, as well as with system requirements, throughout the projects lifecycle
	Liaising with the Global Portfolio Management Unit to ensure coordination and consistency between practices at the LAC regional level and at the Global level
	Support Management of FIG AS on other portfolio related matters, as needed. 


QUALIFICATION CRITERIA

	Bachelors degree in Business, Economics, Finance, International Development or related fields. Post-graduate studies are a plus, but not a requirement
	Minimum 3 years of working experience
	Good knowledge and understanding of business planning, work programming and project management
	Strong numerical and analytical skills. Understanding of financial and key performance indicators, budgeting, financial projections, among other aspects
	Knowledge of development and access to finance issues and of relevant World Bank (and similar) approaches for private sector development
	Ability to work independently on routine issues, organize and prioritize work to meet deadlines. 
	Ability to work under pressure, tight deadlines and have flexibility in handling a variety of concurrent tasks, while keeping attention to detail and producing high quality work
	Ability to present information in different and new approaches to facilitate the managerial decision making processes
	Capacity to work effectively in a multi-disciplinary, multi-cultural and fast changing environment
	Excellent written and oral communication skills in English and Spanish; French language skills is a plus
	Strong computing skills (proficiency required in Microsoft Excel, Word and Power Point; knowledge of SAP and other budgeting and financial/statistical software is a plus)
	Good attitude; dynamic, committed and accountable


Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through Business Opportunities page at the World Bank Group eConsultant2 https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html and via e-mail to the following address: Lchacon@ifc.org.

The application deadline is December 5, 2016. Applications without a cover letter (1 page max) will not be considered. Only short-listed candidates will be contacted, and the position will be paid in local currency. The appointee will be stationed in Mexico City, Mexico. IFCs Recruitment and Employment Policies reflect its strong values for cultural, racial and gender diversity. Citizens of any country are encouraged to apply. Women and minorities are strongly encouraged to apply.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-05T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231171</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Portfolio Analyst Consultant FIG AS - Mexico</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">451446</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231171</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">451447</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231171</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0539</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">FIG - LAC - FMTAAS</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>