<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231926</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-15T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-11-22T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1231926 - Assistance to BCFI to develop GRM for BC/Agent Banking Sector

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Agent networks in India play a critical role in promoting financial access, by helping financial service providers reach out to under banked areas. In the wake of recent financial inclusion initiatives by Government of India and other stakeholders, there has been a rapid growth in agent networks, with greater focus on building the infrastructure and increasing access points.
In the coming days, viability of agent banking would depend on the quality of services provided (irrespective of the location, product or agent model). In order to have a sustainable agent network, the client must be able to trust the system/agents and conduct transactions with confidence. Indeed various researches  have shown that strong customer service and client protection practices are linked to profitability for both agents and agent network managers.

Mechanisms like dedicated call center lines for BC agents and end-customers, display of banks customer care details at BC outlets, regular monitoring of BC agents by network managers etc. have been implemented by the service providers to address customer complaints. However, findings from the field  indicate that these procedures are often insufficiently robust and inconsistently applied across geographies, by service providers and banks. With financial transactions becoming interoperable through Aadhaar for all banks at a BC Agents location, challenges like agents and customers low awareness on existing grievance mechanisms, customers high dependency on agents for transactions and limited resources deployed at banks to address client complaints (mainly for their own customers and not for other customers), further lead to ineffective grievance redressal mechanisms in the field. This leads to isolation of banking transactions at BC locations, restricted to principal bank mainly and that too with inadequate customer grievance redressal processes. There is a need for devising effective grievance mechanisms that provide direct access to customers to lodge complaints and capacitate agents/ network managers to deliver the same.

Recognizing these challenges, Business Correspondent Federation of India (BCFI) is working with key stakeholders to address these issues and enable customers to have access to responsible formal financial services. 

In this background, IFC in partnership with BCFI, supported by DFID and SIDBI is hiring a consultant/firm to assist BCFI in developing a standardized, robust and effective GRM framework, to be implemented across various BC models. The consultant should focus on:

 - Review of existing GRMs in the industry and its effectiveness in resolving customer complaints.
 - Mapping of stakeholders and their associated roles and responsibilities 
 - Provide clear classification of complaints/issues (existing and potential) faced by customers
 - Incorporate customer facing mobile technologies like mobile apps using mobile data or USSD based services to bring reduced dependence on only manual interface of BC Agent and bring-in standardized complaint number system to make it customer friendly and make it scalable.
 - Define escalation matrix for each type of complaint and turn-around time (TAT) for its resolution
 - Agree with Banks on recourse of customer grievances for not meeting TAT
 - Identify mechanisms (like service feedback calls, customer surveys, mystery shopping exercises etc, but not limited to) to proactively collect complaints and feedback from customers.
 - Technology supported systems/process in the backend (compatible with various BC models) for effective capturing and monitoring of client complaints.
 - Analytical and reporting framework that provides BCFI with a comprehensive picture on usage and effectiveness of the designed GRM.
-ToT module for the capacity building of network managers and agents in implementing the framework.
- Measures to improve awareness among customers on GRM.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-11-22T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231926</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Assistance to BCFI to develop GRM for BC/Agent Banking Sector</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453010</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231926</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453011</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231926</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017293</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Facilitating Financial Inclusion among MSMEs and Low-Income Households in India</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56482</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56483</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56484</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56485</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>