<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231636</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-09T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-11-16T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Uzbekistan: Awareness Raising Workshops for the Regional Climate Investment Facility under the Climate Adaptation and Mitigation Program for Aral Sea Basin (CAMP4ASB)

PROJECT BACKGROUND

The Climate Adaptation and Mitigation Program for Aral Sea Basin (CAMP4ASB) seeks to reap the benefits from regional cooperation in addressing the mounting challenges of climate change, which often transcend borders in Central Asia. The Program will strengthen the knowledge and information base on climate change and provide financing and technical assistance to rural beneficiaries for climate-smart investments in sectoral areas considered as priorities by Central Asian countries. The Program is implemented in phases, with the first phase supporting Tajikistan and Uzbekistan, and the Executive Committee of the International Fund for Saving the Aral Sea (EC-IFAS) with support from the Regional Environmental Center for Central Asia (CAREC). Preparation is underway in other Central Asian countries for their participation in the Program. A brief description is provided below (Project Appraisal Document available at http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/858141468000588741/Central-Asia-Climate-Adaptation-and-Mitigation-Program-for-the-Aral-Sea-Basin-Project).

Total project cost for first phase (implementation: 2016-21) is US$44.8 million:
-	US$15 million IDA grant (recipient: EC-IFAS), supporting regional activities; 
-	US$23 million IDA credit (Tajikistan: U$9 million, Uzbekistan: US$14 million), supporting national activities (primarily, climate investments);
-	US$6.8 million in beneficiary contributions for climate investments in Tajikistan and Uzbekistan.

Component 1: Regional Climate Knowledge Services (to be implemented by the Regional Implementing Agency, EC-IFAS, and Regional Coordination Unit, RCU, hosted by CAREC), to (i) assist in the collection, joint use, and management of public datasets on climate change; (ii) improve systems for monitoring the status of snow and ice cover and/or agricultural and forestry systems; and (iii) enhance the capacity of environmental agencies and other stakeholders for climate assessment and decision-making. The component is also expected to support the development of methodologies, approaches, and tools for the analysis of climate change impacts and response options as well as of information/knowledge products. It will also establish a mechanism to evaluate climate investments under Component 2. Finally the component will facilitate regional dialogue and coalition building through an annual climate knowledge forum and multi-stakeholder networks.

Component 2: Regional Climate Investment Facility (to be implemented by the countries National Coordination Units), to finance climate investments via sub-loans, support sub-borrowers in the implementation of these sub-projects, and build the capacity of Participating Financial Institutions (PFIs) for green financing. The Rural Restructuring Agency (RRA) under the Ministry of Agriculture and Water Resources of the Republic of Uzbekistan hosts the NCU in that country. Project area in Uzbekistan includes the Republic of Karakalpakstan and Khorezm region.
-	Subcomponent 2.1: Investment financing, via sub-loans through PFIs supported by a credit line, to promote the adoption of climate adaptation or mitigation technologies and practices for increased productivity and improved livelihood in rural areas. Sub-borrowers are expected to include private farmers and entrepreneurs; representatives of small and medium size businesses; resource (water, pasture) user groups, all interested in implementing climate change adaptation and mitigation measures in rural areas.
-	Subcomponent 2.2: Capacity building and support to beneficiaries, for international and local consultant services in order to expand beneficiaries knowledge and capacity on climate-smart practices and technologies and to support implementation of subprojects as well as conduct relevant trainings on preparation of business plans/sub-loans applications. Training for PFI staff on evaluation of agricultural business plans/sub-loan applications with a focus on climate change will also be provided.

Component 3: Regional and National Coordination
-	Subcomponent 3.1: Regional Coordination, to support the RCU in implementing Component 1, including procurement, disbursement, financial management, monitoring and evaluation of the project outcomes as well as financing of incremental operating costs. The Unit will also be responsible for overall regional coordination under CAMP4ASB. 
-	Subcomponent 3.2: National Coordination, to support the NCUs in implementing Component 2, including procurement, disbursement, financial management, safeguards oversight, monitoring and evaluation of the project outcomes as well as financing of incremental operating costs. 

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The objective of the assignment is to develop material for awareness raising workshops targeted at potential beneficiaries of CAMP4ASBs Regional Climate Investment Facility in Uzbekistan. 

By discussing climate change threats to rural productivity and livelihoods and showcasing climate-smart technologies and practices, these workshops will be critical to make the case for green and climate-smart investments for which farmers and other rural stakeholders might be willing to borrow under the Facility. The workshops will also help collect feedback on current climate concerns of potential beneficiaries as well as on climate measures they would be most interested in receiving support for. Finally, the workshops will help ensure that potential sub-borrowers under the Facility are made aware of climate investment funding opportunities under CAMP4ASB as well as have a good understanding of the Facility parameters.

Specifically, the workshops will cover:
-	Presentation, tailored to each project areas agro-ecozone (including drylands, mountains, watershed, and irrigated/cultivated), of the most relevant climate change risks to agricultural systems and of the most suitable climate-smart solutions for climate resilience, risk reduction, and mitigation, highlighting technical (to gauge climate effectiveness and to monitor performance of sub-investments) and financial parameters (to assess sustainability). A Handbook of Climate-smart Investments in Rural Areas for CAMP4ASB participating countries will be available, providing information on the technical and financial parameters of the climate investments. The Handbook can be a reliable source of information for this part of the training.
-	Detailed presentation and guidance on the sub-loan cycle under CAMP4ASBs Facility, highlighting each step in the process from sub-loan application to completion, procedures and roles and responsibilities of sub-borrowers and other stakeholders (e.g., eligible investment types, maximum sub-loan amount and minimum co-financing, preparation of sub-loan application/business plan, Social and Environmental Safeguard responsibilities, Monitoring responsibility, etc.). A Credit Line Operational Manual will form the basis for this part of the training.

The workshops are envisage to last each 2 days and cater for about 15-20 participants at a time. The workshops should rely as much as possible on actual case studies (from Uzbekistan, or other countries with similar context) and use (and present) the templates in the Annexes of the Credit Line Operational Manual. Based on the demand and need, additional templates (e.g., forms or excel-based calculators) could be developed. The material must be prepared in English, Russian, and Uzbek. This material will be trialed (i.e., a few training sessions will be conducted) and once finalized, will then be provided to the National Coordination Unit in Uzbekistan and used during implementation for awareness raising (under a separate contract) in the entire project area. The assignment for delivery of awareness raising workshops in the entire project area may or may not be awarded to the company selected for the assignment covered in the present terms of reference, depending on applicable procurement rules at the time of implementation.

Consultant shall be responsible for all aspects of service provision as outlined above in these ToRs.

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS

The World Bank invites eligible firms to indicate their interest for this assignment. Firms must provide information on their qualification to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.). The total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB. Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications. Consultants are encouraged to use expertise in Uzbekistan as much as possible. Consultants can suggest team composition and qualification. 

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html). Shortlisted qualified companies will be invited to submit Full Proposals. The Bank reserves the right to directly award or otherwise assess the selected firm's eligibility to compete for downstream work in accordance with applicable procurement World Bank Group's rules.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-11-16T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231636</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Uzbekistan: Awareness Raising Workshops for the Regional Climate Investment Facility under the Climate Adaptation and Mitigation Program for Aral Sea Basin (CAMP4ASB)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">UZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Uzbekistan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452397</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231636</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452398</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231636</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A2580</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">ECAPDEV Grant for the Climate Adaptation and Mitigation Program for Aral Sea Basin</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56347</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in preparing awareness raising/training material and organizing related workshops</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56348</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience in addressing climate change challenges and developing climate-smart solutions in the context of rural development of at least 5 years</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56349</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Familiarity with agriculture sector context in Uzbekistan highly desirable</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>