<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231742</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-18T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-03T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Terms of Reference For Special Diagnostic and Comprehensive Restructuring Plan for Myanmar Economic Bank

1.	The Myanmar Economic Bank (MEB) was established in 1976 and is currently the largest SOB and the second largest bank in the system with estimated assets of over $4.5 billion in March 2015.  The bank has an extensive 327 branch network covering virtually all townships. Despite limitations in its information technology, infrastructure and operation platforms, MEB handles all government accounts and payments, acts as an agent of the CBM, provides policy loans and performs limited commercial banking functions. 

2.	MEB has a recognizable brand among the public and holds large public and other institutional deposits in the form of fixed deposits and savings certificates. The bank has been able to build a solid customer base. However, the MEB business model and processes need urgent improvement and reengineering to ensure efficiency and sustainability. 

      Objective of the Special Diagnostic

3.	There is currently insufficient data on the financial, operational and institutional conditions of MEB for the MOPF to draw up a comprehensive reform plan to reform SOB in order to make it viable, efficient and effective in its delivery of financial services.  As such, the GOM/MOPF is seeking technical input from the World Bank utilizing a Consulting Firm to: 

	Undertake a financial, operational and institutional review (Special Diagnostic) of MEB to have a full and fair assessment of the financial, operational and institutional condition of MEB;  and 

	Develop a comprehensive restructuring plan for MEB (Comprehensive Restructuring Plan). The Restructuring Plan would be implemented over the next 2 to 5 years covering all elements contributing to financial sustainability and performance, including: clarification of MEBs mandate, development of strategic vision, corporate governance reforms, operational efficiency, HR and institutional development, IT modernization and investment, and disclosure and transparency. 

I.	Scope and Content of the Special Diagnostic

4.	The assignment for the Consulting Firm would be conducted in two phases: 

	Phase I will focus on conduct of a Special Diagnostic of the MEB. 

	Phase II will focus on developing a comprehensive Restructuring Plan that is informed by the Phase 1 Special Diagnostic findings. 

Phase I --Scope of the Special Diagnostic. 

5.	The Special Diagnostic must address the following issues, details are given in attached document:
	Ownership arrangements. 
	Legal Framework. 
	Accounting policies and procedures
	Opening balance sheet. 
	Governance arrangements 
	Reporting framework. 
	Risk Management. 
	Credit origination and credit management.  
	Asset quality management
	Accounting standards.  
	Credit concentration and exposure risks. 
	Connected counterparties.  
	Provisions for credit risk losses and other losses.  Liquidity risk management. 
	Liquidity position. 
	Foreign exchange risk. 
	Quality of earnings
	Capital adequacy plan.  
	Intangible assets. 
	Informal or unrecorded activities. 
	Internal control policies and procedures. 
	Viability. 
	Verification of title to fixed assets.  


Deliverables for Phase I:

6.	The deliverable will be Special Diagnostic report with an Executive Summary, addressing the scope and issues outlined above as technical input to GOMs decisions on restructuring of MEB. This report should be delivered in draft to the World Bank in close collaboration with the MOPF, and then within 4 weeks or receiving comments, a revised and final report will be issued. 

7.	The report should include a set of specific restructuring options which will be developed thoroughly under phase two, following MOPF/GOMs decision on the appropriate restructuring option for MEB. 

8.	Opening balance sheet and opening statement of financial position of MEB.

9.	Findings should be presented at a workshop to the MOPF and other stakeholders as MOPF deems appropriate. 


Phase II-- Scope of the Comprehensive Restructuring Plan

10.	Based on the review and analysis conducted under Phase I of this assignment, the Firm will develop a comprehensive restructuring plan (Restructuring Plan) for MEB as technical input to the GOM decisions on the restructuring of MEB. The plan will take into account and seek to address the deficiencies in the MEBs operational framework in order to improve financial performance identified above. It should be informed by the MOPFs overall goals to reduce fiscal risks, improve transparency and accountability, and increase the competitiveness of the financial sector. 

11.	The Comprehensive Restructuring Plan should specifically include a specific time-bound Implementation Plan to be carried out over 2-5 years addressing, among other things, the following areas: 

	Clarification of goals of reform/restructuring;
	Clarification of mandate and identification of business plan;
	Ownership issues (including MOPF mandate);
	Legal framework;
	Corporate governance framework;
	Operational and credit policies;
	Risk management policies and procedures;
	Accounting and auditing policies and procedures, including IFRS transition plan; and
	HR and skills policies and institutional development.

12.	Deliverables for Phase II

13.	The deliverable will be a Comprehensive Restructuring Plan, with an Executive Summary, in accordance with the scope and issues that are outlined above. 

14.	This Comprehensive Restructuring Plan should be delivered in draft to the World Bank in close collaboration with the MOPF as technical input to the GOM for the restructuring of MEB, and then within 4 weeks or receiving comments, a revised and final report will be issued. 

15.	Findings should be presented a workshop to the MOPF and other stakeholders as MOPF deems appropriate.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-03T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231742</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Special Diagnostic and Development of Comprehensive Restructuring Plan for Myanmar Economic Bank (MEB)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Myanmar</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452611</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231742</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452612</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231742</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF083254</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Institutional Strengthening</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56522</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56523</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56524</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56525</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>