<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231748</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-18T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-03T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Terms of Reference for Special Diagnostic and Comprehensive Restructuring Plan for 
Myanmar Agriculture Development Bank

1.	Myanmar Agricultural Development Bank (MADB) is the second largest state-owned institution in the banking system, after the Myanmar Economic Bank (MEB). As at the end of 2012, MADB served 1.87 million customers, mostly smallholder farmers, and had a network of 206 branches (which accounted for 23 percent of all bank branches in Myanmar). MADB was established in June 1953 by the Government of Myanmar (GOM) to support the development of agriculture, livestock, and rural enterprises in Myanmar. The Ministry of Agriculture and Irrigation (MAI) had hitherto performed the ownership and oversight functions over MADB even though there is now a GOM decision to transfer the ownership and oversight responsibility to MOPF. 

2.	Since its establishment, MADB has played an important economic and social role in Myanmar by providing loans to a large segment households in rural areas engaged in agricultural activities. Most MADB loan products are designed to cover the short-term working capital needs of farmers, such as purchase of seeds, fertilizers, and pesticides; payment of salaries for farm workers; and lease of agriculture equipment. MADB lends at subsidized interest rates, following the lending policies and programs issued by MAI.

3.	MADB provides loans to farmers to cover a fraction of the production costs for up to their first 10 acres. Most of MADBs borrowers are engaged in subsistence agriculture using rudimentary cultivation techniques that prevent them from reaching high yields for their crops. MADB does not support medium or large holder farmers engaged in commercial agriculture or other agribusiness firms, traders, exporters, and other type of firms along the entire value chain, although the MADB law allows it to lend for production, processing, storage, distribution, and marketing activities relating to the agricultural and livestock enterprises.

      Objective of the Special Diagnostic

4.	There is currently insufficient data on the financial, operational and institutional conditions of MADB for the GOM/MOPF to draw up a comprehensive reform plan to reform MADB in order to make it viable, efficient and effective in its delivery of financial services.  As such, the GOM/MOPF is seeking technical input from the World Bank utilizing a Consulting Firm to: 

	Undertake a financial, operational and institutional review (Special Diagnostic) of MADB to have a full and fair assessment of the financial, operational and institutional condition of MADB;  and 

	Develop a comprehensive restructuring plan for MADB (Restructuring Plan). The Restructuring Plan would be implemented over the next 2 to 5 years covering all elements contributing to financial sustainability and performance, including: clarification of MADBs mandate, development of strategic vision, corporate governance reforms, operational efficiency, HR and institutional development, IT modernization and investment, and disclosure and transparency. 

I.	Scope and Content of the Special Diagnostic

5.	The assignment for the Consulting Firm would be conducted in two phases: 

	Phase I will focus on conduct of a Special Diagnostic of the MADB. 

	Phase II will focus on developing a comprehensive Restructuring Plan that is informed by the Phase 1 Special Diagnostic findings. 

Phase I --Scope of the Special Diagnostic. 

6.	The Special Diagnostic must address the following issues, details are given in attached document:
	Ownership arrangements. 
	Legal Framework. 
	Accounting policies and procedures
	Opening balance sheet. 
	Governance arrangements 
	Reporting framework. 
	Risk Management. 
	Credit origination and credit management.  
	Asset quality management
	Accounting standards.  
	Credit concentration and exposure risks. 
	Connected counterparties.  
	Provisions for credit risk losses and other losses.  Liquidity risk management. 
	Liquidity position. 
	Foreign exchange risk. 
	Quality of earnings
	Capital adequacy plan.  
	Intangible assets. 
	Informal or unrecorded activities. 
	Internal control policies and procedures. 
	Viability. 
	Verification of title to fixed assets.  

Deliverables for Phase I:

7.	The deliverable will be Special Diagnostic report with an Executive Summary, addressing the scope and issues outlined above as technical input to GOMs decisions on restructuring of MADB. This report should be delivered in draft to the World Bank in close collaboration with the MOPF, and then within 4 weeks or receiving comments, a revised and final report will be issued. 

8.	The report should include a set of specific restructuring options which will be developed thoroughly under phase two, following MOPF/GOMs decision on the appropriate restructuring option for MADB. 

9.	Opening balance sheet and opening statement of financial position of MADB.

10.	Findings should be presented at a workshop to the MOPF and other stakeholders as MOPF deems appropriate. 


Phase II-- Scope of the Comprehensive Restructuring Plan

11.	Based on the review and analysis conducted under Phase I of this assignment, the Firm will develop a comprehensive restructuring plan (Restructuring Plan) for MADB as technical input to the GOM decisions on the restructuring of MADB. The plan will take into account and seek to address the deficiencies in the MADBs operational framework in order to improve financial performance identified above. It should be informed by the MOPFs overall goals to reduce fiscal risks, improve transparency and accountability, and increase the competitiveness of the financial sector. 

12.	The Comprehensive Restructuring Plan should specifically include a specific time-bound Implementation Plan to be carried out over 2-5 years addressing, among other things, the following areas: 

	Clarification of goals of reform/restructuring;
	Clarification of mandate and identification of business plan;
	Ownership issues (including MOPF mandate);
	Legal framework;
	Corporate governance framework;
	Operational and credit policies;
	Risk management policies and procedures;
	Accounting and auditing policies and procedures, including IFRS transition plan; and
	HR and skills policies and institutional development.

13.	Deliverables for Phase II

14.	The deliverable will be a Comprehensive Restructuring Plan, with an Executive Summary, in accordance with the scope and issues that are outlined above. 

15.	This Comprehensive Restructuring Plan should be delivered in draft to the World Bank in close collaboration with the MOPF as technical input to the GOM for the restructuring of MADB, and then within 4 weeks or receiving comments, a revised and final report will be issued. 

16.	Findings should be presented a workshop to the MOPF and other stakeholders as MOPF deems appropriate.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-03T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231748</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Special Diagnostic and Development of Restructuring Plan for Myanmar Agricultural Development Bank</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Myanmar</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452621</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231748</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452622</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231748</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF083254</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Institutional Strengthening</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56518</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56519</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56520</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56521</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>