<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1231557</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-09T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-11-23T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1231557 - Short-term Consultant (STC) for EDGE &amp; Green Building (GB) Indonesia Program

Assignment Countries:
  - Indonesia

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Background:
The overall objective of the Indonesia Green Building program is to reduce carbon emissions and improve energy, water and other resource efficiencies associated with new building construction and retrofitting of existing buildings. Through a programmatic approach and in partnership with the government, the private sector and like-minded organizations, the program will help address market failures and major barriers in developing and implementing green buildings in Indonesia.

Regulatory Work
The program has been working with GoI counterparts (Ministry of Public Works and Public Housing and 3 selected sub-national governments: Jakarta, Bandung and Makassar) to develop regulations that will mandate certain building stakeholders to develop more energy efficient buildings (to be the first movers); as well as review incentive schemes to make it more attractive for them. 

In meeting the requests from the some selected cities, including the Jakarta Provincial Government and the Bandung City Government, for assistance in developing their first green building codes, IFC has provided technical recommendations on the energy and water savings as well as developed an electronic tools to record and monitor the submission of building permit application for code compliance. Since the online application system has been developed for the Jakarta Province Government in 2013/2014 and for the Bandung City Government in October 2016, these online application systems will then be replicated to other client cities with some adjustments according to the local code. 
The project looks to leverage its experience in Jakarta and Bandung to assist the Ministry of Public Works plus other Indonesian city like Makassar in the similar process of drafting green building codes (where codes are not in place yet) and the code implementation. Given the Indonesia decentralization, building regulations and authority have largely been delegated to cities and districts; however, the Ministry of Public Works still maintains the role of formulating nation-wide umbrella regulation and national guideline on how cities and districts should develop their building regulations. 

To this end, the project jointly with the sub-national government clients will carry out: (i) Baselining and Regulatory Impact analysis: Building Market and Energy Efficiency Studies; (ii) Regulation Drafting and Public Consultations, (iii) Develop Implementation Framework and Support and (iv) Monitor Implementation. In addition, the project team will work with the national client in developing national guidance/toolkit as mentioned in the previous paragraph.


EDGE Voluntary Certification in Indonesia
The project also engages with leading developers to pull higher standards through demonstration projects that meet the Excellence Design in Greater Efficiencies (EDGE) voluntary certification standard of 20% reduction in energy and water consumption and embedded energy in materials at minimal additional cost and with attractive investment returns. EDGE was created by IFC and aims to reach a 20% penetration of voluntary green certification in targeted markets for new building in Indonesia within seven years through engagement with the EDGE local partner, Green Building Council Indonesia (GBCI). 
Scope of work: 
The Green Building Consultant (the STC) reports directly to the Project Leader (PL) of the Indonesia Green Building Project and will work closely with the project team including IFC operations officers, EAP Regional Green Building Specialist, CAS Team, Global Green Building/EDGE Team and other IFC resources. 

The STC will provide substantive support to the PL and the project team mostly on the EDGE Indonesia areas which are as follow:
A.	Support EDGE Certification Implementation
1.	Work with IFCs investment teams to provide assistance to their clients for their EDGE projects; 
2.	Develop relationships with all key stakeholders, including developers, investors, financial institutions, public policy makers and others to promote EDGE;
3.	Ensure a smooth certification process for at least 20 initial certifications by working closely with the local Indonesian auditors and the local certification partner;
4.	Assist in the development of modules and delivery of training programs for local partner staff and professionals/auditors, including EDGE Auditor Training;
5.	Assist in business development efforts such as organizing CEO Breakfast meetings for developers and/or financial institutions;
6.	Work with the EDGE Marketing team and IFCs communication officer to develop marketing materials and articles to advocate for EDGE;
7.	Support the Green Building Specialist and Project Leader to document performance evidence for EDGE certified buildings;
8.	Help the EDGE local partner in developing an EDGE marketing plan in Indonesia;
9.	Support local partner to develop EDGE content on their website;
10.	Develop and nurture effective working relationship with relevant government and private sector partners to ensure good communication and productive collaboration;
11.	Take an active role in discussions with private sector and government counterparts to explore and/or demonstrate the practical feasibility of the EDGE Tools and incorporate private sector feedback into development of the Indonesia EDGE Tools;
12.	Consolidate and analyze lessons learned from project implementation experience and share with team members;

B.	Support Code Development and Enforcement Work
1.	Take an active role in discussions with private sector and government counterparts to explore and/or demonstrate the practical feasibility of the proposed reforms and incorporate private sector feedback into development of and advocacy for new reforms and user guidance;
2.	Prepare materials for code discussion, including developing the baseline, code drafting, incentives, etc.  referring (but not limited to) the templates created already for Jakarta and Bandung;
3.	Develop green building code manual / e-learning tools for government officials to carry out their regulating duties as well as for the private sector to assist them in complying to the code; 
4.	Help build the government clients human resources capacity to execute and monitor implementation;
5.	Develop monitoring framework including supporting data collection and preparing case studies;

C.	External Outreach:
1.	Represent IFC and the EDGE/GB certification program at meetings, workshops, conferences, round-tables or working groups as assigned by the Project Leader;
2.	Work with IFC Communications team to develop GB/EDGE communication plan including content creation.

In addition, the candidate is required to perform other functions as requested by the Project Leader. 

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET
  - Hungary EXIM Bank-Funding for Green Buildings in EAP (CAS)

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-11-23T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1231557</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Short-term Consultant (STC) for EDGE &amp; Green Building (GB) Indonesia Program</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">ID</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Indonesia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452263</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231557</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">452264</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1231557</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A2798</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Hungary EXIM Bank-Funding for Green Buildings in EAP (CAS)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>