<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232709</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-29T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-07T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1232709 - Assessment Development for Lesotho

Assignment Countries:
  - Lesotho

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The selected firm will be responsible for:

(i)	Attempt to draw and analyse as much valid information from the existing and available data (if any);
(ii)	Prepare a student test and questionnaire to be used in the context of a 2016 baseline and future national assessment data collection activities for Form B. 
(iii)	Help MoET construct teacher tests for junior secondary teachers which will measure: (i) content knowledge for Mathematics, (ii) Content knowledge for Science (Physics, Biology, Chemistry at the junior secondary level), and (iii) pedagogical knowledge to be used in the context of a 2016 baseline and future rounds of data collection;
(iv)	Help MoET construct teacher tests for primary (Gr 1-4) teachers which will measure: (i) content knowledge for numeracy, (ii) Content knowledge for literacy, and 
(v)	Work closely with the WB and MoET to conduct power calculations and sampling for the student and teacher exams. 
(vi)	Prepare training materials, as needed and participate in enumerator and data entry training of  the firm working on data collection and data entry
(vii)	Provide oversight and guidance to local survey firm recruited by MoET under the LEQEP for coordination of data collection, data entry and analysis
(viii)	Analyse Form B National Assessment and Teacher Math and Science competency test results and produce reports on the findings. 

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:

  - Lesotho Basic Education Improvement Project

ELIGIBILITY

The project addresses, inter alia, MoETs focus on improving the quality of Math and Science education, particularly in junior secondary schools. In this regard, the Project Preparation Facility provides for a consultancy firm to undertake baseline studies of both student and teacher competencies at the secondary level, as well as primary teacher competencies, in order to understand the current status of learning, develop strong programs under the new IDA project, and assess progress in these areas. MOET therefore seeks the services of an external consultancy firm for  the development of instruments for the study on teachers Maths and Science competencies in secondary schools (grades 8, 9, 10), grade 9 baseline assessment as well as teachers numeracy and literacy competencies in primary schools (grades 1  4).

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-07T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232709</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Assessment Development for Lesotho</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">LS</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Lesotho</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454596</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232709</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454597</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232709</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3377</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Lesotho Basic Education Improvement Project</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56894</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Within the firm, it is necessary to identify the Team Leader, and the other key staff. The Team Leader shall provide CVs and a description of each team members role and responsibilities and their corresponding qualifications, such as highest level of education attained, discipline of study, the number of years of relevant experience, language skills, etc. Preferred qualifications of key staff for each position include:</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56892</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">He/she should have the following credentials: University degree, Masters Degree preferred, in relevant field (e.g. Social Sciences, Education, Economics, etc.); Expertise in student test construction for the secondary level Specialist in Item Response Theory or possessing strong knowledge of classical test theory Expertise in questionnaire development, monitoring and evaluation Minimum 10 years experience in educational assessment/research related work, some of which should be in th</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56891</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">The Consultancy Firm should have subject specialists in English, Sesotho, Mathematics and Science. Each Subject Specialist is responsible for developing all relevant instruments (both tests and questionnaires) in his/ her subject as required for each of the studies mentioned. The Subject Specialists should each have: Bachelors degree in a relevant field, with majors in one or two of the subjects of interest to the surveys (English Sesotho, Mathematics and Science.).</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56893</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">The Subject Specialists should each have: Bachelors degree in a relevant field, with majors in one or two of the subjects of interest to the surveys (English Sesotho, Mathematics and Science.). A Masters Degree will be considered an advantage; Expertise and experience in student test construction Expertise and experience in questionnaire development, monitoring and evaluation.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>