<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232466</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-24T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-11T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Ukraine Crop Receipts Legal Consultant (-s)

IFC is looking to recruit a short-term expert (STC) or experts who will undertake legal and regulatory project related work under the overall guidance of the Project Manager.

The duties of the Legal Expert(s) will include:

To create and strengthen the regulatory and legislative environment that will help implement the crop receipts instrument in Ukraine.  The project is working in the following directions or key focus areas including:

Enforcement procedure of crop receipts 
- review and analyze the current legislation, regulations and enforcement procedures;
- provide amendments on surrounding issues to improve the enforcement process for crop receipt;
- provide advice and support to companies/creditors on Enforcement procedures;
- develop and conduct training for Enforcement Authorities; 
- work closely with the Ministry of Justice and companies-creditors on the national level; and 
- provide support in the regions to solve real cases with to crop receipts enforcement process.

Banking regulations
- Support the Project to enact all the necessary procedures, resolution and processes to facilitate crop receipts usage by banks;
- link with the National Bank of Ukraine, banks and their associations (NABU) and support them in any arising issue with crop receipts.

Taxation procedure
- review and analyze the current legislation, regulations and taxation procedures; 
- develop and propose, if needed, amendments to the legislation to ensure clear and understandable taxation process of crop receipts in Ukraine; 
- support the state authorities in implementing the needed amendments;
- support companies-creditors with the needed consultations and advice with respect to the current legislation. 

Crop Receipts Registry legislative framework 
- develop amendments and updates to the resolution/decree on Crop Receipts, support the state authorities in implementing the amendments; 
- provide needed consultations for developing and implementing Crop Receipts Register (set the features of the Crop Receipts Registry, test it according to the Cabinet Ministers decree and support the full launch of the National Crop Receipts Register in Ukraine);
- develop all the necessary materials on the Crop Receipts Registry, consult and support notaries on the national and local levels on all procedures concerning registry.

Complex financial operations:
- provide legal support to the project team to study the ways of developing a crop receipt as a financial instrument or a securities instrument;
- review and study international experience that might be helpful for Ukrainian model.
SME and Cooperative and Corporate legislative framework 
- provide legal support to the project team regarding administration of revolving lines of credit, adaptation of crop receipts for value chain intermediaries, processors, credit unions and cooperatives. 

Job qualifications:
-              University Degree in Law; a postgraduate degree would be a strong advantage;
-              At least 3 years of work/professional experience in one or more directions described above; 
-              Sound experience in drafting legislative acts is desirable;
-              Experience in legal analysis and assessment;
-              Knowledge of national legislative system;
-              Relevant experience of working in Ukraine is obligatory;
-              Strong communication, analytical and drafting skills;
-              Ability to work in a team and travel extensively throughout Ukraine;
-              Good computer skills;
-              Excellent speaking and writing skills in Ukrainian and English.

Assignment Title: 1232466 - Ukraine Crop Receipts Legal Consultant (-s)

Assignment Countries: Ukraine

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Interested applicants should submit their CV and a cover letter identifying their experience under at least one or more of the key directions stated above.  Applications should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-11T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232466</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Ukraine Crop Receipts Legal Consultant (-s)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">UA</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Ukraine</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454036</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232466</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454037</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232466</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0237</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SECO - Ukraine Crop Receipts Project (Supplement 20-Project 24)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>