<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232779</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-30T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-11T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The GEF IEO invites interested consultants to submit applications to be the senior short term consultant to the Evaluation of GEF Engagement with Indigenous Peoples.
The consultant will perform the following tasks:

a.	Review GEF Council and Secretariat documents, reports, GEF IEO and external evaluations and other related documents relevant to reviews engagement with indigenous peoples by bilateral and multilateral agencies. 
b.	Contribute to the design of surveys with stakeholders, interviews and focus groups 
c.	Analyze data and information gathered through focus groups, individual interviews and surveys 
d.	Contribute to triangulation, gap analysis and report writing  
Travel is not expected for this assignment. 
Selection Criteria:
	A Masters degree or higher in environmental policy/natural resource management or relevant social science
	More than 10 years of experience in working with Indigenous Peoples in international setting
	Demonstrated knowledge of the GEF and/or its Agencies
	Strong quantitative and qualitative analytical skills as applied to monitoring and evaluation
	Excellent writing and speaking in English
	Demonstrated experience with preparing analytical outputs and contributing to reports
	Ability to write concise reports/excellent speaking skills in English. Ability to work in a collegial way with multi-disciplinary teams in cross-cultural settings. Additional UN languages would be considered an advantage. 
Duration and Compensation 

The assignment will be for a period of up to 30 work days. The consultant daily rate will be determined using the World Bank rules and procedures. The position is based in Washington, DC and can include working from a home-base. The duration of the contract would be December 2016 to March 2017.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-11T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232779</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Support to Evaluation of GEF Engagement with Indigenous Peoples</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454730</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232779</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>