<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232031</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-18T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-05T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1232031 - Consulting Services in Support of the Implementation of the new World Bank Environmental and Social Framework for Investment Project Financing (IPF) Operations

Assignment Countries:
  - United States

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

A.	Project Background and Objectives
On August 4th, 2016, following four years of intensive review and consultation, the World Banks Board of Executive Directors agreed to replace the World Banks Environmental and Social Safeguard policies with a new Environmental and Social Framework (ESF) for Investment Project Financing (IPF) (www.worldbank.org).  The ESF is currently scheduled to become effective for new Bank projects in early 2018.  The goal of the ESF is to better support the Bank in achieving its twin goals to end extreme poverty and promote shared prosperity in a sustainable manner in all Partner countries.  To that end, the Bank has sought to modernize its approach to environmental and social risk management by developing a modern, fit-for-purpose framework to safeguard people and the environment, that better meets the varied needs of Borrowers facing new environmental and social challenges.    

The ESF comprises a Vision, a Policy and a set of ten (10) Environmental and Social Standards (ESS).  The Policy governs the Banks approach to the Framework, and the Standards are the environmental and social standards that Borrowers have to meet for their project to receive financing by the World Bank.  The ESF is less proscriptive in its approach than the former safeguard policies, requiring Bank staff to exercise more judgment in the management of environmental and social risk.  It adopts an adaptive management approach over the project cycle that will change the way teams think about designing and delivering projects.  It also enhances the scope of social issues covered, boosts protection for the environment and the poorest and most vulnerable people, and addresses new issues such as labor and community health that will require both Bank and Borrowers to learn new technical skills.  For more information on the ESF please consult the following link: 

https://consultations.worldbank.org/consultation/review-and-update-world-bank-safeguard-policies

The Bank has developed a plan to implement the ESF in four phases over five years.  Implementation will require capacity strengthening of both Borrowers and Bank staff, to upgrade existing skills, learn new skills, and adapt behaviors to a new way of working.  It will also require renewed management systems, procedures and processes, development of knowledge resources and guidance materials for Borrowers and Bank staff, and a range of additional activities to support both the Bank and the Borrowers to transition to the new Framework.     

The World Bank Group is now seeking experienced consulting firms to provide services in support of the implementation of the Framework.

The World Bank seeks to pre-qualify consulting firms specialized in the delivery of professional environmental, social and health and safety consulting services for support across a range of tasks and topic areas, in support of ESF implementation.   Firms should indicate their wish to bid on some or all of the following work and/or technical areas.  The Bank reserves the right to add additional assignments at a later date.   

Potential work areas:
	Support for the design and development of training materials
	Support for the delivery of training to Bank staff
	Support for the delivery of training to Borrowers
	Support for the development of guidance materials, procedures, processes and documentation

Areas of specialist technical expertise of interest include:
	Environmental and Social Impact Assessment
	Environmental and Social Risk Analysis
	Non-discrimination
	Indigenous Peoples
	Resettlement
	GHG accounting
	Security
	Disability
	Ecosystems Services
	Biodiversity/Critical Habitat
	Occupational Health and Safety
	Labor
	Community Health and Safety
	Natural Hazard Assessment
	Cultural Heritage including intangible
	Financial Intermediaries
	Stakeholder Engagement
	Emergency response planning

Bidders are encouraged to partner with other companies or individuals where specialist skill sets may be required.  Firms may appear in up to two bids, if one of those bids is as part of a consortium.

Bidders should specify those areas of expertise and work packages for which they wish to be considered.  Not all firms are expected to offer all areas of expertise, or be able to deliver on all work packages.   Failure to offer all areas will not necessarily disadvantage a bidder.   

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.

Submissions should be no longer than 20 pages plus CVs</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-05T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232031</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Consulting Services in Support of the Implementation of the new World Bank Environmental and Social Framework for Investment Project Financing Operations</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453188</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232031</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56567</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that the firm has a well-established track record in delivering on the types of services described in one or more of the work packages, or with relevant specialist technical expertise, in an international development context, with public sector and/or experience working with the World Bank or similar organizations.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56568</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm including showing a delivery team of professional staff with demonstrated expertise and experience in the management of environmental, social or health and safety issues : (a) At least 5 years demonstrated experience in one or more of the work packages described, or areas of technical expertise; and (b) International experience working with environmental and social risk management in different countries.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56563</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information demonstrating proficiency in delivering documents in English.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56565</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56566</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56564</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>