<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232001</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-08T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-15T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY INTERNATIONAL FINANCE CORPORATION
REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST
Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html
ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW
Assignment Title: 1232001 - Firm -A study on consumer preferences for solar off-grid products
Assignment Countries:
  - India
ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
India has the largest population in the planet without electricity access, with nearly 60 million households (300mn people) un-electrified. During the period 2013  2016, sales of quality assured solar lighting products in India, doubled from 1 million to 2 million units and India is the single largest potential market for this product category. Despite this growth, market penetration remains below 10%. Some of the road blocks to the adoption of solar lights - namely awareness and availability of quality products, and access to consumer finance, remain. A consumer preference study is therefore required, to understand the current consumer preferences and challenges to the adoption of solar lights. The findings from the study will lead to the Lighting Asia/India program providing inputs based on consumer insights, to the stakeholders-manufacturers, distributors etc. for efficient working in the market.
ELIGIBILITY
A.	SCOPE OF WORK 
IFC is hiring a research firm to conduct research on consumer perceptions, preferences and willingness to pay for solar lighting and select DC appliances (IFC will provide a list of these appliances to be studied like DC fans, TVs etc.). It will also help understand the variety of off-grid lighting products that are currently being sold in India.
The findings of this study will assist the solar products manufacturing and distribution (and other stakeholders) companies in developing their go to market strategies and product offerings, and will also inform the design of a consumer education campaign to be implemented by the program to promote quality assured solar lighting products in the country.  

B.	Research Methodology
Qualitative and Quantitative Research - For this activity, the firm will employ a range of research techniques, with an emphasis on focus groups discussions individual household surveys, and retailer surveys to provide data and analysis on the following topics: 
(1)Current off-grid lighting, appliances and mobile phone charging practices, including:(Respondents-Current users of Solar/off grid products)
a.Technology used for lighting and mobile charging
b.Technology used for any other household non-cooking energy needs (e.g. TVs, fans), and hours of use per day. 
c.Key decision criteria while making a purchase decision for an off grid lighting product (price, runtime, brightness etc.)
d.Typical number and type of lighting devices used and hours of use per day.
e.Typical monthly expenditure and any seasonal variations in expenditure on lighting, mobile phone charging and other appliances (for all types  candles, kerosene, batteries, diesel generators).
f.Any potential large energy consumers/productive uses (e.g. rice mills, water pumps). Potential institutional users of solar lighting like schools, rice mills, government offices etc.
g.Information on the electricity situation within the household and in the surrounding area (e.g. if the house is grid-connected, hours of power cuts in a day, number of households with electricity in a given locality etc.)
h.Profile of the off grid appliances user (education, occupation, earning, nature of appliance used etc.)

(2)Awareness and perception of solar lighting, including investigation of: (Users and Non users of solar lights)
a.General awareness of solar lighting products along with positive or negative perception of solar lighting
b.Previous direct experience with solar lighting (e.g. product details, prices paid, product performance and lifespan, distribution channel). 

(3)Preferences and willingness to pay for solar lighting products (based on demonstration of different solar lighting products): ((Users and non-users)?
a.Preferences in terms of type of product (e.g. task light, solar lantern, small solar home systems, solar appliances including fans and TVs).
b.Price points/willingness to pay for different product types.
c.Preferences for product performance and particular product features. 
d.Preferences for different sales models (e.g. direct cash sales, consumer financing, pay-as-you-go systems).  

(4)Social, cultural or gender factors influencing consumer perception, buying behavior and usage patterns.

(5)Preferences for media and communications/marketing channels:
a.Preferred radio stations, TV stations, newspapers, and/or other media sources. 
b.Other trusted sources of information (e.g. the government, religious leaders, celebrities, etc.). 
c.Other organizations active in the local area (e.g. NGOs, MFIs, distribution companies, etc.).

(6)Quantitative survey will be undertaken of those participating in the FGDs to document consumer preference and behavior. Data will be used to further substantiate the FGD results.

The research will include fieldwork in Bihar, Uttar Pradesh, Rajasthan and Odisha. The qualitative research will include fieldwork in at least 5 districts in each state (to be aligned with the list of districts finalized for the consumer campaign) and preferably 2 FGDs in each district with 8-10 participants.

The research will target a representative population sample of suitable size that takes into account variations of:
Demographics including age, profession,education
Geography
Income level
Rural/peri-urban location
Grid-connected/off-grid; prior experience with LED lighting technology and/or solar lighting products
Gender balance
The firm will propose a detailed research methodology that will take these considerations into account. This will also include suggestions on the areas/geographies where fieldwork will be undertaken and the selection criteria. A final decision on the fieldwork areas will be taken jointly with the IFC program team.  
Notes: 
1) The firm will be responsible for all the logistics and related costs including but not limited to the following:
-Identify the participants and location for the focus groups. 
-Lead focus group sessions and questionnaire surveys in the language appropriate for the participants
-Provide all necessary ground transportation for the field team conducting the focus groups to and from the sessions and the nearby city where the team has accommodations
-Provide all necessary ground transportation for the focus group participants to and from both sessions
-Provide necessary/appropriate food and  refreshments during focus group sessions
-Procure and transport solar lighting/appliances samples from relevant client/IFC office to the location of the focus group sessions 
-Take professional photos during the focus group sessions 
-Compensate the owner of the premises where the focus group sessions are held if and as required 
 Provide transcription of all interviews/questionnaire surveys in English 
 Provide a preliminary report detailing the data collected during the FGD and survey questionnaires in word and/or excel format
2)The firm should provide approach and methodology for both the qualitative and quantitative components separately and clearly

C.	Field Work Quality Control by IFC and Consultants
IFC reserves the right to monitor the quality of data collected by the firms interviewers (a quality control approach/methodology to be mutually decided before start of the work). These checks may be performed in a random sample of respondents and questionnaires determined by the IFC, and at times based on the data collection schedule agreed to by the IFC and the consultants.
Acceptance of Deliverables: Deliverables will be accepted if 
 The whole scope of work presented in this TOR has been addressed, and
 IFC comments on the draft reports/presentations have been incorporated and adequately addressed in the final reports.
Note - Should it be necessary to modify the budget, scope of work or exceed the time allocated, the firm must discuss the circumstances with IFC and obtain prior written approval through a modification of the contract.  
The firm will be required to undertake a quick desk based review of similar studies undertaken by other IFC programs like Lighting Asia/India I and, Lighting Africa, Lighting Pakistan, Lighting Bangladesh, to enhance its understanding of the research required and to incorporate the learnings and experience from these programs in the methodology and approach. The information about these will be provided to the firm who has been awarded the contract.  

D.	DELIVERABLES/SPECIFIC OUTPUTS EXPECTED FROM FIRM
SEE ATTACHED TOR

E.	SPECIFIC INPUTS TO BE PRESENTED BY IFC TO THE FIRM 
SEE ATTACHED TOR

F.	SPECIAL TERMS &amp; CONDITIONS / SPECIFIC CRITERIA
SEE ATTACHED TOR

G.	Special Terms &amp; Conditions / Specific Requirements
SEE ATTACHED TOR</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-15T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232001</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Firm -A Study on Consumer Preferences for Solar Off-Grid Products</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453148</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232001</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453149</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232001</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF011083</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SBA MDTF CE and REff Regional</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56513</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56510</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56511</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>