<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232420</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-23T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-04T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Assignment Title: 1232420 - Research Analyst for the Study of the GEF Support for Transformational Change

The Independent Evaluation Office of the Global Environment Facility (GEF) is requesting Expressions of Interest from individual consultants  research analysts  for the Study of the GEF Support for Transformational Change. 

Transformational Change
Transformational change is deep, systemic, and sustainable change with large-scale impact in an area of a major environmental concern. Catalyzing transformational change is one of the strategic priorities of the GEF.  The Study will aim to inform GEF-7 about the lessons from experience for the identification, design and implementation of GEF interventions that could support transformational changes.

Responsibilities and Accountabilities
The consultant  research analyst  will perform the following tasks:

1.	Gather information on GEF interventions sampled for the study, including from project documents, GEF IEO evaluations and evaluations of GEF Agencies, terminal evaluations and mid-term reviews, as well as external evaluations, studies, and publications.
2.	Review data and information gathered and enter it into templates provided by the IEO.
3.	Conduct a qualitative and quantitative analysis and prepare intermediary analytical outputs for the study.
4.	Perform any other duties that may emerge during the course of the study. 
The IEO will provide quality assurance, methodological support, technical inputs, as well as documentation.

Qualification Criteria
1.	A Masters degree in environmental management or policy or other relevant social sciences
2.	Three years experience in evaluation, research and/or policy analysis
3.	Experience with international environmental projects, programs, and organizations 
4.	Strong quantitative and qualitative analytical skills
5.	Demonstrated experience with preparing analytical outputs 
6.	Excellent writing and speaking in English
7.	Some previous experience with qualitative comparative analysis (QCA) is preferred 

Submission Requirements
Interested consultants are invited to submit expressions of interest and CVs in English by December 4, 2016 through the World Bank Group online platform: http://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html. Click on Business Opportunities at the top of the screen, choose Selection #: 1232420. If any technical questions regarding submitting your application, please contacts the helpdesk at wbgeconsultant@worldbank.org; phone: (202) 473-1010.

Notes
The assignment will be for a maximum of 30 work days. The duration of the contract is from December 2016 to March 2017. The consultants daily rate will be determined using the World Bank rules and procedures. The position can be home-based.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-04T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232420</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Research Analyst for the Study of the GEF Support for Transformational Change</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453960</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232420</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>