<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232801</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-14T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Position of Agriculture Banking Specialist

The International Finance Corporation, a member of the World Bank Group, promotes sustainable private sector investment in developing countries as a way to reduce poverty. IFC, through the Private Enterprise Partnership (PEP), also executes a major donor-funded program of private sector advisory work in Eastern Europe, Central Asia and the Caucasus. The objectives of the program are to promote direct investment in the private sector, build local businesses and financial intermediaries, and help improve the business enabling environment. 
IFC Europe and Central Asia Agri-Finance Project (ECA Agri-Finance) supports local banks to develop and/or improve lending to actors in the agribusiness value chain as part of a comprehensive agribusiness banking strategy. The ultimate goal of the Project is to improve (a) access to finance, and (b) productivity and access to markets for farmers/producers of supply chains in Eastern European and Central Asia countries including Azerbaijan.
ECA Agri-Finance created various products and approaches (tools/developments and methodologies) for agricultural banking, which are successfully used in Ukraine and other countries to improve agriculture lending and access to finance (A2F) expansion. Particularly, the project has developed an agriculture/crop and profitability matrix (CLARA) for agricultural financing and agricultural leasing. CLARA will be used in Azerbaijan but some adaptation to Azerbaijan crops is required, therefore some local agriculture specific knowledge will be necessary.  The Agriculture Banking Specialist will be required to understand agriculture lending principles and assist financial institutions to adapt their banking practices to better agriculture lending approaches, inclusive of updating processes and methodologies, credit risk assessment tools, helping farmers prepare for agriculture lending requirements, and other such related tasks.

SCOPE OF WORK
	Assemble and analyze key risks and value chains understanding costs of production and economic implications of crop/animal husbandry development. Input will go to the World Bank Agriculture Risk Assessment, bank agriculture assessments, CLARA framework development;
	The Consultant may provide support to ECA Agri-Finance team to develop detailed typical crop plans in a special format that is used in CLARA. The Consultant will also engage with expert agronomists and agricultural economists with experience relevant to the whole country and collaborate with the Project teams specialists. The consultant will also conduct analyses of agricultural sector in Azerbaijan through internet and other available sources;
	The Consultant will assist financial institutions to understand the future of agriculture and the banks role in lending, understand best agriculture lending practices and innovative approaches, develop and deliver training to banks to use new policies, procedures, and credit risk assessment tools; facilitate adaptation required by contributing to the banks agri-lending diagnostic, and mentor intermediaries on new products, tools, change management support, as required.
	The Consultant will take the cost of production formulations and update the IFC Farm Business Management Training Program.  The Consultant will design appropriate local related exercises and case studies.  The Consultant will translate the material into the local language and deliver it to farmers and agribusinesses interested in agriculture finance.;
	The Consultant will deliver training to Finance Institution clients/farmers as required;
	Other tasks and duties as required: the TOR may be adjusted to meet the Projects requirements.


APPLICANT REQUIREMENTS
The successful applicant will have:
	Practical expertise in agronomy and agricultural economics relevant to the whole country and multiple crops;
	Appropriate education and training in agrarian science from a reputable university;
	Experienced user of MS Excel and Word;
	Demonstrated ability to set priorities and to work with minimum supervision in order to meet changing deadlines;
	Methodological skills to identify, collect, summarize data;  
	Strong presentation and teaching skills required;
	Excellent written and spoken Azerbaijani and English language;
	Able to work in a team, well-organized, self-confident and energetic.

PERIOD OF PERFORMANCE AND DELIVERABLES
	The Consultant will work offsite and onsite as per a mutually agreed work plan.
	Start of the contract period: January 15, 2017; End of the period: June 30, 2017.
	The contract may be reviewed annually subject to work requirements.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-14T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232801</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Selection of Agriculture Banking Specialist</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">AZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Azerbaijan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454778</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232801</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454779</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232801</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017314</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Hungary EXIM Bank-Funding Agri for ECA (Agri Finance)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>