<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232703</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-14T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Position of Agriculture Insurance Specialist/Trainer/Analyst

The IFC Agri-Finance Project would like to increase access to finance to agriculture.  To do so, the Project works on facilitating financial intermediaries to lend to agriculture with legislative and regulatory reform, advisory services to understand agriculture and how to more efficiently lend to the agriculture sector.  In addition, the Project focuses on the risks facing agriculture through the establishment and development of agriculture insurance.  In this role, the Project can work with Government and legislators/regulators to improve the laws, regulations and sector oversight to foster the proper and robust development of agriculture insurance.  The Project will also work with the private sector to develop and advance new and useful insurance products to foster lending and overall growth of the agriculture.

SCOPE OF WORK
	developing a concept with the government bodies like Ministry of Agriculture and Financial Market Supervision Authority (MoA and FMSA) and other stakeholders;
	participate in the drafting or amending of laws, normative acts and regulations with respect to agri-insurance;
	mapping the task and information flow of MoA, FMSA and other stakeholders;
	facilitating the development of statutes to support operations of the Public Private Partnership (PPP) entity;
	mentoring/coaching/observing that the entity is operating well/troubleshooting;
	working to create public awareness, designing materials and training programs, training farmers and other stakeholders, writing articles, etc to promote the understanding and uptake of agriculture insurance;
	provide individual consultations to project stakeholders where needed to understand their position or to work out compromises and agreement;
	assist the Project Manager in any other duties as required.

APPLICANT REQUIREMENTS
The successful applicant will have:
	A finance or economics degree from a reputable National university, special degree in insurance is preferable;
	Understanding of the agriculture and insurance sector, its legal framework and major stakeholders in Azerbaijan;
	Methodological skills to identify, collect, summarize data;  
	Strong presentation and teaching skills required;
	A minimum of 5 years relevant work experience in areas of the insurance sector;
	Excellent written and spoken Azerbaijani and English language;
	Computer literate; 
	Able to work in a team, well-organized, self-confident and energetic.

PERIOD OF PERFORMANCE AND DELIVERABLES
	The Consultant will work offsite and onsite as per a mutually agreed work plan.
	Start of the contract period: December 15, 2016; End of the period: June 30, 2017. 
	Contract may be renewed annually subject to work requirements.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-14T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232703</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Selection of Agriculture Insurance Specialist/Trainer/Analyst</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">AZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Azerbaijan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454576</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232703</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454577</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232703</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017314</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Hungary EXIM Bank-Funding Agri for ECA (Agri Finance)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>