<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232360</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-28T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-19T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The World Bank is seeking a consultant to conduct a review of the regulatory and institutional framework and provide recommendations for the enhancement of the SME credit guarantee and other government supported market friendly instruments for improving access to finance for SMEs in the Philippines.

Philippines law sets mandatory targets for lending to micro, small and medium enterprises (MSMEs) with the objective to improve access to finance in these underserved sectors. RA 10000 known as Agri-Agra Law requires that all banks allocate 25% of their total loanable funds for agriculture and fisheries credit, of which at least 10% of the loanable funds should be allocated to agrarian reform beneficiaries. Magna Carta for MSME requires that all banks allocate at least 8% of their loan portfolio to micro and small enterprises and 2% to medium enterprises.
The analysis of compliance with mandatory lending targets to MSMEs and agriculture indicates that on a system basis banks struggle to expand lending to micro and small enterprises and agrarian reform beneficiaries. Over the past five years lending to micro and small enterprises grew on average at 3% per annum, to medium enterprises at 13%, lending to agriculture actually declined. At the same time total lending portfolio expanded at an average rate of 25% per annum. Despite the targets, growth in priority sectors was significantly lower than the growth of the overall lending portfolio. Philippines experience is not unique and evidence from other countries over the years indicates that lending volume targets are ineffective and may contribute to greater level of risks in the system.
Credit guarantee schemes are one of the more market friendly types of interventions for SMEs, as they commonly combine a subsidy element with market-based arrangements for credit allocation.  Unlike other types of interventions directed lending arrangements or subsidized lending schemes, they may generate fewer distortions in the credit market and may lead to better credit allocation outcomes. 
There is a number of institutions providing guarantees in the Philippines. Small Business Guarantee and Finance Corporation, known as Small Business Corporation or SB Corp) is designated as the primary agency providing assistance to MSMEs including but not limited to finance. PhilEXIM also is a potentially important source of guarantees and credit insurance for exporter SMEs.  Both institutions are small and currently are not able to fully perform the functions envisaged in their mandate due to a range of constraints including regulatory, capital, skills, and ability to attract and retain qualified staff.  


Scope of Work
1. Review existing legal and regulatory framework for operation of credit guarantee instruments including RA8289, RA9501 and relevant regulations.
2. Review performance of existing SME guarantee instruments based on available reports, interviews with guarantee providers, banks, and SMEs.
3. Drawing on international experience SB Corp provides primarily direct financing and not guarantees.  There is an opportunity to refocus and reform guarantee mechanisms in the Philippines to help facilitate provision of credit to the underserved sectors in an efficient manner through the reform of the guarantee instruments as well as other investment incentive vehicles for start-up and early stage companies equity finance.      
provide recommendations for improving legal and regulatory framework and options for enhancing guarantee instrument.
4. Drawing on international experience, provide recommendations on structuring start-up equity finance program to stimulate equity finance by private sector for start-up and early stage SMEs.

Deliverables
1. Recommendations report on the Philippines SME guarantee and equity finance support. The report should cover (1) international experience on the effectiveness of SME guarantee instruments drawing on recent reports by OECD, World Bank and other international organizations; (2) assessment of effectiveness of existing SME guarantees in the Philippines (3) assessment of strengths and weaknesses of the legal and regulatory framework for SME government guarantee fund and equity fund operations in the Philippines and recommendations on improvements; (4) a set of possible options for enhancement of guarantee instruments and introduction of equity finance vehicles to stimulate early stage equity finance by private sector for SMEs
2. Delivery of a presentations summarizing preliminary and final report findings and recommendation options for key counterparts.
3. The work is estimated to require 30 man-days and to be completed within 5 months starting January 2017.
Qualifications
International experience with at least 10 years of work experience in SME and retail finance.
Strong understanding of framework and operation of government support programs for SME finance, especially guarantee funds and equity funds or similar structures
Demonstrated ability to conduct country-level assessment of effectiveness of available mechanisms drawing on international experience
Demonstrated ability to effectively manage engagement with multiple stakeholders and sensitivity to the associated cultural and political context
Demonstrated ability to work in a multicultural team
Flexibility to travel and ability to deliver under tight deadlines
Excellent communications and report writing skills in English</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-19T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232360</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Philippines SME credit guaranty review</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">PH</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Philippines</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454263</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232360</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454264</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232360</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3771</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">PH Financial Development and Inclusion</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>