<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232253</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-11-22T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-19T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>IFC is tendering for a firm to evaluate and provide guidance on the potential (or feasibility) for specific gender related housing finance products. It should determine whether there is a business case for the offering of specific gender related housing finance products (e.g. mortgage, home improvement loans, etc.). In order to determine the business opportunity, three topics are of relevance:

1. The Barriers that women currently face in accessing housing finance (and housing):
	- Obstacles that prevent women from accessing a title on a home (e.g. 
        regulatory constraints) 
	- Obstacles that prevent women from obtaining a housing loan 
	- Obstacles that prevent financial institutions from creating and providing appropriate financial mechanisms to increase women's access to housing

2. Market related opportunity for gender-related housing finance products and mechanisms 
	- Size of the gender gap in housing finance [mortgages secured]
	- Size of the market for women housing finance borrowers [total revenue]
	- Segments of women affected most by these barriers, e.g. based on income or 
        employment

3. Recommendations for lenders to target women as borrowers and clients (including potential product solutions)
	- Changes need to the enabling environment to increase women's access to a
        title (e.g. legal/regulatory framework)
	- What housing providers can do to target women as borrowers (new products,
        educational/marketing measures)
	- Incentives that can be created for lenders to develop specific financial 
        products &amp; services for female customers.

4. Additional information about the research work to be undertaken:

Data availability. The research is expected to outline the market opportunity of gender-related housing finance products and financial mechanisms, if possible with quantitative data, but at the minimum with qualitative data, underline the barriers that women currently face in accessing housing finance and finally develop recommendations that housing finance providers can implement in order to specifically target women as clients and borrowers. The recommendations should also outline/sketch potential product solutions that are poised to increase the access of women to housing finance. As data may be difficult to obtain, the consultant needs to make several design choices in scoping the research: (i) how to identify and isolate target segments of female borrowers; (ii) desired precision and granularity of findings; (iii) how to augment existing data: resource-intensity of primary data collection methods. 
	
Individual country assessments. The study should include an assessment of 3 countries to showcase the business case. Currently, the following countries have been considered for a more detailed analysis: Colombia, India and Kenya. The firm is requested to review these suggestions of countries critically (in the proposal).

Firms which are interested to sent an EOI should met the following qualification:

- Superior drafting skills and high command of the English language;
- Solid track record in research and analysis related to financial sector issues (especially retail banking/residential housing finance). Expertise and knowledge of econometric modeling, and gender gap analysis is considered an asset;
- Experience in gender related issues in an emerging market context;
- Good understanding of regulatory and institutional frameworks in emerging markets;
- Deep understanding of banking, especially retail banking and mortgage loan products;
- Good understanding of the constrains on the supply of affordable housing;
- Good understanding of process flows within a lenders organization is considered an asset;
- Good understanding of the gender business case</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-19T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232253</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Gender Housing Finance Pilot</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453611</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232253</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A2433</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Gender Housing Finance Initiative</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">453610</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232253</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56619</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56620</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56621</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">56622</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>