<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1232838</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-11T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The Independent Evaluation Office of the Global Environment Facility (IEO) is requesting Expressions of Interest from individual consultants for the Formative Process Review of the Sustainable Cities IAP program.

As part of its work program for GEF-6 the IEO has been tasked with the Sixth Overall Performance Study (OPS6) of the GEF, assessing the extent to which the GEF is achieving its objectives and identifying potential areas of improvement. The reviewing of the Sustainable Cities IAP program (hereafter called Cities IAP), one of three IAP programs being implemented under GEF-6, is part of the OPS6 process. Common among these three pilots is that they are designed with the objective to address global environmental issues more holistically, within a much broader and more complex set of development challenges. 

The purpose of the process review is to critically assess the potential of the Cities IAP to generate multiple Global Environmental Benefits (GEBs) through integrated planning and investments related to urban sustainability that result in environmental, social and economic benefits at the local and global scale. The three overarching OPS6 objectives for the formative process review of the Cities IAP are the following: 
(i) To provide early evidence on whether the design of the IAPs is based on a more holistic approach compared with standard programmatic approaches and reflects synergies in delivering focal area strategies and the implementation of the Multilateral Environmental Agreements (MEAs), while accounting for country needs and ownership;
(ii) To provide early insights into whether the design of these pilots have drawn on the strengths and comparative advantage of the various partner agencies and the Secretariat and are encouraging within partnership collaboration;
(iii) To analyze the extent that these pilot programs aligned with the overall GEF-6 strategy and the System for Transparent Allocation of Resources (STAR) allocation framework, the GEFs resource allocation system for biodiversity, climate change, and land degradation focal areas?

The findings, conclusions and recommendations of the review will inform OPS6.

The IEO invites highly motivated and experienced senior consultants to indicate their interest in providing their services. Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (CV and cover letter). 

Selection criteria include:
i. Master or advanced degree in a subject matter related to urban development, urban environmental improvement, urban sector development issues, or related areas
ii. At least 15 years of experience in large scale policy, strategic, thematic and/or program evaluations, including significant experience in the evaluation of urban sustainability / urban environmental improvement initiatives globally in the context of international organizations
iii. Background and experience in the areas of environment or sustainable development, with a general understanding of global environmental issues
iv. Preferred knowledge of and/or direct experience with the GEF and its Agencies
v. Strong quantitative and qualitative data gathering and analysis skills
vi. Proven ability to write concise reports and excellent speaking skills in English. Additional professional communication skills in UN languages will be considered an added advantage.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-11T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1232838</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Senior Consultant  Formative Process Review of the Sustainable Cities Integrated Approach Pilot (IAP) Program.</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454845</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232838</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">454846</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1232838</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF010191</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Multi-Year Evaluations</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>