<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1233732</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-20T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-29T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>IFC Climate Business

Terms of Reference 
Communications Analyst
 Short-Term Consultant
(January  June 2017)

BACKGROUND

IFC, a member of the World Bank Group, is the largest global development institution focused exclusively on the private sector in developing countries. IFC works in more than a 100 developing countries and allows companies and financial institutions in emerging markets to create jobs, generate tax revenues, improve corporate governance and environmental performance, and contribute to their local communities. 

IFC has been investing in climate businesses for 10 years. As the international community contemplates how to keep warming within a 2 degree increase, they are looking to the private sector to provide insights into how to build more sustainable economies. With $13 billion of investments in renewable energy, resource efficiency, agriculture, forestry and other climate sectors, IFC is being asked to share its experiences in international dialogues, conferences and working groups. GCCCS has worked with investment staff to build this portfolio and the staff time is allocated accordingly. The short term contractor will leverage GCCCSs industry and strategy expertise by supporting the thought leadership process. 

OBJECTIVES AND PURPOSE OF ASSIGNMENT

The objective of this short-term assignment is to provide communications and analytical support to IFC Climate Business department (CBD), reporting directly to the Senior Communications Officer, focusing on web, social media and content development. The Analyst will work closely with industry teams to research the projects and portfolios, extract lessons learned and package into impact stories, features and social media messages, as well as provide support with internal and external web/content management and media outreach tracking. 

SCOPE OF WORK 

(1)	Analytical Support for developing stories and features drawing on IFCs climate-investments globally
-	Work closely with IFC Climate Anchors to determine success stories; draft into blurbs and larger communications pieces
-	Develop a pipeline of blogs and feature stories
-	Identify and map out digital media channels for the content to be places/featured

(2)	Support with web and online platforms
-	Provide periodic fact-checking and update of CBD external and internal web platforms, identify content gaps and package content appropriately; 
-	Work with CBD Senior Communications Officer to set and manage IFC online editorial calendar; 
-	Post news items to landing page of CBD site; ensure consistency with CCG themes and priorities;
-	Help select and maintain a database of photos and usable graphics for various knowledge management and communications outputs (such as Factsheets, brochures, case studies, etc.)

(3)	Events, Campaign Support and Other Tasks 

-	Assistance with campaigns and events, including help with identify speakers and format and organizational support (with relevant CBD program support staff);
-	Help publicize the event throughout the World Bank and IFC channels;
-	Support development of marketing collateral, publications design, typesetting and layout, as well as provide copy-editing support as needed as related to events and/or other communications outputs
-	Monitor and track media mentions of IFCs climate-smart investments, analyze and report on trends.


DELIVERABLES:

-	Deliverables will be specified as per the above stated scope of work and upon the needs of each event and activity 
-	The timeline for this project will run from approximately January 15 - June 30, 2017

REQUIRED SKILLS:

-	Advanced university degree completed or in progress in Communications, Business Administration, Environmental Studies, Knowledge Management, International Development or related fields with 3+ years of relevant experience 
-	Strong English writing skills and ability to synthesize complex technical information into concise and well-written communications and strategy materials 
-	Solid skills in content development and packaging for various audiences and channels
-	Background and understanding of economic development and the climate change agenda, as well as the relevant audience groups
-	Ability to carry out tasks with efficiency, communicate ideas clearly, articulate issues and recommend solutions 
-	Strong team player with strong organizational skills and demonstrated ability to handle multiple tasks simultaneously with minimal supervision 

TO APPLY:

-	Eligible consultants are invited to indicate their interest by submitting a CV and cover letter, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 , under "Business Opportunities" then look for selection number ) in order to apply for the position. 
-	Applications can also be submitted by email to: spanajyan@ifc.org with a Cover letter and a CV. Please, indicate CBD Communications Analyst Application in the title.
-	The deadline for applications is Thursday, December 29, 2016.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-29T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1233732</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>IFC Climate Business Department Communications Analyst - Short-Term Consultant</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">456683</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233732</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>