<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1233231</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-08T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-20T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1233231 - FEASIBILITY STUDY FOR TECHNOLOGY CENTER- BANGLADESH

Assignment Countries:
  - Bangladesh

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The World Bank intends to hire consulting firm to carry out a feasibility assessment for the development of a network of Technology Upgrade Centers to address skills, technology awareness and access, technology utilization barriers, and business development services, particularly in target sectors like Leather, leather goods and Footwear (leather &amp; non-leather), Plastic and Electronics/electrical goods. 

This network will potentially provide a range of services designed to help upgrade the production and management capabilities of small and medium sized businesses, and improve the supply chain linkages within these sectors. The target market will be both SMEs and large sized businesses depending on the sector, need, and the sector strategies driving the overarching initiative.  These centers and technologies address cross cutting issues (e.g. waste management to spare parts fabrication and testing and calibration services), based on project requirements. Services may include;
	Technology demonstration  housing modern manufacturing equipment and processes and providing access to these to SMEs. 
	Workforce training on new production technologies. 
	Business advisory services  including change management, production and technology up gradation, management improvement
	Internationally accredited product and component testing and certification services with strong demand (another potential revenue source). 
	Supply chain and market development services

Interested consultants must provide the following information that will indicate that they are qualified to perform the services:
-Provide information on your expertise and experience with prior similar assignments; experience in similar conditions; availability of appropriate skills among technical and managerial staff, etc.
-Provide information on their core business and years in business.
-Demonstrate a capability to meet the World Bank Groups Vendor Eligibility Criteria as available on www.worldbank.org/corporateprocurement.  
Please note that Marketing Brochures should only be provided as attachments and will not be considered as a substitute for written responses.  Elaborate artwork is not required or encouraged. 
WBG reserves the right to limit the number of qualified firms shortlisted for efficiency. WBG reserves the right to verify any information provided, or to request additional information after REOI packages are received. WBG reserves the right to proceed, or to not proceed, with issuing an RFP. WBG reserves the right to modify the scope of work for the RFP as necessary to meet Project requirements. 
All data and information received from WBG for the purpose of this assignment are to be treated confidentially and are only to be used in connection with the execution of these tasks. The contents of written materials obtained and used in this assignment may not be disclosed to any third parties without the expressed advance written notice of WBG.
Responses must be delivered through the EConsultant2 system on or before 20 December 2016 and shall not exceed 10 pages. If the submitted response exceeds 10 pages, WBG reserves the right to read only the first 10.
By responding to this REOI, you are confirming compliance with the World Bank Group Procurement Policy.


INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services. Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB. onsultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-20T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1233231</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>FEASIBILITY STUDY FOR TECHNOLOGY CENTER- BANGLADESH</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">BD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Bangladesh</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">455636</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233231</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">20</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">455637</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233231</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3151</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">80</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Enhancing export diversification through greater conenctivity and integration into global value chain</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57141</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57142</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57143</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57144</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>