<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1233694</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-04T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-19T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1233694 - S&#227;o Tom&#233; and Pr&#237;ncipe - Multi-Tier framework for Energy Access -National Household Survey

Assignment Countries:
  - Sao Tome and Principe

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The World Bank Group, and ESMAP team, in collaboration with the Ministry of Finance, Commerce and Blue Economy  of S&#227;o Tom&#233; and Pr&#237;ncipe, are launching the first Global Energy Access household Survey in access deficit. The survey would set a baseline to track progress towards Sustainable Energy for All (SE4All) goal and Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) number seven on access to affordable, reliable and sustainable modern energy by 2030, and an overall baseline for the Power Sector Recovery Project IDA D1260.
The Democratic Republic of S&#227;o Tom&#233; and Pr&#237;ncipe is a small island state comprising two main volcanic islands and several islets located off the west coast of Central Africa in the Gulf of Guinea. Sao Tome, the largest island, covers an area of 859 km2 and has around 180,000 inhabitants, Principe Island, situated 150 km to the North, covers about 142 km2 and has around 7,500 inhabitants. The country is divided into six districts (Agua Grande, Cantagalo, Cau&#233;, Lemb&#225;, Lobata, and M&#233;-Z&#243;chi) plus the Autonomous Region of Pr&#237;ncipe, which has been self-governed since 1995.
Access to electricity in S&#227;o Tom&#233; and Pr&#237;ncipe has increased from 53% to 61% of the population from 2000 to 2012. However, this access is concentrated in the urban areas (68%) with rural areas lagging behind (47%) . Electricity access is more widespread among non-poor families (58%) than poorer families (48%). While there is no available data on the quantity or duration of power cuts, service quality is widely acknowledged as unreliable and extensive outages are frequent, especially during periods of peak demand. This limited supply, even to those connected to the grid, leaves only privately owned diesel of gasoline generators for reliable supply, which results in a costly and unsustainable proposition for household budgets and private sector growth. Kerosene is a frequent recourse for lighting in both poor household (42%) and in relatively non-poor households (32%). The use of other energy sources varies widely, with 74% of household in rural areas using firewood or charcoal for cooking, compared to 35% in urban areas. The low rate of access to non-solid fuels for cooking, estimated at 29%  has an impact on pollution from solid fuel stoves which can cause eye problems and respiratory diseases. 
A reputed firm with extensive experience in household and, preferably, expertise on energy sector is sought to conduct the household, community/facility and enterprise baseline survey on energy access in S&#227;o Tom&#233; and Pr&#237;ncipe using the multi-tier framework approach to track progress towards SDG7 and SE4ALL goal. The survey will be nationally representative and administered to both urban and rural localities. The firm will work with the World Bank-ESMAP to pre-test, finalize and implement the survey. Data collection should be carefully monitored to ensure high quality information. The firm will provide capacity building to the National Institute of Statistics (Institute Nacional de Estat&#237;sticas ) and the Ministry of Finance, Commerce and Blue Economy to ensure continuity on tracking of energy indicators. After completing the fieldwork, the firm will deliver the final dataset and summary report to the World Bank-ESMAP.  Additional details on the scope of work will be available in the Terms of Reference (TOR). 
Interested firms should provide a brief summary of their qualifications to perform the services (maximum of 3 pages). The short-listing criteria will be based on:
1.	Experience in carrying out household and enterprise surveys in Sub-Saharan Africa, and specific experience in S&#227;o Tom&#233; and Pr&#237;ncipe is highly desirable;
2.	Experience in the energy and other infrastructure sectors (e.g. water and sanitation); 
3.	In-depth understanding of the energy access sector and its socio-economic dimensions; 
4.	Strong technical skills in qualitative/quantitative research and data analysis; 
5.	Proven skill in using CAPI-tablet based data collection ;
6.	Cultural awareness in dealing with local communities, and interacting with government and local authorities;  and,
7.	Excellent writing and analytical and presentation skills in English and Portuguese.

Preference will be giving to local firms with high knowledge of the country sector and socio-economic context, also, international firms are encouraged to team up with local partners. The assignment should start in February 2017 and it is expected to be completed by end of May 2017.
Short-listed firms will be invited to submit a full technical and financial proposal for the final selection round. 
The EOI must be sent by 9 January 2017.


ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-19T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1233694</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>S&#227;o Tom&#233; and Pr&#237;ncipe - Multi-Tier framework for Energy Access -National Household Survey</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">ST</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Sao Tome and Principe</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">456859</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233694</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">456860</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233694</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1528</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">MTF Global Surveys</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">456861</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233694</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3444</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Sao Tome and Principe: Strengthening energy monitoring/planning</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57417</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57418</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>