<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1233601</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-24T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-09T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Assignment Title: 1233601 - IFC Coordinator for Study on Local equity sharing schemes for hydropower projects in Nepal

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
The hydropower potential of Nepal offers a unique opportunity for both economic and social development. In order to maximize these economic and social benefits and opportunities, the government of Nepal in consultation with the various stakeholders has provisioned for various benefit sharing mechanisms arising from the hydropower development. One key aspect of the Benefit Sharing mechanism focuses particularly on the practice of offering direct financial equity or shares to local populations affected by the development of hydropower projects. 

The main objective of the consultants assignment is to oversee and guide the study of the delivery of Local Equity Sharing Schemes commonly referred to as Community Shares in Nepal, in the context of benefit sharing mechanisms applicable to hydropower projects. 

A team of experts will be hired to conduct the study, however IFC is first hiring a Consultant to coordinate the study and oversee a team of experts to produce an in-depth study on the allocation mechanism and distribution of local shares.  

The specific objectives of the study are to:
1.Undertake a big picture desk review and an analysis of the available benefit sharing models/case studies (offerings from the past, present, and future projects) preferentially with respect to hydropower, but could draw from other infrastructure or extractive projects globally. It should aim to understand their strengths, weaknesses, risks and opportunities, as well as where would Community Shares fit in the overall Benefit Sharing landscape / mechanisms;

2.Perform a detailed review of existing Community Shares examples in Nepal and elsewhere in the world, and provide a comparative analysis of the structures around and functions of the different Community Share models, the different modalities of offering shares locally, and the possible risks and rewards therein;

3.Understand and assess the range of concerns, expectations and beliefs that exist around this issue from different stakeholders (project developers, investors, policymakers, and local concern groups, political parties, etc) as well as differences within these groups;

4.Analyze the policy implications and dimensions of the implementation of Community Shares and the existing/ongoing judicial review process that is underway. Also to consider how existing policies relate to the Community Shares and how the work of different institutions relate to these issues and challenges. Suggest ways and means to align policy level issues with stakeholder expectations;

5.Based on the above analysis, discuss where these current trends might be leading to in the future and the potential implications in terms of risks and challenges these trends may have for hydropower project development in Nepal.

6.Propose and provide guidance on good practices for definition of eligibility criteria of Community Shares, as well as Delivery Mechanisms and Timing of this delivery. This guidance should clearly outline the appropriate stakeholder engagement process/ mechanism to assure that good practices include extensive consultation and engagement with all stakeholders/ think tanks and other relevant interested parties. 

Expected Outcomes of the Study
In line with the above objectives and scope of work, this study is expected to provide a Knowledge Product / Report outlining Lessons Learned and Good Practice to: 

1)Define the eligibility criteria for Community Shares (the WHO). 
2)Design and provide guidance and alternative approaches/models to implement / delivery of the Community Shares Scheme in Nepal (the HOW).
3)Provide alternative and good practice to formalize engagement of the key stakeholders in the sector with the aim to generate consensus, engagement and communication.

Expected Deliverables
The Consultant will be required to:

Deliverables	
	
1) Meet with IFC team, attend first scoping workshop on local shares January 23-26 in Kathmandu, Nepal, to lead discussions and submit a workshop report and separate summary note on findings and exchanges for further conducting the study - February 10, 2017 (5 days)

2) Elaborate on the study TOR including specifics for the envisaged team to conduct the study; support the procurement process - February 17, 2017 (5 days)

3) Develop TOR and form Consultative Panel to oversee study - March 15, 2017 (7 days)

4) Review proposals submitted, contribute to recommendations, organize virtual team meeting (depending on locations of consultants) and submit an inception report suggesting detailed approach within 15 days of other team members hired- March 30, 2017 (10 days)

5) Organize periodic Consultative Panel Meetings during the study 
a) Meeting 1: Presentation by study team on study objectives and inception report
b) Meeting 2: Before and/or after consultations
c) Meeting 3: Draft Report
d) Meeting 4: Final Report	
Periodically (12 days)

6) Oversee study team and organize a series of multi-stakeholder consultations. Submit stakeholder consultation summary and monthly progress reports	
April 1  July, 2017	(10/month for a total of 40 days)

7) Consultant team submit a draft final report and coordinator reviews/improves for submission to IFC  - August 15, 2017 (5 days)

8) Consultant team submits a final report with comments incorporated within - September 15, 2017 (5 days)

9) Preparing a presentation of findings - Oct 10, 2017	(3 days)

10 Presenting findings to various stakeholder groups - October 30, 2017	(5 days)

Total indicative days allocated		97

Selection criteria of Study Coordinator 
 Minimum 10 years of experience of working on social and environmental issues in the hydropower sector
 Extensive experience in the hydropower sector in Nepal
 Other skills include project management, engagement with stakeholders, in-depth and practical knowledge of benefit sharing mechanisms around infrastructure projects and financial tools
 Excellent  English communication and drafting skills
 Ability to work across cultures and lead a highly diverse team 

The consultant will be expected to join a local shares workshop from 23-24 January in Kathmandu.


ELIGIBILITY

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit your cover letter and CV, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-09T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1233601</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Coordinator for Study on Local equity sharing schemes for hydropower projects in Nepal</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">NP</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Nepal</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">456454</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233601</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">456455</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233601</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1440</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Rockefeller E and S Knowledge Development</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>