<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1233032</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-08T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2016-12-21T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE INTERNATIONAL FINANCE CORPORATION

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1233032 - Firm - Mapping CSR projects in renewable and off-grid energy sector in India

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The Lighting Asia/India program has been undertaking various activities since 2012 to remove market barriers to adoption of quality assured products, through a series of market interventions. The program works with manufacturers and distributors of quality assured solar lighting appliances, to help them develop a robust footprint in underserved markets in India. Over the next 3 years, the program will scale up energy access through targeted interventions in Bihar, Uttar Pradesh, Rajasthan, Odisha and Assam to help expand market access of quality assured solar lighting products and associated DC appliances like TVs/fans etc.  As part of these market building activities, the program aims to facilitate linkages between suppliers and distributes of these products with users (bulk and individual consumers) including CSR initiatives.

Scope of work

Research and Analysis:
	Create a country wide database of corporates that have an active CSR portfolio. The database should include details of the focus sector; any major projects/initiatives being undertaken as part of the CSR portfolio and contact details of the focal point. 
	Create a filtered database from the above of corporates focusing on/interested to structure CSR projects in the renewable energy/off-grid energy sector.
	A database of implementing agencies who have in the past or are currently undertaking projects in the off-grid energy sector, along with key details of these projects.
	Prepare 5-7 case studies of CSR projects that focused on off-grid energy in India to highlight challenges faced, success factors and/or reasons failures of the projects. 


Information Dissemination and Networking Facilitation:
	Organize 4-5 workshops across key cities in India to create a platform for corporates, implementing partners and other stakeholders to deliberate on and understand the current scenario of renewable energy/off-grid energy in CSR projects. This will include all administrative and logistics required organizing the workshops (setting agenda, preparing workshop kits, sending invitations, venue hiring, preparing summary of workshops, managing registration desk, feedback forms etc.).
	The consulting firm will be required to work closely with the IFC communications team and the project team to prepare a media plan and implement the same. This will include preparing press releases and support in consuming media interviews of key participants in the workshops if required.
	Special attention should be given to states of Bihar, Uttar Pradesh, Rajasthan, Odisha and Assam for all the above mentioned tasks, though events may be in other metros.

Deliverables
The following activities are to be completed by the firm: 

   Deliverables	                                 Timeline from issuance of contract
1)Inception Report: Including detailed project 
  plan and proposed methodology 	                  2 weeks
2)Country wide database of corporates with  
  active CSR portfolio 	                                  4 weeks
3)Database of corporates focused on renewable 
  energy/off-grid energy projects	                  4 weeks
4)Database of implementing partners 	                  6 weeks
5)4-5 workshops across key cities in India 	          10-12 weeks
6)5-7 case studies of CSR projects that focused 
  on off-grid energy in India	                          12-14 weeks

The format of all deliverables will be agreed with the project team during the assignment. All documents will be produced in English and will be submitted electronically to IFC as MS Word, Excel, or PowerPoint documents as required. 

ELIGIBILITY
Interested firms/consortiums should submit a proposal in the standard World Bank format addressing the following:    
    - Qualifications and competence of the key staff related to the assignment 
    - Skills and experience relevant to carrying out the required activities 
 
Please note, if proposing a consortium, firms must clearly identify a lead firm that will be the main point of contact and will be responsible for producing the deliverables described. 

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2016-12-21T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1233032</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Firm - Mapping CSR projects in renewable and off-grid energy sector in India</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">455243</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233032</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">455244</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233032</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF011083</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SBA MDTF CE and REff Regional</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57054</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57051</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57052</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57053</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>