<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1233701</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-20T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-03T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Terms of Reference for a Short Term Consultant to Support Market Analysis and Business Development in Fragile Conflict and Low Income Countries in Africa for 
Tourism, Property, Retail and Manufacturing Sectors

Dept.\Unit: MAS 
Location: TBD [preferably Abidjan]
Term: Short Term Consultant (180 working days per year) 
Contact: Mari&#232;me Travaly 

Background 
The IFC Manufacturing and Consumer Services department working on Sub Saharan Africa is seeking to undertake a detailed mapping in the following Fragile Conflict and Low Income Countries: Chad, C&#244;te dIvoire, the Gambia, Guinea, Liberia, Mali, Madagascar and Togo. 

Role 
1.	The team is looking to recruit a short term consultant, based in Abidjan, to research and analyze the Manufacturing (M), Tourism (T), Retail (R) and Property (P) (commercial and housing) markets in the above mentioned countries. The initial area of focus would be: C&#244;te dIvoire, Guinea, Liberia, Mali, and Madagascar given IFCs presence on the ground. It will be followed by the other ones: Chad, the Gambia, and Togo. 
2.	The Consultant will also do a screening of the Health and Education (H&amp;E) sectors in the above mentioned countries.
3.	Research will include desktop research, interviews with market participants as well as relevant experts (e.g. industry associations, consultants, auditors, banks, etc.), country visits and meetings with prospects. 
4.	Research should identify market dynamics (size, growth, competitive landscape, regulation etc.), key players and the financing needs of the private sector (including current sources of finance and unmet needs). 
5.	For C&#244;te dIvoire, the team has already carried out a mapping, the consultants task will be to help develop an investment thesis for each sub-sector (T, R, P) and identify potential partners and opportunities. 
6.	For Mali, the mapping will cover T, R, P and Light Manufacturing.
7.	The expected duration of the consultancy is 180 days. 

The consultant will report to the Lead for TRP for those countries and will be based in Abidjan. Given that there are 2 assignments going on for the H&amp;E sector and for the Manufacturing sector in some of these countries, the consultant will have to coordinate with the respective consultants to avoid duplicating efforts.

Deliverables 
Key deliverables will be: 
1. A report on each market, covering market dynamics and financing needs in these countries 
2. An excel spreadsheet listing key participants in each market (including an overview of their business and contact details) and identifying 5-10 companies in each market that have potential to become IFC clients; A basic IDD check will have to be done on each of the company identified.
3. An investment thesis on C&#244;te dIvoire per sub-sector along with the list and details of partners/opportunities identified

Experience, qualifications and skills 
1.	Undergraduate degree from a reputable institution
2.	2 to 3 years of experience in finance and/or consulting
3.	Good knowledge and network in Sub-Saharan Africa (SSA) which should help in identifying relevant sponsors - Working experience in the region.
4.	Solid analytical skills and commercial acumen
5.	Speaks fluently French</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-03T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1233701</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>M&amp;S Mapping in FCS Countries Consultant</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Chad</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">CI</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Cote d'Ivoire</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">GM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Gambia, The</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">GN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Guinea</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">LR</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Liberia</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">ML</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Mali</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MG</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Madagascar</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TG</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Togo</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">456625</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1233701</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>