<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234020</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-23T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-18T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The World Bank is seeking the services of a firm to conduct an analysis of how to promote forest smart Artisanal and Small Scale mining (ASM).

Background: 
In its five-year Forest Action Plan, the World Bank prioritizes investments in sustainable forest management and forest-smart interventions that take a landscape approach and consider other sectors. The present program on Extractive Industries in Forest Landscapes fits into this vision that economic sectors do not erode forest capital and generate instead positive forest outcomes. The objective of the program is to enable client countries and the World Bank Group to make better-informed decisions about minimizing trade-offs and maximizing benefits from forest-smart mining. More specifically the program will generate knowledge on the Extractives-Forest Nexus, and how to translate this into forest-smart mining strategies and accompanying tools. 

Forest-smart implies avoiding or minimizing potential adverse impacts on forests. Avoiding any impact can be targeted in landscape level planning of extractives development. Minimizing impact of mining may be pursued through mitigation or compensation measures or LSM and ASM activities. Supporting forest-smart interventions will not only ensure that adverse impacts on forests and their biodiversity are avoided or minimized, but also identify opportunities for increasing the productivity and resilience of other sectors. Maximizing benefits of forest-smart interventions can contribute to sustainable food production, providing timber, paper and energy, housing critical biodiversity and providing ecosystem services. Minimizing threats involve: avoiding deforestation and degradation; reducing greenhouse gas emissions due to land use change; mitigating impact of droughts, floods and storms; regulating water and climate, and; protecting infrastructure. 

Forest-smart interventions are based on the aforementioned integrated landscape approach. The consultancy should take into account this concept of Forest-smart mining and answers to what it exactly means for Artisanal and Small Scale Mining. 

Objective: 
The Objective of this study is to identify and analyze, by means of a series of Case studies on Artisanal and Small-scale Mining in Forest Landscapes; good and bad practices that feed into the overall studys objective and serve to identify conditions and mechanism for forest-smart ASM. 

Outcomes:  Identification of good and bad practices and/or enabling conditions related to promoting Forest-Smart ASM based on a series of case studies.
These are intended to inform policy recommendations for the World Bank and World Bank Clients on how to better facilitate/ promote 'Forest-smart mining. 

This work will be undertaken in two phases: 

A first phase will include a literature review, general assessment, refinement of criteria and presentation of a short list of potential case studies and a detailed plan of action and methodology for phase two including an outline of the final report. This work will be presented in a discussion forum, to be identified, with the World Bank.

A second phase will include in-depth analysis of case studies which presented to the World Bank and/or other parties for feedback which will be incorporated into a final report. This could include travel to a limited number of case study sites.

The Estimated budget for this work is 230,000 USD. 
The estimated duration is 8 months. 

PROFILE AND QUALIFICATION

The firm shall have a proven track record of experience in issues around artisanal mining and sustainable development, community engagement, sustainable supply chains,  environmental management and ASM, mineral sector policy development and Sustainable Forest Management 

Team members should have: 
	Strong knowledge of, and experience in, the development of policies and strategies around ASM and sustainable development. 
	Post-graduate level qualifications in a relevant field, such as conservation biology, natural resource management, mineral economics, forestry etc.
	At least ten years of relevant experience working on ASM in developing countries
	Good knowledge of the policy environment governing the artisanal mining sector with strong experience in working with governments, private companies and civil society. 
	Excellent written English, good communication and leadership skills.
	Experience in methodology design and a history of related publications. 
	Working knowledge of the languages of the countries on which case studies are to be conducted would be an asset.
	An existing network of practitioners and local experts in potential case study countries would be an asset.


Please limit the EOI to a maximum of 20 pages total.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-18T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234020</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>ADVISORY SERVICES ON: Forest Smart Mining: identifying good and bad practices of ASM in Forest Landscapes</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">457294</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234020</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">457295</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234020</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3278</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Forest Smart Strategies for the Extractive Industries</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57591</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57592</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57593</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57594</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57595</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the methodology and approach the firm would take  in undertaking this work</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57596</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>