<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234861</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-17T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-02T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1234861 - Monitoring, Evaluation, and Implementation Support of Education Programs in Myanmar

Assignment Countries:
  - Myanmar

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The Ministry of Education (MoE) in Myanmar is expanding education funding and programs. The World Bank (WB) and the Australian embassy have been supporting the expansion of government programs since 2013.  In order to complement the MoEs regular monitoring of the programs, the WB provides technical assistance on monitoring and evaluation (M&amp;E) by closely supporting the MoE in the implementation of supported programs and providing external confirmation and feedback on the progress.  This process monitoring so far has collected a wealth of findings and lessons learned, providing valuable inputs to the annual program review, informing MoE's key decisions on expansion and improvement of programs. 

We are looking to recruit consultancy firms to conduct various monitoring, evaluation, and implementation support activities (including process monitoring) of the programs implemented by the MoE with support from the WB and the Australian embassy for the next two school years (2017-18 and 2018-19). The targeted programs include school grants, stipends, teacher mentoring, cluster support, and reading intervention.  New programs could be added at a later date. The geographic coverage vary by programs: the school grant covers all basic education schools and monastic schools in all townships nationwide, the stipend covers selected schools in 55 townships in 2016 (and could be expanded in the future), the teachers mentoring and cluster support program covers 40 townships in 2016 and will be progressively phased in to cover all townships; and the reading intervention will cover one region or state in 2017-18. 

The primary objectives of this consultancy are to (i) carry out M&amp;E to improve the design and procedure of targeted programs and (ii) provide support and share/exchange knowledge with the MoE in implementing and monitoring the programs. Methodological approaches that could be used to collect the M&amp;E data include checklists, desk reviews, focus group discussions, key informant interviews, observations, participation in training and meetings, etc. I mplementation support and knowledge sharing will require working closely with the MoE at various levels, including national (e.g., M&amp;E Working Group members), sub-national (e.g., township), and community (e.g., schools) levels. 

This consultancy will compliment and support the MoEs internal M&amp;E mechanism and some of activities will be conducted jointly (e.g. joint field visits), depending on the objectives and nature of the activities.  It will also compliment other WB activities being implemented in parallel including large-scale quantitative school and households surveys, tailored analysis of existing Myanmar data (e.g. administrative, other surveys, etc.), and rigorous impact evaluations.

To reach these objectives, the firm will be expected to carry out the following activities
(a) Process monitoring/evaluation of the programs, including assessing which procedures proved difficult/problematic and why and making practical and concrete recommendations on how to improve the programs; 
(b) Spot-checks to give external validation on the monitoring and reporting data; 
(c)In-depth and tailored investigation to delve issues identified through preceding monitoring activities, just-in-time evaluation and technical support to respond to emerging issues/demands, and operational research/feasibility study to delve how the programs can be further improved;
(d)Technical support/assistance to the implementers (MoE at different levels) of the programs including with the aim of building their capacity for M&amp;E.

The firm will cover selected townships depending on the specific target program or activitys objectives, so flexibility in moving field staff across states/regions will be essential. The number and location of sample townships will be determined based on the discussions among the consultant firm, the WB and the MoE.  It will be responsible for outputs which will be discussed and agreed with the WB according to the focus and activities.  The outputs will be in forms of (1) finalized instruments; (2) presentation of main findings; (3) raw and processed data/information; and (4) final report/outputs. 

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - School Grants and Stipends Bank Executed

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

The consultancy firm must meet following skill requirements and qualifications:
(1) Demonstrated experience of rolling out social programs (preferably education program) and carrying out M&amp;E activities (including delivery of relevant analysis to highlight lessons and propose recommendations) in Myanmar for at least 2 years. Experience in community mobilization, community targeting, and/or transfer programs is an advantage. 
(2) Full-time presence in Myanmar for at least one year, defined as a physical branch office and the presence of at least one full-time employee in Myanmar.
(3) Assignment of full-time staff  to this task should include, at a minimum, one team leader and 8 officers located in the field (township, village level) with solid (at least 3 years) experience implementing and monitoring programs at grass-root level.

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-02T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234861</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Monitoring, Evaluation, and Implementation Support of Education Programs in Myanmar</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Myanmar</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459222</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234861</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459223</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234861</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017753</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">School Grants and Stipends Bank Executed</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58071</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58072</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58073</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58074</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>