<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234386</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-09T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-23T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1234386 - Ghana - Secured Lending and Credit Enforcement Evaluation

Assignment Countries:
  - Ghana

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Finance &amp; Markets Global Practice

The World Bank Group Finance &amp; Markets Global Practice (F&amp;M GP) delivers tailored development solutions to countries and the global community working with our public and private sector clients. Our commitment is to support the twin goals of eliminating extreme poverty and promoting shared prosperity.

The F&amp;M GP structures and implements comprehensive financial sector solutions that bring together World Bank knowledge, finance loans, credits, guarantees, and risk-management products, and convening services, and IFC advisory and investments in private-sector firms. 

The F&amp;M GP delivers its work to clients through several thematic areas and six regions. This allows for greater efficiency, ensuring quality of technical staff, availability of top global expertise, and an ability to stay on top of latest development and in tune with the Bank Group's overall agenda. Our presence in all six regions enables us to respond to specific country needs, ensuring consistency of approach across regions and a tailored delivery of expertise across the thematic areas. 

Credit infrastructure Global Solutions Group

The Credit Infrastructure Global Solutions Group (GSG) assists client governments and the global community in improving access to credit. We do this primarily through the establishment and strengthening of credit reporting, secured transactions and insolvency &amp; debtor/creditor rights (ICR) systems. We have a special focus where the infrastructure for credit remains a huge obstacle for SMEs. The GSG provides advice to clients helping them reform legal and regulatory frameworks, creating and/or strengthening related institutions, including electronic registries, raising awareness and building capacity as well as monitoring impact. In addition, the GSG leads the setting of international standards in certain areas of credit infrastructure and promotes global expertise. In particular, this GSG carries out the World Bank Group's mandate as the global standard-setter for ICR, as designated by the Financial Stability Board.

Ghana Secured Lending Framework

Ghana secured lending framework focuses on increasing the private sector access to credit in the country by strengthening lenders' rights in movable assets.  This in turn will expand the variety of collateral lenders will accept, promote increased lending to MSMEs, as well as improve risk management through more effective collateral arrangements. This objective will be achieved through a) effective legislative reforms resulting in amendment of the Borrowers and Lenders Act which will enhance rights of creditors in movable assets; b) creation of functioning movable asset registries to enable lenders to effectively file a notice related to their proprietary rights, and c) awareness raising and capacity building activities for both public and private sectors, to increase knowledge among stakeholders about the benefits of well-functioning secured financing systems. 

Credit Enforcement Process

In Ghana, despite the establishment of commercial courts and the collateral registry, there is still a perceived risk around the financial institutions ability to enforce its right as a creditor which limits lending particularly to the Small and Medium Enterprise (SME) segment. In this context, F &amp; M GP is seeking to hire a Legal Firm (Consultant) with strong knowledge of the Ghanaian legal context, the collateral registry regulatory framework, including the Borrowers and Lenders Act and enforcement processes, to undertake an evaluation process that will assess creditors ability to enforce their rights against movable collateral in case of default. The aim of this evaluation exercise is to aid policy development and decision making that will strengthen credit enforcement practices within the financial sector. The legal firm is expected to produce a written report of methodology, findings and recommendations. The legal firm will also maintain regular communication of progress with the members of the F &amp; M Collateral Registry project team and external stakeholders during the performance of duties.


FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET
  - Sub-Saharan Africa Financial Infrastructure

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-23T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234386</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Ghana - Secured Lending and Credit Enforcement Evaluation</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">GH</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Ghana</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458386</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234386</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458387</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234386</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1502</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Sub-Saharan Africa Financial Infrastructure</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57915</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57916</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57917</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57918</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Demonstrate a very good knowledge of the local financial market and legal context, the collateral registry regulatory framework, the Borrowers and Lenders Act and enforcement processes and be able to demonstrate such expertise</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57919</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>