<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234361</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-30T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-31T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>IFC is seeking an expert consultant to lead EDGE Green Building Program implementation in Ghana and one or more other African markets. The position will be based in Accra, Ghana, or Johannesburg, South Africa.  The location will depend upon the consultants preference and IFCs needs.  There will be the need for potentially extensive and frequent national and international travel. 

The EDGE consultant will help launch the EDGE program in Ghana and potentially in Nigeria and/or one or more other markets.  The consultant may also support the implementation of the established EDGE Program in South Africa.  

The EDGE consultant will be expected to evaluate new markets readiness for an EDGE Program, by assessing the current public sector policies and regulations, mapping the key influencers and decision makers in the public and private sector, and assessing the structure and growth rate of the new building market.  

The consultant will help the EDGE technical team calibrate the EDGE software model for Ghana and any other relevant market(s).    

The EDGE consultant will help identify, due diligence, and coach one or more EDGE certification providers.

The consultant will work with national and local governments to ensure EDGE is integrated into incentives and policy planning.  Depending on the interest of the government, the scope of work may expand to include assisting the government to create green building codes on national and local levels. 

As per IFCs policies, the consultant will be able to work for up to 150 days maximum during IFCs fiscal year (July 1  June 30). 

To apply, please send a resume and a cover letter to edgebuildings@gmail.com entitled Consultant  EDGE Implementation Africa.  

Both the resume and the cover letter should clearly explain the candidates fit with the program, address the selection criteria and the candidates ability to execute the duties described. 

Application deadline is 12 midnight on Tuesday, January 31 Eastern Standard Time (Washington DC time zone).</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-31T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234361</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Consultant - EDGE Implementation Africa</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">GH</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Ghana</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">NG</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Nigeria</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458258</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234361</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458259</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234361</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3067</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">GB - Global FMTAAS</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>