<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234746</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-16T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-30T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP


REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST


Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html


ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1234746 - Feasibility Study for Public Service Delegation of Drinking Water Supply (DWS) in Rural Areas

Assignment Countries:
- Tunisia

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The Ministry of Agriculture requested the World Banks assistance to explore the potential feasibility of introducing a public-private partnership (PPP) approach in the management of rural water supply. The government considers PPPs as a way to modernize the operations and management of water schemes and to strengthen the governance of the sub-sector.

Drinking water supply in the rural areas of Tunisia is ensured in part by SONEDE, on the one hand, and by the Directorate General of Rural Engineering and Water Development (DGGREE) (45%) of the Ministry of Agriculture, on the other. The latter plans and constructs drinking water supply systems then entrusts their operation to beneficiary associations called Agricultural Development Group (Groupements de D&#233;veloppement Agricole) or GDAs. There are currently 1,400 drinking water GDAs and approximately 140 mixed DWS and irrigation GDAs in Tunisia.

The arrangements for the management of rural DWS by GDAs do not consistently satisfy beneficiaries. Some GDAs are unable to provide quality service (frequent outages) whereas others provide fully satisfactory services. With the understanding that management arrangements using GDAs cannot be replicated consistently or across all rural areas, the Ministry of Agriculture wishes to provide alternative management arrangements, i.e. private management through Delegation of Public Service Contract (PSD). The Ministry wishes to implement a project to pilot this management arrangement so as to convince both decision-making and political authorities, as well as the beneficiaries themselves, which highlights the importance of the project addressed by these terms of reference.

The Ministry of Agriculture, Hydraulic Resources, and Fisheries of Tunisia requested the World Bank's assistance to conduct this project and mobilize a grant for its funding. The mission relating to the development of the study addressed by these terms of reference is funded by a Private Infrastructure Advisory Facility (PPIAF) grant. The contracting authority for this mission is the World Bank. The beneficiary is DGGREE of the Ministry of Agriculture of Tunisia. 

The purpose of this consultation is to recruit a firm or grouping to conduct a mission of due diligence, feasibility study, and design of a Pilot Project for the private management of rural DWS systems. The assignment will include the following phases and activities:

1.	PHASE I: CARRYING OUT OF DUE DILLIGENCE AND SELECTION OF PILOT SITES

This phase will consist of (i) providing a short description of the rural drinking sector (DWS) in Tunisia; (ii) describing the framework of the management arrangements of rural DWS systems under the public service delegation (PSD) scheme; (iii) reviewing the legal aspects of public service delegation; (iv) reviewing the institutional aspects of public service delegation contracts; (v) reviewing the technical aspects of public service delegation contracts; (vi) reviewing the financial aspects of public service delegation contracts; (viii) carrying out a supply chain analysis (profiling operators and supply chain analysis); (viii) provide recommendations for the public service delegation model; and (ix) select pilot project sites to be managed under the public service delegation contracts.

2.	PHASE II: IDENTIFICATION AND DESIGN OF THE PILOT PROJECT - FORMULATING THE PUBLIC SERVICE DELEGATION (PSD) PILOT PROJECT

Under this phase, the consultant will: (i) draw up a description of pilot sites; (ii) conduct consultations with stakeholders in the pilot sites; (iii) assess the current demand and supply; (iii) assess the technical aspects of the project; (iv) review the institutional and organizational aspects and propose adjustments and recommendations; (v) conduct an assessment of the financial aspects; (vi) carry out an environmental and social assessment; (vi) conduct a detailed review of the legal framework;(vii) design the PSD model for the pilot project; (viii) develop a financial model and provide contract costs and determine impact on tariffs; (ix) conduct a value-for-money analysis; and (x) formulize all the arrangement through the drafting of preparation of contract plan and the provision of a timeframe to implement various actions.

3.	PHASE III: INFORMATION WORKSHOP - ORGANIZE AND CONDUCT A ONE-DAY INFORMATON WORKSHOP TO PRESENT THE PILOT PROJECT

Following the preparation of the final version of the "Phase II Pilot Project" report, a one-day information workshop will be organized to present the Pilot Project. The costs associated with the workshop will be borne by the Consulting Engineer. For the purpose of calculating costs in the bids, it is expected to have up to 100 people attending the workshop.

Detailed the Terms of Reference are provided for all activities under each phase.

List of Core Experts Needed:

-	Project Team Leader: An expert in concession and/or PSD contract with extensive experience (at least 5 projects and 10 years of experience) in drinking water systems, including small systems.
-	One or two Legal Expert(s) with good international knowledge in PSD and/or concession contracts (at least 5 projects in PSD and/or concession contracts and 10 years of experience) and good knowledge of the Tunisian legislation (at least 2 projects in PSD and/or concession contracts and 10 years of experience). In case the two qualifications cannot be provided by a single expert, one Legal Expert may be offered for each of them.
-	One Engineer with experience in drinking water supply systems, particularly in rural areas (at least 5 projects in PSD and/or concession contracts and 5 years of experience).
-	One Financial Expert with experience in developing financial models for water operators, preferably with small systems (at least 5 projects and 10 years of experience).
-	One Socio-economist experienced in the field of water drinking water supply systems with at least five years of experience and three social analysis projects in these systems.
Complementary work may be considered further to this mission for repeating or scaling up the approach. This possible additional work is not included in the lump sum to be paid for this study. 

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - PPIAF: COUNTRY SPECIFIC ACTIVITIES
  - TUNISIA : Support for PPPs in Rural Water Supply and Irrigation

ELIGIBILITY

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-30T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234746</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Feasibility Study for Public Service Delegation of Drinking Water Supply (DWS) in Rural Areas</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Tunisia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458974</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234746</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458975</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234746</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A4208</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TUNISIA : Support for PPPs in Rural Water Supply and Irrigation</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58021</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58022</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58023</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58024</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>