<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234202</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-04T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-11T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE INTERNATIONAL FINANCE CORPORATION

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1234202 - Legal Consultant_Group Captive Power

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Mahindra World City Developers Ltd desires to introduce private sector participation to promote a Group Captive Power solution wherein participating tenants (Tenant Companies) of the Mahindra World City (MWC) in Chennai will benefit from the advantages of collaborative procurement of sustainable power and other facilities/solutions due to aggregation of demand.

Scope of work:

To assist in this project, IFC is hiring a Technical Consultant (experts in the field of renewable power) and a Legal Consultant. The Legal Consultant will provide assistance to IFC in all legal aspects of the Project, including detailed legal review of institutional and regulatory framework pertaining to the power/ renewable sector, making recommendations based on the relevant existing and draft regulations, highlight risk areas, assess and recommend courses for risk mitigation, assisting IFC in transaction structuring, preparing and reviewing tender documents, drafting the Power Purchase Agreement and other agreements, and in conducting a transparent bidding process.  

The Legal Consultant is required to prepare a legal due diligence Report identifying legal and regulatory issues and risks and suggest international best practices that could be incorporated in the proposed structure to address stakeholder, financing and risk issues as well as prepare the necessary transaction/ bidding documents.   For the assignment, IFC envisages a two-phased approach  Phase I  Due Diligence and Preparation of Transaction Structure and Phase II  Competitive procurement which involves signing of the Power Purchase Agreement and formation of the legal entity (SPV); the assignment will proceed to Phase II subject to the acceptance (by IFC and the Legal Consultant) of the proposed transaction structure, and sufficient investor/stakeholder interest. 

The terms of reference for the Legal Consultant for the proposed Project are given below: 
1. Phase I: Due Diligence and Preparation of Transaction Structure (Details in the attached TOR)
2. Phase II: Competitive procurement (Details in the attached TOR)

The transition between Phase I and Phase II will involve consultations with the technical consultant, the SEZ Landlord and the prospective SPV members on, inter-alia, the following aspects: 

Legal aspects of the selected transaction structure and;  
Legal  framework for conducting the bidding process  
The Regulatory environment including existing and draft legislation  

During this consultation phase, the Consultants are expected to assist IFC in responding to any queries from the prospective tenants and other stakeholders. 

ELIGIBILITY

The Consultant team will include, inter alia, the following specialists:  
Legal Team Leader  with at least 10 years of professional experience in advising on Renewable Power and Group Captive transactions in the Power sector. Experience on structuring contracts in the renewables sector is mandatory. Should hold a law degree from a reputable institution and should have substantive experience of working on assignments related to advising private/public sector entities on structuring and implementing multi-stakeholder power purchase transactions, including both legal due diligence and drafting of project agreements.  Experience in developing countries is preferable, with strong focus on India, and knowledge of Indian power sector regulatory framework.   Legal Expert  with at least 5 years of professional legal experience in advising on renewable power purchase transactions in India, preferably in the renewable energy sector. Should hold a law degree from a reputable institution and should have experience of working on sell-side transaction advisory assignments.

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-11T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234202</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Legal Consultant_Group Captive Power</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">457744</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234202</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">457745</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234202</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF019001</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">EU India Cooperation on Clean Technologies and Energy Effeciencies for Eco-Cities Trust Fund</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57701</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57704</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57702</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57703</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>