<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234200</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2016-12-29T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-16T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Dept.\Unit: 	Services (Health, Education, Retail and Property)
Location:	Johannesburg, South Africa
Term: 		Short Term Consultant (150 working days per year)
Contact: 	Natalia Donde (Investment Officer, Services SSA): ndonde@ifc.org 

Background
The IFC Services team is seeking to undertake a detailed analysis of the healthcare, education, retail and property (Services) sectors in South Africa with the goal of identifying opportunities where IFC can contribute to the sustainable development of these sectors. 

The team is looking to recruit a short term consultant, based in Johannesburg, to support these efforts on the business development, investment processing and portfolio management side. 

Role
1.	Research and analyze the Services sectors and private companies in these sectors in South Africa.
a.	Research will include desktop research as well as meetings with market participants.
b.	Research should identify market dynamics (size, growth, competitive landscape, regulation etc.), key players and the financing needs of the private sector (including current sources of finance and unmet needs). 
2.	Support the team lead in processing deals including conducting initial due diligence, presenting opportunities to the investment committee for early approval, preparing and negotiating mandate letters, conducting due diligence, preparing financial models, investment memos and board papers, managing the associated legal documentation and managing portfolio investments. 
3.	In addition to these core responsibilities, the consultant will provide ad hoc support as required to the investment team in other tasks related to business development and investment processing. 
4.	The expected duration of the consultancy is 150 days.

The consultant will be based in Johannesburg and will report to the relevant business development leads for South Africa as well as the Services Manager in SSA.

Deliverables
Key deliverables will be:
1.	A mapping and consistent monitoring of each market, covering a) market dynamics, b) key market players, c) list of potential IFC clients, including relevant company information and financing needs.
2.	Participating in and supporting a) business development activities with potential clients, b) investment processing activities within the Services sectors, c) portfolio management activities for IFC investee companies within the Services sectors. 

Experience, qualifications and skills
1.	Undergraduate degree from a reputable institution. MBA preferred. 
2.	Analytical aptitude and appetite as demonstrated by relevant credentials and achievements. 
3.	At least two years of experience in a reputable financial institution. Investment banking and/or relevant commercial banking experience with an international institution preferred. 
4.	Proactive approach and leadership skills.
5.	Excellent analytical, writing and critical thinking skills.
6.	Relevant sector knowledge would be preferred. 

Please submit your cover letter and resume by 11:59PM on January 16th, 2017, South Africa time.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-16T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234200</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Short Term Consultant - Consumer Services, South Africa</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">ZA</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">South Africa</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">457732</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234200</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>