<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234476</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-12T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-26T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1234476 - 2018 Off Grid Solar Market Trends Report - the biennial  Lighting Global/GOGLA franchise report of market data and trends for the sector

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
The biennial Lighting Global/ GOGLA Market Trends Report has become the report of record for the off-grid solar industry over the last 8 years. The 2018 report, the fourth in the biennial series, is to present recent market data and trends information for investors, industry members, policy-makers, and other stakeholders in the sector.  It should distill sales and impact data provided by Lighting Global that track country/region/global results for Lighting Global Quality Verified and other branded solar devices from pico solar to solar home systems.  The consultant would be expected to complement that data with other research and sources to provide insights about key market trends that will inform the future of the sector, including market share of unbranded, generic products. Sales, distribution, technical, and business model innovations, investments into the sector, expanded services including productive uses, increased interventions by donors and other drivers should be covered to deepen understanding among market players. The work will be undertaken as a collaboration between the chosen Contractor with the Lighting Global/World Bank Group program and the Global Off-Grid Lighting Association (GOGLA). 
Key Details include:
	The comprehensive state of the market report represents the next phase update of the 2010 Solar Lighting for the Base of the Pyramid Report,  2012 Market Trends Report and the 2016 Solar Off Grid Market Trends Report.  It will expand on key trends that are shaping the market at present and set forth projections of where the market would be expected to go under several distinct scenarios.   
  	The Consultant would present the findings at the 5th International Solar Off-Grid Solar Forum and Exhibition. This is planned to take place 20-24 January 2018, in Hong Kong
The Report will cover:
1.	Deepening the broader understanding of the markets stage of development and key factors driving its future. This will be undertaken by profiling distinct geographic markets globally which provide characteristically different examples reflecting markets at different stages of development.  This is intended to heighten understanding that there is no single global market, nor is the pathway to market development necessarily singular. Consultant to suggest focus markets, in consultation with LG and GOGLA availability of information being one of the factors. 
a)	The customer:
	Segmentation of the market for currently unserved and under-served customers: assess for various categories of electricity access solutions (from solar lanterns to grid) which % of un-/underserved customers would/would not be able to afford the propositions currently available in the market; and would/would not be able to be reached with current business models. 
	For each solution category, identify the most important factors determining what limits the group of people who can afford and can be reached
	Indicate for which customer segments, with roughly which market shares, different access solutions could be competing with each other. Indicate to what extent this is currently already the case.
	Highlight geographic differences in customer segments
	

b)	Business models and distribution channels
	Propose a logical grouping of prevalent business models and distribution channels for various solution categories from solar lanterns to large solar home systems. Describe key characteristics and actors within the various groups of models/chains. Provide estimates of number and size of businesses represented in each model (consider providing examples)
	Assess the relative relevance of various models and channels for separate market segments, based on current market share and potential growth in market share. Indicate main differences between regions/countries.
	For leading models (e.g. 2-3 per product segment), describe the main challenges and main drivers for growth/scaling within that model. Describe main sources of finance and the degree to which access to finance is restraining growth. Describe key developments and trends within the segment, and the internal and external market dynamics influencing them. Describe how robust success stories within leading models have proven to be thus far.

c)	The enabling environment
	 	Describe and assess actual and foreseen government measures to promote off-grid solutions. Describe how regulation of the off-grid segment has changed in recent years, and to what effect (good and bad).
	Provide views of various stakeholders on relevance, effectiveness and impact of government policy, and gaps with perceived regulation needs. 
	Describe presence, roles and relevance of sector facilitators (donor funded programs; industry representations; specialized service providers etc). Describe impact (incl perceived/expected; both positive and negative) of their contributions on market.
	Describe presence, role and relevance of public sector funding (state subsidies, donors, MDBs, DFIs etc) for energy access; describe impact (incl perceived/expected; both positive and negative) on the market. 
	Assess costs/benefits of public funding and subsidies for energy access with other possible measures, notably VAT/duties exemptions and quality control measures. 
2.	Overview: provide global updates on current state of the market. Identify remarkable developments and trends. 
a)	Sales and turnover per product segment. Build on LG/GOGLA data by expanding with estimates for non-reported sales. Compare sales developments with other electricity access solutions. Compare with past projections from e.g. leading energy scenarios (IEA and others) and from off-grid market analysis, and with total (addressable) market for unserved and underserved customers. 
b)	Market concentration, branding, and barriers to entrance. Assess developments with regards to numbers of players (manufacturers/distributors) in the market in various segments. Assess trends in market concentration in various segments
c)	Technology  update  developments in 1) off-grid solar products 2) DC appliances; 3) technology supporting distribution of off-grid solar products. What are the developments with regards to e.g. product costs; product performance; added functionality; product lifetime; standardization; serviceability and reparability; end-of-life treatment and recycling. Review this not only for leading branded products but also for smaller brands and generic products. 
d)	Finance. 
	Provide trends in financing for off-grid solar at meaningful detail (split out types of funding, commercial vs concessional, market segment, geographical variations etc).
	Assess investment needs from the industry, as well as investment readiness. What share of the industry is bankable, what share is profitable? Has this changed from recent years?
	Analyze the trends. Who is benefitting from better access to finance, who is not (or not yet)? What are the consequences (positive or negative) of recent developments; what are consequences of absence of change in other areas. 
	Collect views from various segments of investors and industry. Identify and analyze main and recurring themes. e.g. perceived focus of equity investors on small group of leading success stories only; perceived overpricing of companies; perceived crowding out of commercial investors by concessional funding; damage of give-away schemes
e)	Impacts: Analyze LG/GOGLAs social impact data. Expand with (conservative) estimates for product sales not counted. 

3.	Outlook: 
Trends from past years, combined with insights about market changing factors and drivers (eg, government policy adoption, consolidation, etc), the study should produce outlooks on the future, under three realistic scenarios, assessing:
a)	Estimated sales and revenue developments for the next [5] years, broken down in product categories and model (cash sales vs service/lease models)
b)	Estimated investment needs and investment provided 
c)	Estimated price trends for equipment and services 
d)	Industry profile with regards to number of actors, market concentration and profitability

FUNDING SOURCE 
The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET
  - NIPP - Lighting Global

ELIGIBILITY
Eligibility restrictions apply:
None
INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-26T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234476</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>2018 Off Grid Solar Market Trends Report - the biennial  Lighting Global/GOGLA franchise report of market data and trends for the sector</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458629</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234476</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">52</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458630</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234476</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A0699</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">48</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">NIPP - Lighting Global</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57995</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information that staff that will lead the assignment have directly relevant experience in the field of assignment and provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57954</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm; in particular: capabilities in field-based primary research (ideally off-grid Asia and Africa); highlight any capabilities in Africa/Asia sector based reviews of consumers, business models, distribution channels; capabilities in analyzing finance for both rural consumers and for a sector in Africa and/or Asia and analyzing trends for these; any capabilities in reviewing renewable energy technologies and related trends</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57955</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business, which should be in the field of research, management or strategic consulting, advisory, academia and confirm a minimum of 4 years in business</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>