<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234362</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-16T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-30T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Pacific Islands Regional Airport Performance Based Maintenance Contract

The World Bank and other donors have provided US$ 211 million in financing (US$ 191 million IDA) to Kiribati, Samoa, Tonga, Tuvalu and Vanuatu under the regional Pacific Aviation Investment Program (PAIP).  PAIP is providing major upgrades to the infrastructure of international airports in participating countries including airfield pavements, terminals, navigation aids, airfield ground lighting, rescue fire vehicles and communications and surveillance equipment. It is also supporting improved aviation safety and security oversight by strengthening national regulatory bodies. Aviation is the key to on-going economic and social connectivity throughout the region and the continued safe and secure operations of aviation is critical to each of the participating States reputation and economic development. 

The on-going sustainability of the investments has been a concern from the onset of PAIP. To that end, the participating countries have introduced a Safety and Security Levy of AU$ 5 equivalent for departing international passengers which will be used to fund regulatory oversight, as well as ongoing maintenance of infrastructure, training, and other operational needs.

However, the capacity of the individual countries to maintain the infrastructureeven with sufficient fundingis, in many cases, largely constrained by local expertise and not fully embedded in operating practices. Particularly for smaller countries like Kiribati and Tuvalu there is very limited human capacity to have available the range of necessary skills. This lack of maintenance capabilities have had major negative consequences with international jet flights cancelled in Kiribati and Vanuatu, leading to major disruptions. This is particularly critical for countries that are highly tourism dependent such as Tonga, Vanuatu and Samoa.

Currently, the countries are generally taking a very reactive approach to maintenance.  This is defined as a run-to-failure strategy where assets are operated until they fail and are then rehabilitated.  This can and does lead to slow and expensive repairs due to the remoteness of locations and the difficulty in stocking parts and accessing the required expertise when critical assets do fail. While some countries have contracts in place with outside maintenance contractors (Tuvalu, Tonga, Vanuatu), they are generally in place to provide access to specialist support when assets fail or when annual calibration surveys are required.  Also some of the maintenance contracts have been established with a narrow focus to support new infrastructure or equipment upgrades and thus dont provide holistic support to critical infrastructure outside the scope of the initial capital upgrade programs.

A recent review of different vehicles to support ongoing maintenance of critical aviation assets in Pacific Island States (PICs) recommended that under PAIP a regional maintenance contract be tendered for a single provider to support and develop government and airport authorities in taking responsibility for aviation infrastructure maintenance. This would see the company: (i) build an asset inventory; (ii) monitor asset condition; (iii) undertake corrective and preventative maintenance programs; (iv) maintain an inventory of spares; (v) undertake six-monthly inspections; (vi) provide post-disaster support; and, (vii) provide remote support. It is anticipated that a performance based contract, with appropriately tailored key operational and maintenance performance indicators, would be tendered for a potential period of 5 years, with 3-year extension, all in conjunction with each States operator. At the same time, the contractor would work to build appropriate capacity within the client countries to improve the maintenance culture and capabilities.

With funding from the Public-Private Infrastructure Facility (PPIAF), the World Bank is seeking a Consultant to prepare and execute a tender for the Regional Airport Performance Based Infrastructure Maintenance Contract (RAPBIMC).  This would build upon the work done to date to prepare an appropriate tender documentincluding performance assessment measuresand then to provide support through the tender stage. During the tender execution, the consultant will answer any technical questions that may arise during the tendering. The tendering itself would be done by the bank/client. As part of this process, the consultant will provide capacity building to the participating countries so that they are in a position to manage and effectively support implementation.

Expressions of interest are now sought for a consultant to provide these services. The budget is US$ 100,000. The expressions of interest should be limited to 10 pages and should detail:

   The consultants understanding of the assignmentin particular familiarity with the PAIP country challenges
   Relevant experience
   Summary of key staff</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-30T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234362</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Pacific Islands Regional Airport Performance Based Maintenance Contract</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">VU</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Vanuatu</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TV</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Tuvalu</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TO</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Tonga</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">WS</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Samoa</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">KI</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kiribati</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458181</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234362</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57839</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57840</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57841</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57842</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>