<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234241</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-15T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Objective of the assignment

The World Bank Group is seeking a firm to carry out an assessment of selected value chains within manufacturing, services, and agri-business sectors to better understand firm decision-making with regard to suppliers, relationship with clients and labor use, as well as to identify firms opportunities and obstacles for participation in GVCs. 

In case of Vietnam, the survey will cover the following value chains: i) Textile &amp; apparel, and ii) ICT (Information and Communications Technology), with possibility of extension to other value chains.

The scope of the assignment

The assignment will include three major components: i) completion of value chains mapping, and ii) implementation of semi-structured qualitative interviews over a selection of stakeholders, iii) preparation of a report with detailed findings and evaluation of the analyzed value chains. 

The scope of work and tasks for the study includes the following: 

 The consultants will be expected to carry out detailed mapping of the actors in the selected value chains and relation between them. All the stages of a value chain should be covered: input suppliers, processors, producers of intermediate and end products, marketers, brand-manufacturers, distributors, lead firms and global buyers, key equipment and service providers, etc. To capture the participation in the GVCs, it will include companies operating not only within domestic market, but also importers and exporters. The specificities of a value chain may require inclusion not only of formal but also informal firms.
 The consultant will be applying qualitative survey instrument, including combination of semi-structured interviews, focus groups, and other forms of conversation with: i) business owners and managers of the firms in the selected value chains, identified in the mapping, ii) other key stakeholders in the value chain including government agencies, business associations, finance providers (e.g. venture capital and private equity firms), management consulting firms, representatives of special economic zones, NGOs, certification and compliance bodies, sector standard-setting bodies and other related institutions. The interviews will be conducted predominantly face-to-face, and if necessary complemented by telephone interviews.
 The World Bank will provide the qualitative instrument to be administered. It will cover topics on: firm dynamics; analyzing costs, productivity, sourcing and sales strategies; determining the barriers to competitiveness, value chain deepening, and job creation at each stage of value chain; innovation capacity; compliance with industry standards; business environment and industry collaboration. The consultant will be responsible for the translation and is expected to contribute to adapting the questionnaire to the local context. 
 The consultant will conduct a pilot prior to the launching of the fieldwork and subsequently, adapt the survey instrument for the official fieldwork if necessary.
 For each interview, the consultant will provide standardized reports written in English, containing a summary from each section of the questionnaire. 
 The consultant will be responsible for preparation of a summary report of the study written in English containing description of the project and its implementation, detailed findings and evaluation of the analyzed value chains.
 The consultant will be responsible for coordination and management of the project in Vietnam, including communication and timely reporting of any relevant issues related to the project to the World Bank team.
 The consultant will need to work closely with the World Bank team in carrying out the mapping, conducting the interviews and preparation of the report.
 The consultant will be responsible for gathering information from the local authorities, business and community leaders and other pertinent stakeholders for the value chain mapping and qualitative interviews as needed.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-15T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234241</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>GLOBAL VALUE CHAINS QUALITATIVE STUDY IN VIETNAM    IMPLEMENTATION FIRM</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">VN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Vietnam</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">457894</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234241</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">457895</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234241</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF014655</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">KCPII - Job Creation, Structural Change, and Economic Development in MENA with Lessons from East Asia</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57771</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Significant experience in implementing complex business studies in Vietnam, in particular qualitative face-to-face business surveys. Please provide at least two examples of the most relevant studies carried out within past 3 years preferably for public institutions, including: topic of study, type and name of the client (if not confidential); if applicable also: gross sample size, number of achieved interviews, number of interviewers, fieldwork length, mode (face-to-face, phone, online).</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57772</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Demonstrated expertise in analytical work with business registers (or other databases containing firm-level information). Expertise in value chains mapping or similar exercise would be an asset. Please describe the experience in generation, using or improving a business register information, indicating: methods of data collection, data source(s) and if applicable, steps undertaken to enhance it.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57773</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Technical capacity to implement the above mentioned activities. Please describe methods used for implementing, monitoring, data processing and analysis.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57774</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Professional and managerial capabilities to implement the above mentioned activities. Please provide information referring to latest available year (2015 or 2016) on: average number of staff, staff turnover within the past year (number of staff who join / left the company within a year), experience and qualifications of key staff (please enclose corresponding CVs), number of staff qualified to conduct the interviews for the study and their experience.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>