<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234464</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-10T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-23T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The objective of the assignment includes:
- Mapping Central African Republic's SMEs working in different sectors such as agriculture, mining, trade, forestry, construction, telecommunications, tourism, crafts or any other potential sector for the development of the Central African economy;
- Establishing the obstacles to SME development and growth; 
- Making concrete recommendations to improve the business and investment climate.

The specific objectives deriving from the general objective are to:

- Mapping SMEs and the sectors in which they operate: for each sector, identify high potential value chains, key players in the value chain and their characteristics in terms of employment, profits, indebtedness and access to financing (including suppliers, producers, transporters, traders, processors, final distributors and other service providers at different levels of the chain). A description of the value chain with links in terms of flows among all key players is expected as a starting point for the analysis;

- Clarifying the institutional, legal and regulatory bases that apply to each sector of SMEs for their creation as well as their operations;

- Identify the barriers / problems faced by SMEs in each sector and propose short, medium and long-term recommendations for improving their situation. This should include a detailed description of the key problems, constraints and opportunities encountered at each link in the identified value chains, including, inter alia, policy and institutional issues that affect value chain performance and trade barriers (tariff and non-tariff, etc.);

- Making specific recommendations to promote the performance of each value chain in order to improve the volume, quality and value of trade;

- Proposing concrete indicators to measure that the recommendations to be implemented in order to improve the business climate and investments for SMEs;

- Identifying possible modalities and sources of funding for SMEs;


- Proposing a list of investment projects identified during this diagnostic study. These projects should be subject to a preliminary analysis to specify the total cost of the project, the capital adequacy of the sponsors at least and the need for financing; And to validate the requirements: operational credibility, bankability, industry experience, mastery of technology and the market.

- Proposing a capacity building plan to mitigate constraints and obstacles identified; and

- Proposing an operational strategy for private sector development and identify support actions that IFC could provide to promote entrepreneurship, taking into account the expectations of the financial sector.

The study will cover the south and west of the territory of the Central African Republic and Region No. 7 (Bangui). It is understood that the south covers Region 1 (Ombella M'poko and Lobaye) and the west covers Region 2 (Manb&#233;r&#233; Kadei, Sangha Mba&#233;r&#233; and Nana Mamb&#233;r&#233;).</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-23T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234464</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Mapping of SMEs in Central African Republic Conflict Affected States in Africa (CASA)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">CF</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Central African Republic</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458383</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234464</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57911</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57914</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57912</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57913</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>