<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234982</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-18T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-25T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP
REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST
Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html
ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW
Assignment Title: 1234982 - Time Release Study for Serbia Encompassing Imports and Exports of Goods in Air and Road Traffic
Assignment Countries:
  - Serbia
ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
The Contractor will assist the Customs Administration of the Republic of Serbia with the implementation of the Time Release Study (TRS).  The TRS measures relevant aspects of the effectiveness of operational procedures that are carried out by the Customs and other border agencies in the standard processing of imports and exports, with the goal to identify possibilities to improve performance and ensure trade facilitation.  The TRS in Serbia will be implemented using the World Customs Organization (WCO) TRS Guide, software and best practices.  The TRS will measure the time taken between the arrival of goods and their release, surveying all types of good exported (customs procedure - C1) and imported (customs procedure - C4) in air and road traffic at selected busiest customs offices.  The TRS will be conducted during the two consecutive weeks, one week per mode of traffic.
The TRS in air traffic will be implemented at the customs office Aerodrom Beograd, and will cover exports and imports of all types of consignments during the period of 7 consecutive days. In road traffic, the TRS will be implemented at 4 customs offices, namely, border crossing points (BCPs), Pre&#154;evo, Horgo&#154;, Batrovci and inland terminal Terminal Beograd and will cover only import consignments of all types of goods entering Serbia at these 3 BCPs and subsequently cleared at Terminal Beograd; as well as all export consignments destined from Terminal Beograd to 3 selected BCPs during the period of 7 consecutive days.  The TRS survey for imports in road traffic must observe the single consignment from the entry until completion of clearance procedure at the inland terminal, and vice versa in case of exports from the selected inland terminal to the selected BCPs.  Consignments cleared using the simplified procedures of in-house clearance at the premises of recipient and sender, as well as clearance based on invoice will also be included in the TRS.  Based on the 2015 data of the Serbian Customs Administration, during the reference period, around 4,670 consignments were imported/exported in air and road traffic. It is reasonable to expect the similar number of consignments/surveys to be observed during the TRS implementation. 

The implementation of the TRS in Serbia will be supported through the World Bank Groups WTO Trade Facilitation Support Program in Europe and Central Asia  (ECA TFSP) aimed at assisting developing countries efforts to align with the WTO Trade Facilitation Agreement (TFA). The objective of ECA TFSP is to develop a quick response capacity to governments from the ECA region requesting expert advisory services in the area of trade facilitation, in support of countries desire to align their rules and regulations, and implementation capacity, with the requirements of the WTO TFA. One of the first TFA measures ECA countries are implementing is the TRS.
The contractor is inter alia expected to perform the following tasks: 

	For each specified customs office where the TRS will be implemented designate 2 (two) persons/interviewers per shift work  of the customs office to assist the customs officers and other border agencies to efficiently implement the TRS, according to the following schedule;
	First week of the TRS implementation: Air Traffic, customs office Aerodrom Beograd, working hours 0:00h -24:00h, 2 persons per shift =&gt; 6 persons per day =&gt; total of 42 men days for air traffic;
	Second week of TRS implementation: Road Traffic  BCPs Pre&#154;evo, Batrovci and Horgo&#154;, working hours 0:00h -24:00h, 2 persons per shift =&gt; 6 persons per day =&gt; 42 men days per week per BCP =&gt; total of 126 men days for all 3 BCPs; as well as customs office Terminal Beograd, working hours 8:00  20:00h, 2 persons per shift =&gt; 4 persons per day =&gt; total of 28 men days for inland terminal.
	Enter all completed TRS survey forms for both air and road traffic into the electronic form using the WCO TRS software. The Customs Administration of the Republic of Serbia will provide facilities, equipment and access to the WCO TRS software for recording surveys into the electronic form to the contractor.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 
SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.
Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.
Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)
NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.
Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-25T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234982</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Time Release Study for Serbia Encompassing Imports and Exports of Goods in Air and Road Traffic</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">YF</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Serbia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459464</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234982</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459465</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234982</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017884</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TFA &#226; Europe and Central Asia (ECA)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58141</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58142</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58143</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58144</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>