<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234385</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-06T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-16T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The World Bank Groups Trade &amp; Competitiveness practice is recruiting a short-term consultant to to provide support to the Ministry of Industry Trade and Cooperatives (MoITC) of the Government of Kenya to organize investment and trade promotion events in India. The promotion events target investors in textile-apparel, leather and agroindustry. The individual/firm must have technical experience in investment promotion and project/event management.   
 Selection Information:
Assignment Title: Promoting Kenya Investment Opportunities to Indian Investors  
Publication Date: 06/01/2017
Expression of Interest Deadline: 16/01/2017
Language of Notice: English
Assignment country: India 
Individual/Firm: The consultant will be a firm 

BACKGROUND
The purpose of this assignment is to support the Ministry of Industry, Trade and Cooperatives (MOITC) of the Government of Kenya to promote and generate investment in textile-apparel, agroindustry and leather sectors. The consultant will work jointly with MOITC and KenInvest to prepare and organise investment promotion activities and follow-up on key investment leads in the target investment sourcing destinations. MOITC has identified the following as key investment sourcing destinations; China, South Korea, India, Bangladesh, Korea, Sri Lanka, Pakistan. 

A significant part of the work will involve market research prior to the investment promotion investments to identify and advise on the appropriate locations for promotion events, profile potential investors and work with MOITC and KenInvest to package a tailored value proposition for the target investors in each country or specific value-chains or market segments. The key objective of the assignment is to provide support to MOITC and KenInvest organising effective investment promotion events for the identified sectors.   

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW
The consultant will be required to: 
a)	Provide advice on suitable locations for investment promotion events in the target countries. 
b)	Review Kenyas value proposition to the investors and suggest revisions based on the location considerations and investment strategic interests. The consultant isolates the key decision factors, analysis the competitiveness of Kenya (now and in future) and help package a strong value proposition for the target investors based on identified competitiveness strengths. The output is tailored investor presentation for each destination. 
c)	Lead generation and Investor profiling- Based on Kenya value proposition develop a list and brief profiles of potential investors in the target countries.  The profiles capture the basic facts about the potential investor; market segment of focus, size of operations and contacts. Output a report with investor profiles 
d)	Structure and organise half day investment promotion workshops- This includes; developing agenda for events, identify key speakers for the events (jointly with partners) , arrange all logistical requirements for organising investment promotion events including but not limited to; identifying and hiring conference facilities, sending invitations to identified potential investors, participants registration, printing of event materials and moderation and coordination of events.  The investment promotion events are envisaged as half day workshops 
e)	Follow-up with investment leads- Work with MOITC and KenInvest to follow-up with individual companies that express interest (by signing a letter of intent) in investing in Kenya. Follow-up progress reports (after 3 months)</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-16T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234385</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Organizing investment and trade promotion events in India to promote investment opportunities in Kenya</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458227</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234385</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458228</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234385</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017824</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Kenya Investment Policy</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57855</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57856</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57857</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57858</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>