<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234767</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-17T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-25T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY INTERNATIONAL FINANCE CORPORATION

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1234767 - Senior Business Consultant

Assignment Countries:
  - India
  - Bangladesh
  - Sri Lanka

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

IFC, a member of the World Bank Group, is the largest global development institution focused on the private sector in emerging markets. Working with 2,000 businesses worldwide, we use our six decades of experience to create opportunity where its needed most. 
The Cross-Cutting Advisory Solutions Department is managing and delivering expertise and programs which are cross-cutting in nature and have application across the Corporation. These include public-private partnership transactions, clean energy and resources efficiency, SME development, corporate finance, gender and multidisciplinary business solutions. The department also provides administrative and financial management support to all advisory units in IFC and in the joint World Bank Group Global Practices.
A.	Scope of Work

The Consultant will provide strategic guidance and implementation support to the Energy and Resource Efficiency Programs for South Asia.  

The consultant will support the project leads in the responsibility and accountability for engaging with clients and delivering a focused E&amp;RE work program with specific focus on the above mentioned areas. The Consultant will support the project leads on client engagement, ensuring quality service delivery and in finding suitable solutions. The work program is focused on India but could have activities in Sri Lanka, Bangladesh and Nepal as well.  
Key activities include but are not limited to:
	Supporting resource efficiency and energy access teams in client engagement including in preparation of proposals and pitch presentations, particularly enhancing the value proposition from a commercial perspective.    

	Identifying options for enhancing IFC value addition to clients beyond technical reports such as customized training, B2B connections, vendor empanelment, financing etc. 

	Identifying target clients/areas for resource efficiency work and help in drafting convincing service proposals. 

	Strategic guidance on deepening the existing client relationships and engagements  as well as exploring 1 or 2 new offerings which offer medium / long term potential for the above functions.  

	Strategically developing relationships with select industries/ associations or other stakeholders as necessary to help project teams deliver development impacts on the ground. 

	Review the off-grid lighting consumer awareness campaign and propose alternative approaches of conducting the ground activities to improve their effectiveness. 

	Engage with IFC client companies on distributor arrangements and explore with them alternative models, identifying suitable partners such as bicycle dealers in rural areas. 

	Work with off-grid companies as required to provide strategic guidance and find solutions for overcoming supply chain constraints.  


ELIGIBILITY
	Bachelors degree in engineering and (or) Masters degree in engineering with at least 15 years of experience in manufacturing Industry or related consultancy fields; deep understanding of processes and manufacturing supply chain aspects. Strong commercial sense for understanding of projects and contracts; Focus on business case for energy / resource efficiency, renewables etc 

	Strong analytical skills, ability to think strategically and rapidly analyze diverse information as well as undertake early stage financial assessment of project opportunities;
	Ability to write and communicate clearly and concisely 
	Self-starter with  Excellent client relationships, presentation skills and negotiation skills;
	Well networked within the professional community in relevant industries;
	Fluency in English is required. Any regional language is a plus. 

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 
SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  
Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.
Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-25T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234767</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Senior Business Consultant</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">BD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Bangladesh</COUNTRY_NAME></_><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">LK</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Sri Lanka</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459013</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234767</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF016372</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SA Climate Change Partnership Program</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459014</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234767</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF011083</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SBA MDTF CE and REff Regional</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459012</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234767</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>