<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1234393</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-06T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-01-15T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The study will be carried out through a combination of face to face interviews, review of reports and literature and survey of selected procuring entities. The scope of work will include: 
a)	Obtain and review available reports and Procurement Guidelines and Regulations that will include Bank Guidelines, Bank PROCYS reports, Government Procurement Regulations, Independent Procurement reviews, procurement audits by government agencies etc;
b)	Conduct interviews with Bank staff, selected government agencies staff, consultants , suppliers and contractors to identify processes that are vulnerable to bottlenecks and/or redundant; 
c)	Explore the value added to efficiency, transparency and economy resultant from adherence to best practices/government/Bank procedures;
d)	Sample transactions within selected government agencies and review actual procurement transactions from planning to delivery and establish average timelines and cost estimate for each process for goods, works and services based on the sampled transactions and Bank reports. The review of the transaction will include upstream decisions on budgeting, inclusion in the annual budget, procurement planning and readiness for implementation;
e)	Depict the actual prevailing process flow, identify actors, their roles and responsibilities and average time taken to complete performance of their roles with a view to capturing the sources of bottlenecks to the efficiency of the processing of procurement. In analyzing the process flow review the governance structure for procurement decision in terms of efficiency.
f)	Draw from the sampled agencies examples of slow/problematic cases for which bottlenecks in procurement have been identified and conduct and in-depth analysis of the sources and causes of the bottlenecks
g)	Carry out a detailed review of each bottleneck , along the different stages of procurement, tackling preparation process, planning, procedures and timeliness of each step, compare actual procedures with what should have been expected under the procurement rules and practices
h)	Explore and recommend ways of addressing process bottlenecks to include training and use of alternative contracting strategies such as frame work agreements
i)	Identify good practices that can be improved, accelerated and or institutionalized.
j)	Formulate a time bound action plan with costs to address identified bottlenecks as well as incentives and/or deregulation , where necessary to increase efficiency of the procurement process
k)	Determine the weakest link in the procurement chain 
l)	Assess the degree to which open competition is used 
m)	Assess the efficiency and integrity of centralized procurement systems (e.g. GPSA framework contracting).
n)	To estimate time it takes to award a contract from initiation by the user department to signing a contract with a bidder.
o)	Assess the quality of staff involved in procurement and quality of training available for public procurement. 
p)	Assess the functionality of the complaints review system; including how many per year, trends and time to resolve.
q)	Determine the extent to which observed weaknesses are attributable to frequent changes of the law and regulations.
r)	Identify and recommend approvals or clearances that do not 
add value or that may be streamlined for efficiency gains, if these are not part of existing law/regulations.
s)	Conduct a one day workshop to include the sampled implementation agencies, Bank , Ministry of Finance and Development, PPD, PPRA, PPAA, PSPTB, GPSA, Development Partners, Civil Society Organizations and other stakeholders,  to present draft report (findings and recommendations) for feedback</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-01-15T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1234393</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Tanzania-Procurement Value Chain Analysis (PVCA)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TZ</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Tanzania</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">458302</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1234393</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57871</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57872</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57873</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">57874</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>