<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1235066</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-20T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-08T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The World Bank Group (WBG) is seeking to pre-qualify Firms to provide software development services in Sub-Saharan Africa under an Indefinite Delivery Agreement. 

The World Bank Group promotes sustainable private sector investment in developing countries as a means to reduce poverty and improve peoples lives. In addition to its investment and lending activities, the WBG executes a major donor-funded program of private sector technical assistance and advisory services. 

The Trade and Competitiveness (T&amp;C) Global Practice provides a range of lending and advisory services to support client governments in improving the business environment for domestic and foreign investors. Support is provided to implement reforms that reduce unnecessary costs and risks faced by firms, strengthen fair competition, and promote investment.  Investment Climate (IC) reform work focuses on several areas including  business registration, business licensing and inspections, construction permitting, investment policy and promotion, transparency in regulatory rulemaking and provision of business-to-government feedback on the quality of public service delivery. Assistance is also available for a range of short-term interventions designed to address specific issues highlighted in the Doing Business indicators. 

In Sub-Saharan Africa, the T&amp;C Global Practice manages technical assistance programs in over 30 countries through a network of hub offices in Dakar, Nairobi and Johannesburg as well as country program coordinators in the local WBG offices.  These are supported by the Investment Climate unit in Washington, DC, which provides technical expertise in a number of areas, including information technology. 

 The types of services will include the following:
a)	New development and pilot implementation of software application(s) to support investment climate reform and improved government-to-business service delivery;
b)	Application maintenance, support and upgrades;
c)	Localization and deployment of existing applications in new clients; 
d)	Testing of completed software applications;

More details on the assignment are contained in the Request for Expression document attached. 

 This Request for Expressions of Interest (REI) is intended will be used to select qualified Firms to participate in a later solicitation for the above-mentioned services that will be issued by the WBG.  

Unnecessarily elaborate brochures or other representations beyond those sufficient to present a complete and effective response to this REI are not desired.  Firms are requested to limit their Expressions of Interest to twenty (20) pages, not including project references.

Only qualified Firms will receive the solicitation. The WBG is not obligated to award a contract on the basis of the responses to this REI document or to otherwise compensate Firms for providing the information requested. The WBG reserves the right to defer or cancel any solicitation without penalty.
 
All Firms determined to be qualified will be invited to submit a response to the solicitation for the services. 
   
The conditions of contract to be used for this IDA shall be the World Banks standard Services Contract as published by the World Bank Group.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>1</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-08T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1235066</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Development, deployment and maintenance of ICT Applications to support Investment Climate Reforms in Sub-Saharan Africa (Phase 2)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459752</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235066</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459753</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235066</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF014088</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Sub-National Reg Reform (Kenya SNICP)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">459754</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235066</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF018851</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Rwanda Investment Climate Program 3</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58172</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.Firm must have permanent offices and technical staff based in Sub-Saharan Africa, although it may be headquartered outside of the region.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58171</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment. Firm must have at least two (2) years experience in designing and implementing information technology projects with similar scope and complexity for government and non-government agencies in the Sub-Saharan Africa region. Firm must provide examples of three projects successfully completed</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58173</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business. Firm must be in business for at least three (3) years providing similar IT services as set out in Annex B</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58174</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must have experience in developing web and mobile applications to support government service delivery, such as informational portals, mechanisms for collecting feedback on service delivery and transactional systems in areas such as business registration, licensing and inspections. Does your firm offer any packaged applications to support G2B or G2C service delivery?</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58191</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must have experience working with the World Bank Group or other bilateral or multilateral development agencies.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58192</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must have experience developing and maintaining applications using PHP frameworks such as Laravel and Symfony as well as open source databases and related development tools.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58193</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must have experience working in more than one language. Note that the WBG requires firms to have English language capabilities, but some projects will involve delivery of software and services in French and Portuguese.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">7</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>