<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1235747</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-12T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Field Data Collection Tools Software Development

Background

The Global Facility for Disaster Reduction and Recovery (GFDRR) is a partnership of the World Bank, United Nations, major donors and recipient countries under the International Strategy for Disaster Reduction (ISDR) system. Launched in September 2006, GFDRR provides technical and financial assistance to help disaster-prone countries decrease their vulnerability and adapt to climate change. GFDRR works closely with UN agencies, client governments, World Bank regional offices, and other partners. To meet the needs of a rapidly changing world, the GFDRR Innovation Lab supports the use of science, technology, and open data in promoting new ideas and the development of original tools to empower decision-makers in vulnerable countries to strengthen their resilience. Recent innovations in the field have enabled better access to disaster and climate risk information and a greater capacity to create, manage, and use this information. 
In 2011, Global Facility for Disaster Reduction and Recovery (GFDRR) launched the Open Data for Resilience Initiative (OpenDRI) to apply the concepts of the global open data movement to the challenges of reducing vulnerability to natural hazards and the impacts of climate change. OpenDRI supports World Bank Regional Disaster Risk Management Teams to build capacity and long-term ownership of open data projects with client countries that are tailored to meet specific needs and goals of stakeholders. OpenDRI engages with client governments in three main areas:
-Sharing data (through open data platforms): To increase public access to risk information, OpenDRI engages in dialogue with governments on the value of open data through working groups, pilot projects that evolve into long-term locally-owned open data projects. OpenDRI provides technical solutions and assistance for the project implementation through GeoNode, a free and open source data sharing platform.
-Collecting data (through community mapping and crowdsourcing): To engage communities in the creation of accurate and timely data about the rapidly evolving urban and rural environments in the place they live, OpenDRI works with governments and local communities to utilize simple, collaborative, crowdsourcing mapping tools such as OpenStreetMap (OSM).
-Using data (through risk visualization and communication): To communicate risk more effectively to decision-makers in planning, preparedness and response activities, OpenDRI works with governments and partners to develop risk communication activities, including development of the InaSAFE software, an OpenDRI Serious Game, and contribution to the Code for Resilience project.
The OpenDRI team, in partnership with international and national agencies, has developed this suite of complementary tools to improve risk information through better access to data. These tools have global developer and user communities, all of whom contribute to the ongoing use and development of the tools all of which are aimed at providing better information for decision makers at all levels to take action to reduce, prepare for, and recover from disaster risks. While engaging with government to leverage the usage of these tools, OpenDRI also strives to create local communities of user and developers involving government agencies, universities, NGOs, and innovation hubs to create sustainable capacity.

Unifying all three areas of OpenDRI engagement within the context of a single large-scale project still presents some challenges due to gaps in the existing open technology suites, and particularly in the integration of field data collection technology. For much of its work, OpenDRI projects engage in open and collaborative data collection with local communities and governments, heavily leveraging the OpenStreetMap (OSM) open data platform. However, field data collection tools for OpenStreetMap have significant limitations to perform planned thematic field data collection, survey management, and the collection of nonpublic information linked to OSM features. For instance, the tools for managing non-public data (household members, health status, tax records) linked to OpenStreetMap data are incomplete and require adopters to build custom scripts and processes for almost every routine transaction. Similarly quality control and data management tools for OpenStreetMap are nascent and unsuited to the scale and needs of institutions. When tools do exist, installation, setup, and customizations are highly technical and difficult, posing challenges to build sustainable local capacity. As a result, building a decision-making system for risk information using OpenStreetMap data requires significant technical skills from the partners or unsustainable setup and maintenance investments by the OpenDRI team. These shortcomings hobble the global mission of OpenDRI, given the overall aim is to build sustainable ecosystems around open data, where multiple government agencies, organizations and communities use and maintain a common set of open data such as OpenStreetMap out of shared interest.

This project will look at resolving two of the key issues:
1) Field data collection through easy-to-use mobile applications that can read and write geospatial data and related attribute directly to OpenStreetMap, as well as enable users to collect other related attributes that may be nonpublic and integrated in local databases and not in OpenStreetMap.
2) Manage surveyed data with a suite of tools for designing and coordinating surveys, importing, reviewing and updating data, and allowing exporting it in standard geospatial formats.

This approach will first enable quick field data collection based on OpenStreetMap features (e.g. buildings), and, in turn allow to seamlessly integrate OpenStreetMap data with locally hosted or non-public datasets. In this way, OpenStreetMap will become viable as a foundational data layer for applications using data for disaster management and complementary functions. As a result, this approach will link multiple, currently disconnected geographic datasets spread across individual government agencies (e.g. household buildings, streets) and incentivize governments to invest in the creation and maintenance of OpenStreetMap data.

The outputs of this consultancy will immediately be used by universities and government partners to better collect and manage data about households, schools, hospitals and generally the built environment as they relate to disaster management. 
As part of the process, the intention is to actively engage other institutions and potential partners to build an open source community and invest collaboratively in open source technology for field data collection. Therefore, while the consultancy needs to deliver the specifications described below for immediate use, the work also needs to enable a larger vision for further co-development as elaborated by the GFDRR and other partners. 

General Use Cases

We anticipate that the software tools developed through this consultancy will be highly flexible and well suited to a variety of use cases involving data collection and creating/updating OpenStreetMap data. In particular, for the purposes of OpenDRI work, we foresee the following short term use cases for the technology:

Large-scale OpenStreetMap data collection by World Bank teams, government agencies and partners to build asset exposure databases, update them and then conduct assessments after disaster events;
Unifying data management for multiple municipal government services (traffic management, social assistance, disaster risk modeling, water services, etc.) using a common OpenStreetMap baseline data layer (.g. Water utilities use the OpenStreetMap roads layer which is actively managed by the transportation department and vice-versa);
Collecting field data for monitoring and evaluating the progress towards completion of development, reconstruction and humanitarian assistance projects;
Support community-led efforts to collect one or many OpenStreetMap features within a local area of interest.

Components

The consultancy is organized in the following three components:

1. Mobile Application: Create an Android mobile application capable of surveying geographic data features easily, repeatedly, in an organized fashion. It should be well-designed to avoid commonly observed sources of user error in other mobile technologies (e.g. confusing form interface design, map orientation error).
2. Data and Survey Management: Create the workflow and infrastructure tools for managing surveyors within an organization and establish a robust server and database backend that can be managed by trained technical staff and that can integrate OpenStreetMap and non-public data.
3. Provide comprehensive documentation that technical staff can use to train themselves and others within the organization.

Potential Software Library Re-use

The selected consultancy should make use of existing tools and libraries wherever deemed relevant. Code, interfaces and tools from one or many of the following open source tools may feature in the final mobile application and backend system (non-comprehensive list in no specific order):

OpenDataKit - https://github.com/opendatakit 
OpenMapKit - https://github.com/AmericanRedCross/openmapkit 
Portable OSM (POSM) - https://github.com/AmericanRedCross/posm 
Macrocosm - https://github.com/developmentseed/macrocosm 
GeoPaparazzi - https://github.com/geopaparazzi 
QField - https://github.com/opengisch/QField 
NextGIS - https://github.com/nextgis/android_gisapp 
Kobo Toolbox - https://github.com/kobotoolbox 
AkvoFlow - https://github.com/akvo/akvo-flow 
GeoODK - https://github.com/GeoODK 
Maps.me - https://github.com/mapsme 
OSM iD - https://github.com/openstreetmap/iD 

In some circumstances, architectural considerations will probably compel us to recreate features from these applications instead of building on them.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-12T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1235747</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Field Data Collection Tools Software Development</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">461035</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235747</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">461036</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235747</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF018476</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">60</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Open Data for Resilience Technology Development&#226; Project</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">461037</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235747</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF013595</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">40</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">SAR Open Data for Resilience (GFDRR: Track II TA Core)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58583</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Adequacy of Project Team Staffing Plan, Technical Qualifications and Experience</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58584</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Proven expertise and experience in the development of mobile applications. Experience with mobile data collection and/or geospatial in a mobile environment is a plus.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58585</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Proven expertise and experience in the development of open-source geospatial software, data processing, and data management tools. Recent experience of contributing to the development of OpenStreetMap tools or other open geospatial tools is a plus.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58586</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Technical Plan and Approach; Proposal Organization, Clarify, Quality</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>