<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1235518</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-09T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-21T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Responsibilities

The survey firm will assist in revising and administering both qualitative and quantitative instruments to a population of Jordanian nationals and Syrian refugees in the country, in three metropolitan areas. 

Timeframe: March  June, 2017.

The firms specific tasks will include:

(a)Work with the World Bank research team to select a random representative sample of local and refugee households in urban for conducting the interviews. This task may include the following steps: 
Assist in identifying relevant areas (these may include zones where both Jordanian nationals and Syrian refugees reside). 
Assist in creating the sample frame, i.e. a household listing, including name and address information, along with other demographic information, for areas that are selected for the survey
Compile this household listing (preferably) from the 2015 Jordan census data, or through a screening questionnaire. 
If for some reason the census data is unavailable, or found inadequate, and it is not possible to create a listing ahead of time, implement an in-field randomization strategy to randomly select a representative sample of households in the field
(b)Assist in developing a set of instruments in English and Arabic, working closely with the research team, including 
(i)A qualitative focus group interview 
(ii)A social norms and beliefs questionnaire to measure gender norms and beliefs related to womens work
(iii)Narratives asking men and women to discuss their thoughts and opinions on related topics
(iv)Implicit association tests;
(c)Pilot all questionnaires in the field before the survey in order to improve the questions, including the language of the questions, and develop clear instructions to be provided to enumerators. It is critical to ensure that the instruments are appropriate to be administered to both men and women in local and possibly refugee populations;
(d)Assist in developing strategies to interview both men and women in the same household, in a culturally appropriate manner, and without offending any members of the household or community;
(e)Provide tablets and create digital versions of the above questionnaires using a suitable programming language, such as ODK, or commercial application, such as SurveyCTO. Test the digital instruments extensively during the field pilot of the survey to remove errors in the software.
(f)Provide server space where the data can be uploaded and made available to the research team on a daily basis;
(g)Provide laptops for the administration of implicit association tests. 
(h)Ensure that the narratives instrument can be audio recorded using tablets;
(i)Prepare survey instrument manuals for all of the above instruments;
(j)Develop a protocol to carefully select the best performing enumerators, including strategies to recruit sufficient number of female enumerators, and careful selection of enumerators who have superior communication skills through interviews and tests;
(k)Develop training manuals and conduct training of enumerators and supervisors along with the research team. This should include a tablet training module, and training on administering the implicit association test;
(l)Take responsibility for purchases of all necessary materials for the training, including flip chart paper, markers, masking tape, notebooks, pencils, sharpeners, erasers, folders;
(m)Take necessary measures for communicating about the survey; inform the administration at the central and decentralized levels as needed;
(n)Develop a detailed plan for field work;
(o)Ensure that all field workers, enumerators and supervisors, receive necessary financial support to carry out their tasks in a timely and efficient manner, including funds to cover transportation and accommodation during field work and remuneration of field workers. 
(p)Ensure that all the necessary equipment and consumables are available to field workers. Ensure tablets and laptops are kept secured in field locations;
(q)Develop a strategy to ensure highest quality in data collection, including visiting only assigned households, administering a back check questionnaire (in some cases), accompaniments with enumerators, and surprise spot checks. Ensure that data from the tablets are uploaded to a secure server every night;
(r)Collect data initially from about 15 focus groups to improve the instruments. Pilot the revised instruments (social norms survey, narratives, implicit association test) in about 50 households  including both paper and digital versions of the instruments. For the main survey, collect data using the finalized instruments (social norms survey, narrative, implicit association test) from a randomly selected list of about 2000 individuals, of men and women from both local and refugee populations; 
(s)We expect the focus groups to take about 30 mins, and the social norms survey, narratives, and implicit association test to take 45 mins altogether for each individual; 
(t)Report progress in survey implementation. Be in constant contact with the research team to report and flag any potential issues, and seek corrective measures, as and when they happen;
(u)Produce a final report documenting in detail all steps described above, highlighting problems encountered and recommend potential solutions for future surveys.
(v)Take all necessary steps to ensure data security, confidentiality, and anonymity, as appropriate, as agreed upon with the World Bank and government partners. Assist with and take all necessary steps related to ethics and human subjects research.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-21T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1235518</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Understanding How Gender Norms in MNA Impact Education and Employment Outcomes</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">JO</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Jordan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">460760</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235518</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">460761</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235518</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3535</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Understanding How Changing Gender Norms Impact Education and Employment Outcomes</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58495</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58496</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58497</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58498</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>