<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1235324</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-26T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-08T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>DESCRIPTION OF ASSIGNMENT:
The World Bank intends to finance the assignment described below under the Spanish Fund for Latin America and the Caribbean (SFLAC) trust fund. The assignment will require working with counterparts from the Government of ArgentinaMinistry of Transport, to carry out the following tasks.

The appointed firm will be in charge of developing, testing, implementing, and monitoring a data collection system to support a smartphone-based travel diary app that traces the users daily movements by automatically recording high-frequency data on time- and GPS-stamped with the sensors embedded in the smartphone.

The services include the following tasks:
1.	Short report of international best practice and limitations of utilizing cell phones &amp; High-Resolution senor data as a replacement for household mobility surveys.
2.	Creating an integrated data collection system, which includes the creation and employment of a smartphone application, cloud-based data storing and a web-based interface for World Bank and Argentine Government to access data. 
3.	Creating a detailed report describing data collection architecture, data flow, and trip inference methodology and code. 
4.	Developing a user manual for any new Smartphone applications and web-based data collection/validation interfaces created.
5.	On-site training on the use and set up of the application, server and data analytics interface. 
6.	Deploy a pilot of the smartphone based application &amp; data collection to a specified number of participants in coordination with the Ministry of Transport and selected local government.  
a.	Develop a methodology to derive individual trips form high resolution data, including trip mode and purpose 
b.	Created a group of consolidated databases with: socio-economic information and feedback survey of participant; raw high-frequency data collected by smartphone application; inferred trips based on raw high-frequency data collected by smartphone application; and database of validated trips
c.	Produce a detailed report with details of mobility patterns for the city
The assignment will be carried out over a period of eight months. 

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The Consultant will be a firm that meets the vendor eligibility requirements, as stipulated by World Bank procurement guidelines. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals). Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Consultants will be selected in accordance with the procedures set out in the current edition of the World Bank's Guidelines: Selection and Use of Consultants by World Bank Group for Operational Purposes, AMS 15.01, November 2011.

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2: https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

Expressions of interest must be submitted in the World Bank Group eConsultant2 system by February 8th, 2016 at 6pm.

Interested consultants may also obtain further information at the address below:
World Bank
Tatiana Peralta Quiros, Transport Economist
1818 H St NW, Washington, DC
Email: tperaltaquiros@worldbank.org
Tel: +1 202 4737060

FUNDING SOURCE(s): TRUST FUND No TF0A3053 Improving public transport, walking and cycling in Argentinas Cities of the Interior: A look at Smart Mobility Solutions</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-08T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1235324</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Using cell phones &amp; High-Resolution sensor data to Understand Individual Travel Patterns in Argentinian cities</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">AR</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Argentina</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">460213</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235324</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">460214</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235324</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3053</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Improving public transport, walking and cycling in Argentina&#226;s Cities of the Interior: A look at Smart Mobility Solutions</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58369</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58370</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58371</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58372</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>