<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1235895</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-27T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-06T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW
Assignment Title: 1235895 - BILINGUAL FOOD SAFETY CONSULTANT - WEST AFRICA(English/French)
Assignment Countries: - (countries have not yet been selected)

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
A Bilingual (English/French) Individual Consultant, based in West Africa, to upgrade IFC clients' food safety management systems in keeping with the requirements of the internationally recognized food safety standards and recommendations made in its Implementation Action Plan. 
The Consultant will provide consulting and technical advice, conduct training, develop documentation and monitor project timelines for the implementation process.
Upon completion of a specific client engagement, a client should be able to issue self-declarations about conformance and/or obtain relevant third party certification from an authorized certification body.

FUNDING SOURCE
The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - Bank Budget
  - Japan TICAD - Global Food Safety Program

ELIGIBILITY
Eligibility restrictions apply:

Technical Skills
- Bachelors degree in Food Science, Microbiology, Food Engineering or related field.
- A minimum of 10 years experience working on quality related matters of one or more companies in the food business. 
- Extensive knowledge and experience working with internationally recognized food safety standards with food processing companies (ISO22000, FSSC 22000, BRC, SQF, and Global G.A.P. preferred).
- Strong knowledge in GMPs, HACCP, ISO 22000, FSSC 22000, SQF, BRC, GLOBAL G.A.P. and relevant government regulations. 
- Proven experience on food safety issues  specifically, conducting gap assessments and implementing internationally recognized food safety standards.
- Strong record and work experience in Africa in food processing and agribusiness networks. 

Soft Skills
- Strong interpersonal and communication skills (written and verbal), including with senior management.
- Demonstrated project management, coordination and operational experience, and attention to detail.
- Ability to travel at short notice and work under pressure in difficult and remote locations. 
- Strong organizational and time management skills.
- Ability to adapt and be flexible; and to demonstrate the ability to work independently and within a multi-disciplinary and multi-cultural team.
- Strong proficiency in MS Office (Word, Excel, Outlook and Power Point) and scheme standard databases.
- Excellent spoken and written proficiency in both English and French languages. 
- The Consultant is expected to be based in West Africa.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.). 
The Consultant should provide at least 3 references from companies where implementation of Food Safety Management Systems (FSMS) as required above were conducted.
Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-06T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1235895</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>BILINGUAL FOOD SAFETY CONSULTANT - WEST AFRICA (English/French)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">461367</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235895</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">461368</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235895</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3012</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Japan TICAD - Global Food Safety Program</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>