<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1235954</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-07T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-19T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The Independent Evaluation Office of the Global Environment Facility is requesting Expressions of Interest from individual consultants for the Combatting Illegal Wildlife Trade as the part of Biodiversity Focal Area Study.

Previous studies on the GEF Biodiversity Focal Area have looked at benefit generation, biodiversity loss, and impacts including a comprehensive assessment on the effect of PAs and PA systems (Objective 1 of GEF-6 BD strategy). Recently, the GEF IEO undertook a Value for Money (VFM) analysis to assess the efficiency of GEF investments and technical support to biodiversity projects. Drawing on previous studies and evaluations, this current evaluation aims to assess three evolving dimensions of the GEFs Biodiversity Strategy, that are yet to be independently evaluated. These three areas are:  
	Biodiversity mainstreaming 
	Nagoya Protocol and, 
	Combatting Illegal Wildlife Trade

The studies on Biodiversity mainstreaming and the Nagoya Protocol components of the Biodiversity Focal Area study will be commissioned through separate consultancies.


Reduce Threats to Globally Significant Biodiversity.  Hunting, poaching, illegal trade in wildlife and wildlife parts is one of the major threats to species and biodiversity. The value of illegal trade has been estimated at between $5 and $20 billion per year, making wildlife crime the fourth most lucrative illegal business after narcotics, human trafficking and weapons. As per the GEF-6 BD Strategy GEF-supported interventions to reduce poaching and illegal wildlife trade aim to: 
a) Strengthening national legislation, institutions, and law enforcement to reduce poaching;
(b) Strengthening science-based wildlife monitoring, education and awareness; and;
(c) Reducing demand for illegal wildlife products.

Combatting Illegal Wildlife Trade: GEFs flagship program known as Global Partnership on Wildlife Conservation and Crime Prevention for Sustainable Development was launched in 2015 to stop poaching, trafficking and demand for wildlife and wildlife products illegally traded between Africa and Asia. With a $90 million grant from the GEF and an additional $513 million in co-financing the program will work in eight African and two Asian countries .

Most programs and projects for combatting Illegal Wildlife Trade are in the  implementation stage, therefore the purpose of this current study is to undertake a quality at entry review to assess the relevance, ex-ante quality of monitoring and evaluation and the design aspects of these projects. Combatting Illegal Wildlife Trade component of the  Biodiversity Focal Area  study will assess:
a.	Relevance of the component for combatting illegal wildlife trade and reducing threat to biodiversity
b.	Relevance of the component to GEFs BDFA strategy

This study will comprise of a portfolio review of approximately 80 projects to assess the status of GEF support to combat illegal wildlife trade and to identify trends in investment in this sector by geographic area (demand countries, source countries and transit states), and by GEF partners and implementing agencies since GEF 5. It will formatively assess the amount of commitment/co-financing to different interventions that include policy and legislation, law enforcement, effort to protect threatened species and their habitats, protected area (PA) management and capacity building, alternative livelihoods for local communities, and awareness generation.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-19T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1235954</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Biodiversity Focal Area - Combatting Illegal Wildlife Trade Study</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">461441</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235954</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>