<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1235598</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-01-30T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-14T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Objective of the assignment

The World Bank Group is seeking a firm to carry out an assessment of selected value chains within manufacturing, services, and agri-business sectors to better understand firm decision-making with regard to suppliers, relationship with clients and labor use, as well as to identify firms opportunities and obstacles for participation in GVCs. 

In case of Ethiopia, the survey will cover the following value chains: i) Textile &amp; apparel, and ii) ICT (Information and Communications Technology), with possibility of extension to other value chains.

The scope of the assignment

The assignment will include two major components: i) generation of a suitable sampling frame, in particular capturing firms which likely participate in GVCs; and ii) surveying a representative sample of enterprises using a standardized survey instrument. 

The scope of work and tasks for the study includes the following: 

 The overall mapping of enterprises into value chains and sampling strategy will be designed by the World Bank team. If needed, the consultant will be expected to enhance the mapping and sampling strategy, and adopt it to the local circumstances. To properly capture the firms that likely participate in GVCs, and determine the firms eligibility for the survey, a screener questionnaire over the phone might be used before the face-to-face interviews.

 The World Bank team will indicate the business characteristics of firms which will be included in each value chain. The consultant will be responsible for creation of a database containing enterprises information or enhancement of existing data sources (e.g. obtained from General Statistics Office) for the purpose of the surveys sampling frame. The sampling frame should include: i) companys contact details (name, address, telephone, etc.); ii) standard stratification variables (sector, number of employees, region); iii) other information necessary to identify companies along the value chain and the participation in the GVCs (e.g. importers, exporters, foreign-owned). The survey may also require inclusion not only of formal but also informal firms.

 The consultant will conduct the business survey administered to a representative sample of firms. The interviews will be conducted with business owners and managers, predominantly face-to-face, and if necessary complemented by online questionnaire or telephone interviews. 

 The World Bank will provide the quantitative survey questionnaire to be administered. The survey instrument will cover firm dynamics; analyzing costs, productivity, sourcing and sales strategies; and determining the barriers to competitiveness, value chain deepening, and job creation at each stage of value chain. The consultant will be responsible for the translation and is expected to contribute to adapting the questionnaire to the local context. 

 The consultant will conduct a pilot prior to the launching fieldwork and subsequently, adapt the survey instrument for the official fieldwork if necessary.

 The consultant will be responsible for data processing (data entry, coding, validation and cleaning), and timely delivery of data in csv, STATA or other agreed format. 

 The consultant will be responsible for coordination and management of the project in Ethiopia, including communication and timely reporting of any relevant issues related to the project to the World Bank team.

 The consultant will need to work closely with the World Bank team in carrying out sampling frame generation, sampling strategy, as well as piloting and implementing the survey.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-14T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1235598</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>GLOBAL VALUE CHAINS SURVEY IN ETHIOPIA   IMPLEMENTATION FIRM</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">ET</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Ethiopia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">460778</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235598</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">460779</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1235598</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3830</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">more and better jobs through GVC participation</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58511</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Significant experience in implementing large complex surveys in Ethiopia, in particular quantitative face-to-face business surveys. Please provide at least two examples of the most relevant surveys carried out within past 3 years, preferably for public institutions (please fill in information requested in Annex 1).</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58512</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Technical capacity to implement the above mentioned activities. Please describe the interviewing platforms (CAPI/CATI/CAWI, describe all applicable). Provide information on the number of: i) laptops, tablets or other electronic devices used for CAPI, ii) i) available CATI stations (if applicable) - please fill in information requested in Annex 1.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58513</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Demonstrated expertise in sampling and sampling frame generation. Please describe the experience in generation, using or improving a sampling frame, indicating: methods of data collection, data source(s) and if applicable, steps undertaken to enhance it.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58514</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Professional and managerial capabilities to implement the above mentioned activities. Please provide information referring to latest available year (2015 or 2016) on: i) average number of staff (excluding interviewers) located in Ethiopia, ii) average number of interviewers in Ethiopia (face-to-face, telephone), iii) interviewers turnover (number of staff who join / left the company within a year) in Ethiopia - please fill in information requested in Annex 1.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>