<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1236328</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-12T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-27T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: Selection of Technical Consultant for Grid-Tied Solar PV Projects in Bangladesh

Assignment Countries: Bangladesh

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The power sector in Bangladesh has grown rapidly over the last decade, maximum generation increased from a little over 3,000 MW in 2009 to more than 8,000 MW in 2016. However, supply still lags behind peak demand resulting in demand curtailment particularly in the rural areas. Annual per capita energy consumption in Bangladesh is relatively low at 407 kWh, compared to 1,010 kWh for India, 2,600 kWh for China, and 13,246 kWh for the United States. However, Bangladesh has been successful in increasing access to electricity from less than 50% a decade ago to 76% today, including about 14% from renewable energy.

Considerable challenges, however, remains for ensuring that people connected to the grid get uninterrupted electricity supply. The primary challenge is that Bangladesh's reserves of natural gas, which accounts for about 67% of power generation, are estimated to deplete from 2020 if no new gas reserves are discovered. Considering the depleting gas reserves, the Government of Bangladesh ("GoB") is targeting to reduce its single source dependency on gas and has initiated fuel diversification measures to achieve an efficient mix of gas, oil, coal, and renewable energy as per the Power System Master Plan 2010.

Particularly, on renewable energy, Bangladesh still lags behind in its efforts to tap into potential grid-tied electricity generation despite the tremendous success of its off-grid renewable energy program. Installed renewable energy generation capacity is currently 430 MW, with the 230 MW Kaptai Hydropower project being the only grid-connected renewable energy resource, and the remaining is mostly from off-grid solar homes in rural areas. To increase the generation through renewable energy, GoB has taken a systematic approach by formulation of relevant policies and targets. As per the National Renewable Energy Policy 2008 ("NREP"), generation capacity of 2,000 MW is planned to be added by 2020 from renewable sources. GoB has also set renewable energy development targets for several technologies for each year from 2015 to 2021 ("RE Development Targets"). Furthering the ambitions of NREP, the RE Development Targets call for an additional 3,100 MW of renewable energy capacity to be installed by 2021. Most of the new capacity is planned from solar (1,676 MW, or 54%) and wind (1,370 MW, or 44%). 

Despite the government commitment, there has been no utility-scale solar PV projects delivered in Bangladesh. A number of unsolicited proposals for grid-tied solar totaling around 500 MW were received by the Power Division over the past few years but none of the projects awarded is expected to come in operation anytime soon due to difficulties in obtaining land by the private sector and the inexperience of some of the companies. About 15 MW in solar rooftop PV systems have been installed in the main cities as a result of a government requirement for a certain percentage of lighting loads to come from solar for getting a new grid connection. However, most of these panels were installed to comply with the requirement to get a new grid connection and there were inadequate quality control and monitoring to ensure that quality panels were installed. As a result, most of this capacity produces little or no energy. 

Under such circumstances, IFC is currently in discussion with the Power Division and Power Cell under the Ministry of Power, Energy &amp; Mineral Resources ("MPEMR") to bring private sector investment in solar power generation through, i) ground mounted utility scale solar PV projects across multiple sites in Bangladesh, and ii) grid-tied rooftop solar PV projects across different cities ("Projects"). IFC plans to undertake the feasibility of the above Projects in terms of technical, environmental &amp; social, legal, and financial viability. Depending on the outcome of the feasibility study, IFC may continue to provide transaction advisory services to facilitate selection of private sector partner(s) to develop the Projects on PPP basis, and till the Projects achieves financial closure. 

To assist IFC for this Projects, IFC intends to hire a Technical Consultant to advise IFC on the techno-commercial due diligence and to work in coordination with IFC and its other advisers, dedicating sufficient qualified resources to meet the deliverables and the timetable. The broad scope of the Technical Consultant comprises the following but is not limited to:

1. Conduct site assessment studies including site visits and evaluation of the sites (lands/rooftops) to understand the suitability of the sites to house a solar PV project (ground mounted/rooftop). It will include accessibility of the sites, site characteristics, availability of physical infrastructure &amp; utilities, site layout, space availability, weather conditions, ground conditions etc. Also, suggest grouping of the sites/rooftops in different clusters, based on the suitability;
2. Review existing grid codes, tariff regulations, generation &amp; transmission regulations, transmission and evacuation infrastructures, interconnection arrangements, grid stability and management issues etc.;
3. Conduct technical due diligence on site irradiance, seasonal variation, carry out an indicative energy yield assessment, estimate the expected plant performance ratio, and provide predictions on the plant availability; 
4. Evaluate solar PV technologies and select the appropriate ones for the Projects, provide conceptual layout of the solar PV plant to optimize electricity generation potential, provide indicative equipment and civil infrastructure specification, provide indicative item-wise capex and opex projections, and develop an O&amp;M guideline for the plant; 
5. Determine the metering technology (rooftop only), and identify technical risks and develop mitigation measures etc.;
6. Develop a risk allocation matrix and a project implementation timeline, review the existing commercial environment and provide inputs for financial analysis, develop bid evaluation criteria, and conduct Environmental &amp; Social scoping following IFC Performance Standards; 
7. Provide inputs to the technical specifications and schedules including performance standards during the preparation of transaction documents and marketing documents and assist IFC in bid processing for selection of the private investor including investor consultation, responding to bidders queries, bid evaluation etc.; and
8. Liaise with government authorities and other agencies to get the necessary data for carrying out the assignment, and participate in capacity building programs, if required. 

Detailed Terms of Reference will be provided at the Request for Proposal Stage.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE

The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS

The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals). Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB. Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES

Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-27T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1236328</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Selection of Technical Consultant for Grid-Tied Solar PV Projects in Bangladesh</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">BD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Bangladesh</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462226</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236328</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">5</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462227</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236328</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF094152</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">95</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">CSA PPP FMTAAS</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58801</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on experience in grid connected solar PV projects (both utility scale ground mounted and rooftops) relevant to the assignment. Experience in grid connected solar PV projects globally will be an added advantage.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58802</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key technical staff. Experience in grid connected solar PV projects globally will be an added advantage. Experience of working with Governments would be beneficial.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58803</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical experience and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58804</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business relevant to the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>