<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1236448</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-14T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-25T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1236448 - Technical Consultant (individual) to support the on-going SME Energy Efficiency Finance Project under Eco-Cities India Program

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

IFC/WBG is seeking the services of an individual consultant to support the activities of the SME EE Finance component activities and deliverable, under its EcoCities Program.

The activities to be undertaken should lead to an increased uptake of SME EE financial product(s) being developed for/by partner financial institutions; resulting in an increased number of EE loans being disbursed.

The chosen Consultant is supposed to support the overall Program and help coordinate these activities, by providing his/her technical inputs and experience.


ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:

Masters degree in a relevant field/discipline (e.g., energy, energy and environment, environmental management, environment engineering, economics/Finance) and a minimum 5 years of relevant professional experience;
 At least 4-5 years relevant experience working in the energy efficiency sector;
 Field experience in both assessing project site vulnerabilities/risks, as well as supervising/ inspecting/monitoring Technical Energy Audits during implementation to mitigate and monitor environmental impacts, would be a strong advantage.
 Basic knowledge of project financing alternatives; ability to provide inputs to develop solutions to financing in the environment sector.
 Knowledge and experience in one or more of the following areas would be an advantage but not required: SME Financing, environmental sector policy, or integrated development planning, in various sectors; capacity assessment and institutional strengthening.
 Knowledge of safeguards concepts, especially for environmental impacts, and willingness to master their application.
 Proven ability to work in a team and intercultural environment, with minimal supervision;
 Ability to work under tight deadlines, manage multi-task requirements and a high degree of pro-activity and initiative. Strong research and analytical skills with demonstrated ability to deliver high caliber analytical work will be a distinct advantage.
 Computer skills, such as Word, Excel spreadsheets, PowerPoint, web-based research, Microsoft Outlook, etc.
 Excellent interpersonal and communications skills and proven track record of effective communication, including on difficult issues, and build strong partnerships with clients and colleagues
 Willing to travel as the position may require.
 Experience working with a wide range of stakeholders, NGOs, international organizations, development partners and/or with the government in India will be an advantage;

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-25T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1236448</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Technical Consultant (individual) to support the on-going SME Energy Efficiency Finance Project under Eco-Cities India Program</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462476</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236448</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462477</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236448</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF019001</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">EU India Cooperation on Clean Technologies and Energy Effeciencies for Eco-Cities Trust Fund</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>