<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1236224</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-09T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-23T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>IFC is seeking a highly motivated Communications Consultant for its Manufacturing, Agribusiness and Services Advisory Unit in sub Saharan Africa.  The three sectors are identified as priorities to drive Africas economic growth. 
 
The World Bank estimates that by 2030 agriculture could develop into a US$ 1 trillion industry in Sub-Saharan Africa.  As a member of the World Bank Group, and the worlds largest development organization focused on the private sector, IFC can bring to bear significant resources to help develop modern agribusiness sectors that meet citizens needs and help African firms become globally competitive. IFC invests directly in agribusiness projects in Africa, and works with banks, and other intermediaries to ensure finance also reaches small farmers who need it the most.  IFCs MAS Advisory team supports the development of a modern commercial agribusiness sector by linking producers to local, regional and global markets. MAS Advisory also guides farmers on social and environmental practices, and sustainable value chains.  IFC works closely with companies across Africa to train farmers, ensure quality inputs, invest in critical infrastructure and equipment to reduce post-harvest losses

Objectives/Purpose of Assignment 

Support the MAS Advisory Team to develop  a communications strategy in close coordination with IFCs communications Team 
Produce a series of articles, narratives, PowerPoint pitch books and other marketing materials to showcase impact of IFC projects in agriculture.  
Interview farmers and other beneficiaries of IFC projects in several countries in Africa, develop stories targeting donors, external and internal audiences.  
Develop key program messages and ensure they are consistently conveyed through communication materials.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-23T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1236224</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Communications Consultant</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">KE</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kenya</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462011</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236224</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462012</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236224</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017544</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">EFAM: Firm Aggregation</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>