<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1236384</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-13T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-18T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Terms of Reference  ESROC Community Manager and Knowledge Coordinator, World Bank
The Energy Subsidy Reform Facilitys Knowledge program requires a Short Term Consultant to manage two online Community Platforms and help coordinate various knowledge activities, including global online workshops, regional learning events and webinars).

The Energy Subsidy Reform Facility (ESRF) interacts through an internal community of practice (COP) with World Bank staff across several Global Practice areas (Energy and Extractives, Macroeconomics and Fiscal Management, Poverty, Social Development, Social Protection and Labor, Trade and Competitiveness, Environment, and Governance, and Communications. In addition, an external community of practice (Energy Subsidy Reform Online Community or ESROC) has been established to offer country clients a private online space to discuss with their peers the social and political challenges of reforming energy subsidies.

The consultant will be responsible for the day-to-day management and administration of the ESROC Web Platform, the internal COP website, and the coordination with other knowledge activities. The consultant will also support the ESRF teams effort to extend the global network of practitioners and assist in the preparation of knowledge products and implementation of global initiatives.

Specifically, the STC will be expected to:

a) Manage the day-to-day activity of the Community Web Platform on the Jive Based Collaboration for Development Platform, ensuring that the platform is regularly updated and meets high quality standards.
b) Work with WBG staff and the ESROC team to design, coordinate and implement demand-driven online events such as webinars, and blogs; identify ways to assess the needs and interests of government members of ESROC.
c) Identify in coordination with the communities (internal and external) new topics for webinars and other knowledge events.
d) Work with the ESROC Team to define, track and report metrics and success measures; contribute to reporting to donors.
e) Design, oversee/curate content, keep updated, and manage the intranet website for the internal Community of Practice for energy subsidy reform.
f) Originate and edit/finalize summaries of events that can be posted online and used as marketing pieces for ESROC.
g) Support the ESRF team in organizing and participating in regional and global knowledge events, including drafting text, invitations; marketing the events; and coordinating logistics.
h) Coordinate with CMUs and regional coordinators on global/ regional events.

In more detail, under these heads, the consultant will also be actively engaged in:

 Managing membership of both internal and external platforms: knowing the community members, their needs, and challenges; identifying active government and World Bank members and coaching them to become champions of the communities.
 Community Strategy: designing a strategy, setting annual priorities and developing a calendar of engagement activities based on member feedback and program goals.
 Content production and delivery: based on emerging community strategy; will include planning and organization of community activities/ workshops/ webinars, blogging, uploading materials from past events, and autonomously maintaining activity on the Portal/website by posting news feeds and announcements, and uploading knowledge materials suitable for public view from the internal Community of Practice website onto the Web Portal.
 Platform Management: selecting, designing, and managing content and administrative aspects (signup, approvals, troubleshooting, email outreach, etc.) for the online community spaces. This will serve as the community home base and should reflect the value this community brings to its membership.
 Monitoring, evaluation and reporting: documenting engagements and feeding lessons learned back into products and services; routinely reporting and filing new case studies and lessons learned to the Energy &amp; Extractives Knowledgebase; developing key performance indicators and tracking system, reporting monthly and producing one annual summary report, contributing ideas to improve the engagement strategy.
 Forum management: engaging in the forum for discussion, including posting comments and tracking discussions to monitor when a particular topic has enough comments to form the basis of a small knowledge piece in the Frequently Asked Questions section.
 Expert coordination: encouraging the inputs of experts within and outside the Bank in targeted discussions and occasionally asking them to write a piece on a FAQ or prepare a presentation for a webinar.
 Event organization: identifying, though the fora and through direct communication, topics of high interest to government members and/or internal staff, organizing the timing, program and coordinating with speakers and attendants for webinars on these topics, Following up on webinars by uploading the transcripts/videos, and making sure members know where to find these.
 Collaboration with outside organizations: Liaising with counterparts within the World Bank Group and key donor organizations (IMF, IEA, GSI, GIZ) to encourage their participation and collect their feedback on the web platform.
 Collaboration with the internal CoP: Helping to coordinate with the internal Community of Practice on subsidy reform, possibly by preparing monthly updates on trends in the Community about topics of interest.
 Providing other support as needed: Examples: building capacity and engagement of other core team members, participating in team meetings, providing periodic reports and updates, and being available periodically for staff discussions or to facilitate training to accommodate members in time zones around the world.
Key Qualities and Competencies
 Masters degree or Bachelors degree and at least 2 year of relevant experience.
 Strong writing and editing skills.
 Proven analytical, conceptual, organization, multitasking, and problem-solving skills.
 Knowledge of or experience working in the Energy sector.
 Proven ability to initiate, develop and/or support one or more communities of practice/interest or other type of communities.
 Relevant work experience in the area of online community engagement, communications, knowledge management, marketing, or capacity development
 Proven experience organizing and facilitating participatory events including workshops, presentations, learning sessions, etc.
 Proven member engagement/people management/community engagement skills.
 Ability to build ownership and generate enthusiasm among diverse external and internal stakeholders around new initiatives and programs.
 Ability to creatively engage with south-south knowledge strategies
 Demonstrated ability to work effectively within an authorizing environment that involves multiple stakeholders.
 Excellent task and project management skills, with experience coordinating across units and institutions.
 Familiarity with online communications and basic website development
 Strong work ethic and ability to work independently, Strong organizational skills
 Proven capacity to deliver quality results on time, and demonstrate quality in work products
 Prior experience managing a World Bank Group CoP is a plus
 Language skills are a plus (French, Spanish, Arabic or Russian)
 Knowledge of the World Bank Group and its organization a plus
 Knowledge of the energy field and in particular fossil fuel subsidy reform is a plus

Duration

The consultant should be available to work full time starting in February 2017 and continuing through June 30, 2017. The consultant will report to Sheoli Pargal, Lead Energy Specialist and Thomas Flochel, Economist. Remuneration will be determined based on the qualifications of the selected candidate in accordance with World Bank guidelines. The successful applicant will be remunerated on a time only basis as per the normal procedures of the World Bank.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-18T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1236384</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>ESROC Community Manager and Knowledge Coordinator.</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462350</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236384</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462351</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236384</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1310</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">World: Energy Subsidy Reform Online Community</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>