<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1236345</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-13T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-02-20T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1236345 - JAPAN - APPLICATION OF KITAKYUSHU MODEL TO THE ROLE OF SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT IN ADDRESSING URBAN FLOOD RISK

Assignment Countries:
  - Japan

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

Background of the Research
Kitakyushu Citys experience on environmental management, particularly how the city overcame pollution problems (air pollution, water contamination, etc.) through partnership of the citizens, government and companies is of particular interest for World Bank clients.  The city has been carrying out various projects in over 110 Asian Cities based on the Kitakyushu Model.  The uniqueness of the model is that it is constantly being developed by learning from experiences past applications to different cities (peer to peer learning among Asian cities).  The active involvement of Kitakyushu International Techno-cooperative Association (KITA) has been crucial for the citys success.  While the city has taken various countermeasures to combat environmental pollution since the 1960s, KITAs establishment dates back to 1980, proving the citys long-term commitment to environmental policies and exporting them to other cities.  

The city has abundant experience with working with cities of different economic development stages and is the frontrunner of cities in Japan in terms of knowledge/ technology transfer to developing countries.  Moreover, the city has been selected to work with the OECD Green Cities Programme and has established itself as a major exporter of technical assistance in the environment field, conducting various research and feasibility studies around environmental strategies.  

The key thematic areas of comparative advantage put forward by Kitakyushu for the CPP are: i) Green Growth and ii) Solid Waste Management. Nonetheless, partnership activities will not be limited to these areas and both sides will seek to expand cooperation beyond these areas.

About the Kitakyushu Model and Objectives of the Research
The Kitakyushu Model is a methodology developed in Kitakyushu City, Japan to help with urban master planning. It provides appropriate solutions for environmental challenges to pursue sustainable urban development. The Kitakyushu Model aims to be a methodology that allows cities to easily apply sustainability more broadly and in a holistic fashion, beyond isolated projects and individual advice. Kitakyushu Citys experiences and strategies have been refined over the years to incorporate the real changes and challenges gained through both past success and mistakes. Therefore the methodology is presented in a technically rigorous, but user-friendly framework to realize real urban transformation.

The Kitakyushu Model is composed of: 1) Kitakyushu Story, 2) Sustainability Framework, 3) Waste Management, 4) Energy Management, 5) Water Management, 6) Pollution Management, with a new component for 7) Transport. 

The purpose of this research is to enhance the current model by adding a subsector, assist the global dissemination of the model through Bank channels, and connect the model and application on the ground by liaising and mobilizing technical experts from the city. 

B.	SCOPE OF WORK 
The list of tasks and guidelines presented hereunder in these TOR shall not be considered to be exhaustive.  The specific tasks are as follows: 
About the Additional Subsector

The linkage between solid waste management and disaster risk management, particularly flood events is an area of emerging focus for Bank clients. It includes issues about improper waste treatment leading to river blockage, sludge accumulation, and potentially water-borne diseases following disasters. 

Kitakyushus experience is grounded on the idea that solid waste management and disaster risk management, or more broadly climate change are closely related. Some aspects include, among others: 

1.	Generation of methane gas as a result of open dumping of municipal waste
In developing countries, municipal waste is not recycled and does not undergo intermediate treatment. Most waste is openly dumped, generating massive amounts of methane gas with a greenhouse effect that is 21 times higher than CO2.

2.	Reduction of environmental impacts through resource recycling
By promoting the recycling of iron and nonferrous metals from waste home appliances and end-of-life vehicles, as well as controlling the use of virgin resources, it is possible to save vast amounts of energy consumed in the process of producing virgin resources.

3.	Flooding caused by scattered waste and illegally dumped waste
In developed countries, frequent flooding occurs when storm water cannot be smoothly discharged to rivers during concentrated torrential rains because of scattered waste and illegally dumped waste in drainage canals.

Task 1: Data collection: The Consultant is expected to undertake basic data collection including surveys and key informant interviews with stakeholders as needed. 
Task 2: Write up of additional subsector for the Kitakyushu Model: Based on the data collected, the Consultant is expected to write up a report of approximately 30-40 pages. The output report is expected to be in English. The case study report can be written in English or the initial draft can be in Japanese to be translated into English at a near-final stage. The consultant should include translation fees in the financial proposal if necessary.  

Task 3: Consultation with stakeholders on contents: The contents of the output report should be consulted with relevant stakeholders such as national and municipal governments, private sector etc. to ensure accurate reflection of facts and coherent messaging. Prior to finalization, the output report will be subject to thorough internal screening by the Bank team wherein the consultant is to revise/ update the report based on comments given.

Key Considerations on the Scope of Works 
The consultant should have a thorough understanding of Kitakyushu City, including historical development, legislative and institutional background, past challenges and solutions. This will be an important factor in proposal evaluation. Nonetheless, consultants are expected to have knowledge and experience on relevant global practices as well.  

The Kitakyushu Model is essentially a textbook of actual how-to steps on policy implementation. However, in practice this textbook supported by a rich cloud database of documents, policy tools and analytical data of the citys experience in past 30 years. In order to transform the textbook into practice, requires investment of on-site direct support and commitment by skilled practitioners (coordinators) for customizing and applying to target cities. The city has a pool of retired staff (city officials in Kitakyushu Asian Center for Low Carbon Society, private sector OB/OGs in Kitakyushu International Techno-cooperative Association) which have abundant technical knowledge and interested to seek possible schemes in utilizing them for Banks operational support (both short-term and long-term as possibilities). The consultant is required to provide support in liaising with and mobilizing experts for this purpose linking the Kitakyushu Model to Bank on-going and pipeline operations. 

C.	DELIVERABLES/SPECIFIC OUTPUTS EXPECTED FROM CONSULTANT
The assignment is expected to be completed within by June 30, 2017 after the start of this assignment, including stakeholder consultation.

D.	STAFFING ARRANGEMENTS
The Consultant Team is expected to include highly qualified and experienced professionals. The required key experts and their estimated time for input required to carry out this assignment are given below. The Consultant Team may propose additional technical experts to improve the quality of the output.  
#	Key Specialists	Years of Experience
1	Team Leader/ Urban Development and Environmental Management	 10
2	Urban Development and Environmental Management	 5

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET
  - TDLC - Phase 3

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-02-20T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1236345</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>JAPAN - APPLICATION OF KITAKYUSHU MODEL TO THE ROLE OF SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT IN ADDRESSING URBAN FLOOD RISK</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">JP</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Japan</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462269</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236345</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462270</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236345</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF083027</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TDLC - Phase 3</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58829</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58830</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58831</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58832</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>