<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1236680</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-17T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-06T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1236680 - PMR Costa Rica: Review of the National Carbon Neutrality Plan (NCNP) and reform of its Domestic Carbon Offset Market (DCM)

Assignment Countries:
  - Costa Rica

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The objective of this activity is to provide technical and advisory assistance to the Climate Change Directorate (DCC) at the Ministry of Environment and Energy (MINAE), the PMR-Costa Rica technical team and relevant stakeholders throughout the process of (i) reviewing and updating of the current National Carbon Neutrality Plan (NCNP) and (ii) reforming and strengthening the current (voluntary) Domestic Carbon Market (DCM) as to transition into a transformation-oriented Costa Rican Offset Mechanism (Mecanismo de Compensaci&#243;n de Costa Rica, MCCR). These instruments are intended to stimulate enhanced mitigation action in priority sectors and contribute to Costa Ricas ambitious climate goals set out in its Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) under the Paris Agreement. In the context of Costa Ricas participation in the Partnership for Market Readiness (PMR), the World Bank is contracting consultant services to support the technical team anchored at the Ministry of Environment and Energy (MINAE), currently in charge of carrying out this work.


This assignment will comprise activities/tasks and deliverables along the following specific objectives: 

(1)	Review the current National Carbon Neutrality Plan (NCNP; Programa Pa&#237;s Carbono Neutralidad), and provide advice on technical, institutional and regulatory issues during the redesign process of the NCNP, to broaden its appeal and to align it with the long-term deep decarbonization goal of Costa Rica. 

(2)	Develop detailed technical inputs for draft operational guidelines, rules and modalities for the updated NCNP, including revised certification system (expanding from single-level recognition (C-Neutrality) toward multiple certificate levels (inventory, neutrality)); enhanced GHG reporting program structure and requirements (i.a., program coverage/classification of organizations, emissions quantification methodologies,   guidance on uncertainty and materiality, quality control and assurance procedures); third-party audit/verification system (incl. accreditation scheme for Certified Carbon Experts ("Peritos de Carbono"); others.

(3)	Develop detailed policy options and technical notes to inform decision-making for the strategic transition of the voluntary Domestic Carbon Offset Market (DCM) towards a transformation-oriented Costa Rican Offset Mechanism (MCCR), in alignment with the long-term decarbonization goals of Costa Rica.

(4)	Develop detailed technical inputs for draft operational guidelines, rules and modalities for the reformed MCCR, including, inter alia, guidelines for the selection of priority sectors and technology types for the generation of Costa Rican Offset Units (Unidades Costarricenses de Compensaci&#243;n, UCCs); guidelines for open tenders for scaled-up UCC asset creation (proposals for GHG emissions reductions crediting in transformational mitigation actions in priority sectors); guidelines for the development of methodologies and protocols for the generation of UCCs (for select transformational mitigation actions).
 
(5)	Develop and launch a capacity building program for the Technical Secretariat of the updated NCNP and its reformed MCCR, anchored at the Climate Change Directorate/Ministry of Energy and Environment.

These activities will be led and supervised by the Climate Change Directorate/MINAE, with the support of the PMR-Costa Rica technical team. The assignment is expected to begin in the first quarter of 2017 and shall be planned to be carried out in 9-12 months, subject to further coordination with the client counterparts at MINAE.



FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:

  - PMR Costa Rica (MRP implementation phase grant)

ELIGIBILITY
Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm/consortium involving international and national partners, to ensure the utilization of national analytical capacity and international expertise with design and implementation of GHG reporting programs and carbon offset standards in other jurisdictions. Interested firm/consortium must have the ability to engage with local experts in Costa Rica with demonstrated capacity to undertake the technical aspects of this assignment.

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-06T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1236680</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>PMR Costa Rica: Review of the National Carbon Neutrality Plan (NCNP) and reform of its Domestic Carbon Offset Market (DCM)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">CR</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Costa Rica</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462918</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236680</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462919</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236680</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A2395</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">PMR Costa Rica (MRP implementation phase)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58962</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on relevant expertise and experience of the firm/consortium in the specific field of this assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58964</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm/consortium.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">58965</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>