<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1236442</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-20T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-06T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2, selection number 1236442.
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1236442 - LOCAL SHORT-TERM CONSULTANT (STC)

Assignment Countries:
  - Myanmar

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

IFC is seeking the services of a qualified local Short-Term Consultant (STC) from March 13 to December 31, 2017 to achieve the following objectives:

1.To provide technical support to the design, development and implementation of the IFC advisory program on agribusiness development in Myanmar, with likely sub sectors of interest to include animal proteins/dairy, rice, pulses and grains, forestry and agricultural inputs including seeds and fertilizers. 
2.Provide supervisory support to management of IFCs MAS advisory projects with IFC clients and partners in Myanmar. 

Tasks: Working closely with MAS AS team members, the tasks will include, but not be limited to:

1.Based on an already completed agribusiness concept note and the desire to develop activities at sector and sub sector level that add value and cut across sub sectors, provide insight and advice to support refining areas and partnerships where IFC AS activities will be most impactful. 
2.Provide overall support to the design and development of IFCs MAS advisory services at firm level with IFCs clients and pipeline clients, and at the sector and value chain level; 
3.Provide overall support to the implementation of IFCs MAS advisory projects with IFC clients and/or partners; 
4.Support the relationship management with project stakeholders, clients, partners, beneficiaries, etc.;
5.Coordinating with other IFC teams: advisory colleagues, investment officers, E&amp;S specialists, country officers, communications officers and IBRD colleagues and others.
6.Assist TTL in the preparation of reports and presentations for donors and other stakeholders. This can include sector briefings, background reports, case studies, research projects etc.;
7.Contribute substantively to knowledge management; and perform other tasks as required by TTL.

Interested consulting firms are expected to have: 
Commitment to the World Bank Group and IFC's mission, strategies and values and experience in developing and implementing donor funded projects; 
A Master's degree or equivalent professional qualification in agribusiness and a minimum of 5 years of private sector operational experience in agribusiness or a related industry, or equivalent combination of education and experience;
Demonstrated knowledge of the agriculture sector in Myanmar, key private sector players and public sector agencies. Strong understanding of the development challenges facing the sector.
Experience working on agricultural supply chain issues with private sector clients. Experience engaging in agribusiness supply chain development with governments and other sector stakeholders preferred;
A proven track record in business development, nurturing client relationships and resolving challenging issues;
A demonstrated ability to understand what makes businesses succeed, to develop innovative solutions and to challenge the status quo to build businesses;
Recognized as a team player, collaborator, leader and strategic thinker;
Strong written and verbal communications skills in English, 
Willingness to travel frequently throughout Myanmar, and as required in the Mekong Region. 

Interested candidate should submit their Cover Letter &amp; CV indicating that they are qualified to perform the services, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2, selection number 1236442. (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)
 
NOTES
Only shortlisted candidates will be notified and invited for the interview. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-06T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1236442</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>LOCAL SHORT-TERM CONSULTANT (STC)</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Myanmar</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462466</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236442</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">462467</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1236442</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A4346</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Australia PSW GAFSP AS - EAP</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>