<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237695</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-07T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-20T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>This Request for Expression of Interest is for a Firm Selection. Please log in as a valid Firm User if you wish to express interest in this selection.

Selection Information
Assignment Title :Implementation Partner for E-Waste management in Bhubaneswar city

Language of Notice 
English 
Selection Notice 

Assignment Country 
IN - India 

Funding Sources 
The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment/services under: 
TF019001 - EU India Cooperation on Clean Technologies and Energy Efficiencies for Eco-Cities Trust Fund 

Individual/Firm 
The consultant will be a firm. 

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2 https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

Assignment Description 
SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST 

Objectives
The objectives of the Bhubaneswar Municipal Corporation (BMC) through this project include:
1.	Awareness Generation: Generate awareness among consumers and households regarding e-waste so as to increase collection volumes and responsible waste practices.
2.	Establishing an effective e-waste collection system in the city: With the active participation of the manufacturers of electronic items (which generate e-waste), this network must facilitate responsible e-waste collection from households, businesses and other key points of the product value chain. The collected waste is to be channelized to authorized recyclers and dismantlers.
3.	Identify, develop and establish a sustainable e-waste management ecosystem consisting of stakeholders such as, but not limited to: Collectors, Industry Associations, Manufacturers, Recyclers, Grassroots and implementation organizations, Government, subject matter experts etc. so as to implement a long-term e-waste management platform in the city.
4.	Execute and establish a working model for e-waste management in Bhubaneswar with the aim of incorporating best practices in e-waste management and demonstrating effective implementation of the E-Waste (Management) Rules, 2016

SCOPE OF WORK 

IFC is hiring an Implementation Partner (an agency/Consortium). The Implementation Partner will be responsible for supporting the Client in executing the on-ground design and Implementation of a sustainable e-waste solution which is inclusive of all stakeholders. The Implementation Partner will be based in and will operate from Bhubaneswar throughout the duration of the project.

IMPLEMENTATION ARRANGEMENTS
Consultants and agencies appointed by the IFC will report to the IFC Task Team. All deliverables shall be formally reviewed and approved by this Task Team, in consultation with BMC.
The selected Implementation Partner must be based in and operate from Bhubaneswar. The Implementation Partner will participate in regular consultations with the Bhubaneswar Municipal Corporation and may be required to have ongoing presence at the BMC offices.
The Implementation Partner is advised to and may sub-contract select activities that are beyond its core competency. However, the responsibility for these activities remain with the selected Implementation Partner. The selection and sub-contracting of such activities must be done in consultation with IFC and BMC. 
The Implementation Partner, in consultation with IFC and BMC, may appoint external advisors/consultants to advise and support the project. The selected Implementation Partner must cooperate with any advisor/consultant appointed by the BMC and IFC.

TEAM COMPOSITION
The Implementation Partner must have both the skill and experience necessary to undertake the range of tasks set out in these terms of reference. The candidate should demonstrate that it has experience with waste management, preferably in e-waste. The candidate must also include in its proposal the key team members who will be working on the project as well as tasks/components which it will outsource/sub-contract. Please include in the required proposed Implementation Plan the entity/individual who will be responsible to implement each individual activity mentioned above.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-20T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237695</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Implementation Partner for E-Waste management in Bhubaneswar city</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465368</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237695</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465369</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237695</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF019001</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">EU India Cooperation on Clean Technologies and Energy Effeciencies for Eco-Cities Trust Fund</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59655</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">The proposal submitted by the candidate will be evaluated based on proposals relevance to the Key Activities descried in the Scope of Work above. Therefore, the candidate must submit a Proposed Implementation Plan as part of the proposal. The Proposed Implementation Plan must provide the candidates proposed strategy to address the Key Activities.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59656</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">The candidate must agree to refrain from participation in any activities that pose a conflict of interest during the period of the contract.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59657</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Track record in management of multi-stakeholder projects and implementation. It is preferred that the candidate be able to demonstrate, through the proposal, that his/her organization, is capable of collaborating with relevant local stakeholders</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59658</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Experience of working at a grassroots level and mobilizing communities</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59659</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">The selected Implementation Partner must be based in and operate from Bhubaneswar during the tenure of the project.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>