<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237769</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-08T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-22T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1237769 - Assessment of Fertilizer Regulatory and Value Chain Environment in Myanmar

Assignment Countries:
  - Myanmar

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The World Bank Group (WBG), through its Trade and Competitiveness Global Practice (T&amp;C) in the East Asia and Pacific (EAP) region, executes a range of technical assistance and advisory programs to strengthen the competitiveness of key sectors through improvements in the investment climate, and by working with key public and private sector stakeholders on quality enhancements to improve access to markets. In partnership with the Department for International Development (DFID) of the United Kingdom, the Australian Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade (DFAT), and the Government of Japan, the WBG is supporting the development of the agricultural sector of Myanmar by addressing constraints in the private sector provision of key inputs. One of the target areas of this project is to assist the government to ensure high quality fertilizers in the market with a focus on introducing risk management systems into the governments inspection and quality assurance process.  

Agriculture is a key sector in the Myanmar economy, contributing 38% to the GDP and accounting for more than 60% of the labor force. Despite its important role in the economy, agriculture productivity in Myanmar is low, a key reason why farm profits are amongst the lowest in Asia. Farmer access to and efficient use of high quality fertilizers appropriate to the soils and crops in Myanmar is essential to improved agriculture productivity.  However, a key concern in Myanmar is the uncertain quality of fertilizers . The total number of different fertilizer grades is unknown and at all stakeholder levels (public and private sector and farmers), there is a low level of confidence that fertilizers are of high quality, with bag content consistent with the truth in labelling concept. 

The Fertilizer Law needs to be improved in order to enhance the effectiveness of fertilizer registration and licensing, as well as in risk reduction in fertilizer quality assurance. As a result of deficiencies in the public and private sector systems, there is significant scope for the presence of sub-standard fertilizer products. The government typically inspects fertilizer formulation and quality primarily at the legal entry points by lab samples rather through more targeted field inspections. Thus, identifying where the primary risks occur within the value chain, would support the development of a Risk Based Inspection System in order to increase compliance with existing rules and regulations.

The fertilizer market is growing rapidly, with total use of inorganic fertilizers estimated at 1.2-1.4 million metric tons (mt) in 2015/16. There are 628 registered fertilizer importers in Myanmar (2015). Fertilizer imports, mainly from China and Thailand, account for more than 80% of supply. A number of local private sector companies are engaged in value-added fertilizer processing to achieve tailored fertilizer grades/formulations. And, the government owns (5) and operates (3) ammonia/urea fertilizer factories that supply about 150,000  200,000 mt per year of urea fertilizers for the Myanmar market.  With a market-oriented policy environment, private sector investment in fertilizer supply and marketing is expected to continue to expand rapidly. Down-stream marketing of fertilizers is handled by the private sector. The number of registered distributors and retail/dealers totaled 835 and 3,200 respectively in 2015. The Land Use Department (LUD) reported that 2,071 fertilizer products are registered for sale in the country. It is noteworthy that each individual application for fertilizer import (when approved) results in a registered product. This means that each time an importer is approved to import urea (nitrogen fertilizer) that results in a new registered product.

WBG is seeking to hire a Firm to conduct a regulatory and value chain assessment of the fertilizers produced, imported and sold to farmers in Myanmar, which must include, but is not limited to: (a) assessment of the overall regulatory framework (registration, licensing, etc.); (b) sector profile of producers, importers, distributors, retailers and dealers; (c) product flow (to end users) through the value chain, at formal and informal entry points, to determine where the potential risks are regarding quality, manipulation and usage of fertilizer; and d) develop a capacity building program to fortify risk management systems (public and private sector) in fertilizer quality.

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET
  - New Productivity, Income and Quality Improvement in Myanmar Agriculture Sector

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-22T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237769</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Assessment of Fertilizer Regulatory and Value Chain Environment in Myanmar</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MM</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Myanmar</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465545</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237769</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465546</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237769</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3934</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">New Productivity, Income and Quality Improvement in Myanmar Agriculture Sector</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59695</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59696</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59697</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59698</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>