<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237960</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-10T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-27T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Assignment Description 
This assignment is to prepare a comprehensive Bridge Design Manual for Sri Lanka integrating climate change risks, in a manner that it can be used by a practicing engineer to be able to design a bridge with traffic, hydrology, hydraulics, geotechnical &amp; structural considerations, reflecting local conditions that is resilient when it comes to climate change and seismic considerations. 
The consultants work will broadly consist of following key parts: 1) review the existing bridge design manual and other relevant documents; 2) review available traffic loading data to propose suitable and practical design parameters; 3) Establish hydrological &amp; hydraulic consideration to be addressed in designing river bridges; 4) Review the geotechnical investigations required and propose new techniques where deemed necessary to enhance climate and seismic resilience; 5) Demonstrate the practicality of the proposed procedures for identifying the best foundation type/investigation/designs with representative design examples for foundation; 6) Review the substructure &amp; superstructure designs generally adopted and improve the selection and design;7) Review existing construction practices and formworks adopted and discuss/propose alternative practices; 8) Discuss advantages and disadvantages of continuous construction with recommendation for usage, emphasizing on possible methods of achieving continuity using precast components with additional design considerations required with examples.9) Review the bridge accessories adopted currently and improve/introduce them if deemed necessary with sample calculations where required to demonstrate their applicability with respect to loads &amp; durability. 10) Review and propose possible new technologies and materials to enhance the bridge design and climate change consideration into bridge design; 11) Suggest/establish procedure for managing the design process and the Central/Provincial Design offices in a manner to enhance efficiency &amp; effectiveness in Design of Bridges to suit the Bridge stock in general;11) Review existing launching methods and formwork systems adopted/practiced  and discuss/propose various launching practices and form and false work adoptable for local conditions/designs with design considerations required for different bridge types.

ELIGIBILITY
Eligibility restrictions apply:
	The firm shall demonstrate substantial consulting experience in developing bridge design manual, bridge design, bridge construction, and integrating risks and uncertainties around climate change into bridge design. 
	The firm shall have a least 25 years of international professional experience with at least 10 years of managerial experience in projects of a similar nature and magnitude. Experience of working in Sir Lanka would be an added advantage. 
The firm for this task should include the following key members in the team:
The Consultants team to undertake this project shall comprise, as a minimum, a Design Team Leader, a Structural Engineer and a Drainage Engineer. Other specialists, technicians, support and administrative staff may be required as necessary to fulfill the requirements of this TOR.
Team Leader: The Team Leader should be a senior civil engineer with at least 25 years international professional experience with at least 10 years of managerial experience in projects of a similar nature and magnitude. At least 15 years of experience in bridge design involving different types of bridges and bridge construction. Experience of working in Sri Lanka on projects financed by multilateral development banks will be an advantage. The Team Leader will:
	Direct the team in all matters relating to provision of the services;
	Ensure that the Project is designed to be implemented in accordance with this TOR;
	Lead the team on preparation of documents including advising the Road Development Authority on required matters;
	Ensure all reporting required by the Road Development Authority and World Bank is fully and punctually delivered;
	Undertake all tasks consistent with leading a team in fulfilling the TOR.
Structural Engineer: The Structural Engineer shall be a senior engineer with at least 15 years of professional experience in bridge engineering and construction.  The Structural Engineer will:
	Assess the adequacy of current standards in terms of structural design;
	Contribute to preparation of revised documents.
Drainage Engineer: The Drainage Engineer shall be a senior engineer with at least 15 years of professional experience in hydraulic engineering.  The Drainage Engineer will:
	Assess the adequacy of current standards in terms of drainage design;
	Provide an assessment on the impact of climate change on hydraulic design standards;
	Contribute to preparation of revised manuals.

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals). The Expression of Interest should include a list of past similar studies, and a list of studies done in Sir Lanka and Asia. Please note that the total size of the EoI should be less than 10 pages. Prospective Consultants are kindly requested to respect this limit as evaluators may not review information provided beyond 10 pages.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-27T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237960</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Bridge Design Manual for Sri-Lanka: Integrating Climate Change Risks.</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">LK</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Sri Lanka</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465958</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237960</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465959</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237960</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3205</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Resilient Transport Infrastructure Program</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59825</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59826</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59827</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59828</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>