<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237230</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-27T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-14T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
World Banks Global Energy Practice invites firms/consortiums to submit an expression of interest to undertake a technical assistance project that will inform and support the dispatch strategy of the Panamanian, Costa Rican, Nicaraguan, Honduran, Guatemalan and El Salvadorian Power Dispatch Centers to integrate VRE technologies in each country main power system, taking advantage of state-of-the-art forecasting technologies and the latest renewable integration techniques. The study will analyze the stability of each countrys power system as a whole, with special focus on the impact of PV and wind energy, considering the inherent variability of these sources, the characteristics of each countrys main power system as well as the regulatory frameworks. It will also focus on streamlining VRE integration into dispatch decisions by means of a new dynamic reserve-dimensioning methodology and software.

This assistance is divided into four main activities which, as a whole, will estimate the potential associated costs and CO2-equivalent emissions saved from VRE integration in the relevant countries Power Systems; identify critical actions and areas of investment needed in the Power System which will help stabilize the national and regional grids and reduce power outages if national VRE targets are met; provide recommendations to optimize the integration of VRE on the economic, technical and regulatory side; improve individual power systems VRE forecasting and spinning reserve dimensioning capabilities leveraging readily available data in each power system and state-of-the-art forecasting technologies; and assess control equipment needs to fully-integrate VRE into power systems operations using world class control technologies. The tasks included in each individual activity are as follows:

ACTIVITY I: Techno-economic implications of VRE integration
i)	Analyze key technical and economic issues related to the integration of VRE technologies in the power grid.
ii)	Analyze the requirements needed to comply with the regional and national grid codes and provide additional measures to be adopted in these codes to allow a sound integration of VRE into the grid.
iii)	Recommend optimized dispatch operation procedures to manage new VRE additions, and determine the additional cost to be incurred (e.g., grid costs, secondary reserve, impact on economic dispatch, etc.)scaling-up current reserve requirements according to the new VRE capacity and the CO2-equivalent emissions saved with a successful integration of new VRE technologies using an economic dispatch model.
iv)	Propose a methodology to dynamically determine need for spinning reserves as a function of the expected hourly demand and VRE output, taking into account available sources of real-time meteorological information and state-of-the-art forecasting technologies. The parameters used by this methodology will be calibrated using the historical variability of demand and VRE resources recorded in the system. 
v)	Assess the ability of the current system to dynamically calculate and provide the required level of reservesbased on the new methodology proposed, and determine the additional capacity necessary to fulfill reserve requirements as well as its cost.
vi)	Estimate the potential economic benefits of dynamically determining spinning reserve needs, as described in iv), compared to integrating VRE capacity using current practices, as described in iii).
vii)	Identify the potential transmission bottlenecks and provide a high-level assessment of the investments required in the grid and in AGC reserve capacity additions to cope with targeted VRE penetration rates, and the associated cost. In those countries where a transmission expansion exercise has been undertaken (i.e., Panama and El Salvador), the consultant will critically assess the technical and economic feasibility of the plan, with especial emphasis on the value added by each of the lines included in the plan.  
ACTIVITY II: Development of a dynamic VRE forecasting and reserve dimensioning software
viii)	Develop a software solution compatible with the existing systems that receives real-time meteorological forecasts and real-time demand data (if available) to dynamically forecast VRE output and demand based on state-of-the-art forecasting technologies, integrates demand forecasts, and estimates spinning reserve needs based on the procedures proposed in iii) and the new methodology proposed in iv). 
ACTIVITY III: Expert assessment of existing VRE control systems and equipment needs
ix)	Assess by means of one three-day mission per country the adequacy of existing VRE monitoring and control equipment, its ability to integrate the VRE forecasting and reserve-dimensioning software solution, and the equipment needs to support a VRE monitoring and control system fully-integrated with dispatch decisions based on world-class control technologies. 
ACTIVITY IV: Regional VRE integration analysis
x)	Assess how the inclusion of each countrys grid in the regional system can accommodate an increasing penetration of VRE technology. In this context, evaluate the coordination of activities at the regional level, in order to optimize the penetration rate of VRE in each countrys grid.

The analysis will consider a time frame spanning five years beyond the commencement of the assistance, and account for current and future demand needs and expected capacity additions in the focused period (2017-2022). 

The following final deliverables (along with supporting materials, including national grid models in electronic format and power point presentations) will be produced by the Consultant(s): 
1. VRE integration report comprising all the analytical outcomes resulting from Activity I.
2. VRE forecasting and reserve dimensioning software with accompanying user manual resulting from Activity II, and technical training to technical teams using the software.
3. Technical report describing the findings and recommendations resulting from Activity III.

This scope of work defines the framework of the assignment. However, the specifics for the different countries will be set out in their respective TORs, according with local needs, available information and previous studies.  The activities included in the scope of work will be performed in collaboration with the system operator from each individual country, who will provide access to the necessary data.  

The work will be divided in phases, each of which will address Activities I, II and III for a subset of the countries, and a final phase which will address Activity IV at a regional level. Some of the tasks included in Activity I have already been completed for some countries and will be out of the scope of this assistance. The relationship of tasks that have already been completed and tasks that are covered by the scope of this assistance are reflected in Table I.(Please see attachment).

The first phase of this technical assistance (Phase I) will include tasks within Activity I for Panama and El Salvador, and tasks within Activity II and III for Panama, El Salvador and Honduras. The estimated budget for Phase I of the assistance is USD 300,000. Activities I, II, and III for the remaining countries will be covered in a second phase (Phase II), which will be budgeted at USD 300,000. Accordingly, the total budget for Phase I and Phase II of this assistance including all the activities outlined for the 6 countries would amount to USD 600,000. Phase III has not been budgeted yet.

The cost of these meetings transport, lodging, per diem, and any other will be included as part of the financial proposal and therefore borne by the contractor.

The present selection process seeks to contract firms/consortiums exclusively for Phase I of this technical assistance, with a possibility to extend the contract beyond Phase I, upon completion, to the subsequent phases of the assistance. 


ELIGIBILITY

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm/consortium.

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS

The World Bank now invites eligible firms/consortiums to indicate their interest in providing the services generally described above. Interested firms/consortiums must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals). Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB. Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms/consortiums are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be no more than 25 pages and should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES

Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms/consortiums will be formally invited to submit proposals.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-14T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237230</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>6C Scaling-Up VRE Integration in CA: TECHNICAL ASSISTANCE TO INTEGRATE VARIABLE RENEWABLE ENERGY TECHNOLOGIES IN THE ELECTRICITY GRID OF CENTRAL AMERICAN COUNTRIES</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY/><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">464173</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237230</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">464174</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237230</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3719</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Sustainable Green Growth in Central America</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">464175</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237230</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A4010</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">50</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Sustainable Green Growth in Central America</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59271</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59272</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59273</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59274</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>