<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237097</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-27T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-13T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1237097 - MIDLINE SURVEYS FOR THE IMPACT EVALUATION OF COMMUNITY LED TOTAL SANITATION (CLTS) CAMPAIGN IN RURAL PUNJAB

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The World Bank seeks the services of an economic advisory or development consulting firm for carrying out comprehensive midline surveys in rural areas of Punjab, India. These surveys will be used to accurately assess the impact of the community level sanitation interventions under Swachh Bharat Mission Gramin (SBM-G) on household sanitation behaviour in the beneficiary communities. More specifically, the evaluation seeks to answer the following questions: What is the effect of CLTS campaign on hygiene behavior? What is the effect of CLTS campaign on toilet construction and use? What is the effect of the interventions on health, education and satisfaction with quality of life? What is the effect of intensive school awareness programs (both primary and proposed mid-school awareness programs) on toilet use? What is the effect of intensive follow-up and vigilance post toilet construction on toilet use? What is the effect of availability of piped water connection to house on toilet use? What is the effect of variation in village level toilet coverage and usage on individual and community health (Sanitation externality)? In addition, the SaniFOAM framework will be used to identify factors supporting and working against achievement and sustainability of behavior change and drawing policy lessons for future implementation of sanitation program in Punjab

The purpose of this consultancy is to develop, implement and produce various components of the data collection needed for analyzing sanitation behavior and measuring the impacts of sanitation interventions under SBM-G. Following survey instruments will be implemented under this assignment: i) Household surveys in 520 rural communities in Punjab covering 12,130 households that have already been identified during the baseline survey; ii) Surveys of around 3000 migrant farm workers; (iii) Community surveys to collect detailed information on development activities undertaken in the communities including SBM-G interventions; iv) School surveys to document various sanitation awareness campaigns and other sanitation/hygiene related activities undertaken at the school level; and iv) Focus group discussions. Community-wise costing data related to SBM-G interventions will have to be collected/estimated from the projects Management and Information System (MIS). The firm will be responsible for implementing the data collection activities and delivering quality data according to the expectations, protocols and timeframe defined by the World Bank and the impact evaluation team. The selected firm is going to work under the direct supervision of the World Bank impact evaluation team in the Global Water Practice. 

The selected firm shall possess the following qualifications: i) A legal status recognized by Indian Government, enabling the organization to perform the above-mentioned tasks; ii) Demonstrated experience of organizing large scale household surveys within the past ten years (experience in developing this in India and in Punjab is a plus); iii) Demonstrated capacity and experience in planning and organizing survey logistics; iv) Good network of experienced enumerators, supervisors, and data entry clerks; v) Demonstrated strong capacity in data management and statistics; and vi) Previous experience in impact evaluation.

The World Bank now invites eligible consulting firms to indicate their interest in providing the services. EOIs should include a summary of firm profile and capability, snapshots of relevant experience for the task including assignments on designing and implementing household surveys and short biographies of staff who might be working on this assignment. EOIs are strictly limited to 20 pages in length including all attachments.
	
This assignment will be administrated by the Washington DC office of the World Bank in close collaboration with the World Bank office in New Delhi and the projects counterpart in the Government of Punjab, India. The consulting firm will be selected in accordance with the procedures set out in the World Banks Guidelines: Selection and Employment of Consultants by World Bank Borrowers, May 2004, Revised October 1, 2006 &amp; May 1, 2010.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-13T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237097</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>MIDLINE SURVEYS FOR THE IMPACT EVALUATION OF COMMUNITY LED TOTAL SANITATION (CLTS) CAMPAIGN IN RURAL PUNJAB</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">463827</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237097</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">463828</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237097</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF017107</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">IN - WASH - Kerala - IE on Rural WSS</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59161</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">A legal status recognized by Indian Government, enabling the organization to perform the above-mentioned task</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59162</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Demonstrated experience of organizing large scale household surveys within the past ten years (experience in developing this in India and in Punjab is a plus)</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59163</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Demonstrated capacity and experience in planning and organizing survey logistics</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59164</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Good network of experienced enumerators, supervisors, and data entry clerks</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59165</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Demonstrated strong capacity in data management and statistics</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59166</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Previous experience in impact evaluation</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>