<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237083</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-02-24T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-13T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The Government of India has prioritized rural sanitation under the Swachh Bharat Mission (SBM) Clean India Campaign with a prime objective of making India Open Defecation Free (ODF) by 2019. To support achievement of SBM Grameen (rural) goals, the World Bank provides a USD 1.5 billion loan to the Government of India. In addition, a Technical Assistance (TA) program has been initiated, to strengthen SBM (G) program delivery institutions at the national level, and in select states with high number of people practicing open defecation such as Rajasthan, Uttar Pradesh, Bihar, Jharkhand, and Haryana.

Concurrent assessments of SBM (G) have identified an urgent need of strengthening training capacity in the states to develop sufficient human resource capacity at the district and block levels to design and implement successful district-wide ODF campaigns, which covers a range of issues including community planning, behavior change communication and technology options. 

Therefore World Bank Group plans to engage a consultant firm or consortium of firms to develop technical training capacity in the area of facilitating ODF campaign in select states. The selection of states will be based on demand from the states where the Bank has existing engagements on rural sanitation. 

While detailed and specific scope of work will be shared during the RFP stage to the short listed firms, the generic scope of work is given below.  

1.Improve or develop training modules and tools. The firm shall ensure availability of high quality training modules and tools by improving existing modules in consultation with Banks TA team and other stakeholders. The modules and tools shall cover areas such as community led approaches, participatory approaches for sanitation, behavior change communication and technology options of toilets. It is expected that there will be two or three different modules targeting motivators, government officials, and technical service provides working at the block and district levels. 

2.Support selection of training institutions  governmental, non-governmental, and private sector  from select states of India/ from the empaneled agencies at the Ministry level in consultation with government stakeholders and the World Banks task team. 

3.Design and facilitate a training of trainers programs for all selected training institutions: systematic training of a group of master trainers of the institutes shall be facilitated to equip them to roll out  the training modules at scale. 

4.Provide intensive hand-holding support to the selected training institutions to strengthen institutional capacity and facilitate training programs at scale in a sustained manner. This will include providing on the job training of resource persons of the selected training institutes, quality control, additional training, marketing support, and so on. 

5.Support the state governments in strategic deployment of training resources so developed to reach the community, and monitoring the quality of activities implemented by such agencies, to improve scaling up of sanitation outcomes. Help the states to establish systems and procedures to track / monitor these aspects. 


Interested consultant firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, with MAXIMUM SIX PAGES(excluding attachments), electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html).

NOTES: 
(1)Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.
(2)Terms of Reference including duration of the assignment, payment terms and specific deliverables/outputs will be shared to the short listed firms as part of Request for Proposal (RFP)</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-13T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237083</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>DEVELOPING TRAINING CAPACITY TO SUPPORT SUSTAINABLE ODF CAMPAIGNS UNDER SWACHH BHARAT MISSION  GRAMIN (SBM-G), INDIA</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">463793</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237083</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">463794</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237083</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A2034</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">WSP MDTF for SBM -support to selected states (P158645)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59141</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1. Proven knowledge and experience in developing capacity building programs and training tools.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59142</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2. Experience in building capacity of stakeholders on participatory rural appraisal (PRA) , community led total sanitation (CLTS), sanitation technologies and behavioral change communication (BCC).</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59143</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3. Proven experience of working with government systems, in the relevant sectorial and geographical context.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59144</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4. Successful experience of building institutional capacity and handholding/incubating start-ups and other organizations.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59145</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5. Proven ability to mobilize highly skilled human resources in the areas of BCC, Community led and participatory approaches for rural development,    sanitation technology options, capacity development and institutional building.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>