<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237300</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-01T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-15T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>IFC is engaged in supporting urban rail transit investments across a number of metropolitan municipalities in Turkey. As part of this engagement, IFC plans to work with urban rail transit operators to help them benchmark and improve their operational and safety performance. 

The Assignment will be funded by IFCs ECA Cities Platform and will be supervised by the IFC Transport and Cities teams. 

Objective of the Consultant Assignment: 

Is to benchmark the Operational and Safety Performance of Tramway/LRT systems in Turkey, against good global practice comparators, identify the main areas for improvement, and develop a set of actionable recommendations for implementation. 

Indicative Scope of Work:

Will include inter alia the following tasks:

1. Review operational and traffic safety and accessibility of a specific tramway network (tbd), including review of emergency response and preparedness management and tram drivers training and qualification program. Identify a small works program (including indicative bill of quantities and budgetary cost estimates) to retrofit existing tram stations to improve accessibility for users with special needs, safety of pedestrian road crossings &amp; safety of nearby road intersections involving other vehicles to appropriate industry standards. 

2. Develop a set of key performance indicators for Tramway and Light Rail Transit (LRT) Operations focusing on accessibility, operational efficiency and safety, building on past work done in this field. 

3. Work with the urban rail transit operators industry association in Turkey, and individual operating entities, as appropriate, to populate the data base with historical performance of Tramway/LRT systems [primarily at-grade systems with ridership between 40,000 and 200,000 pax/weekday on average] in Turkey, but including at least 5 comparators [Istanbul, plus at least 4 from among Konya, Eskisehir, Kayseri, Samsun, Ankara, Bursa, and any others]. Also assemble performance data from at least [3] broadly similar, good practice comparator systems from Europe and other industrialized countries, based on public data sets, literature surveys, own sources, and direct correspondence with concerned entities including consultation with relevant World Bank colleagues. 

4. Based on the data collected, adjust or replace as needed any performance indicators for which not enough information is available (including use of alternative proxy indicators which are easier to collect, and more comparable across cities and countries) to construct a meaningful sample for analysis. Propose a suitable frequency for reporting of such indicators Flag possible outliers which distort the analysis. Summarize proposed indicators, the data collected and preliminary benchmarking in an EXCEL spreadsheet for IFCs initial review.

5. Prepare a draft report (a) assessing adequacy of municipality tramway company (tbd) emergency response and preparedness management, accident reporting system and tram drivers training and qualification program; and proposing practical improvements ; (b) analyzing the results of the Performance Survey and benchmarking exercise. The report should (i) describe how the operational and safety performance have evolved over time since start of operations and 	particularly what have been the main traffic accident types and causes; (ii) compare the main performance indicators across systems and identify top performing systems within Turkey and from 	among the comparator



6. Discuss the draft report with IFC and incorporate any comments.

7. Assist IFC in presenting the findings of the analysis in Turkish. In consultation with IFC, incorporate any feedback from the report and its recommendations. Furthermore engage with a specific transport company (tbd) on the following: (i) discuss the findings of the Survey; (ii) debate the probable causes of main performance gaps; and (iii) explore partnerships with leading performers to promote staff exchanges and know-how transfer across cities and countries. 

8. Based on the final report and its recommendations, assist IFC to agree with the Metropolitan Municipality (tbd) on an Action Plan for performance improvement.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-15T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237300</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Tramway/LRT Systems Performance Survey and Benchmarking</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">TR</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Turkey</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">464337</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237300</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">464338</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237300</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1554</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Austria - ECA Cities Platform</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59331</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Consulting firm with an appropriately qualified Operational Specialist of Rail transit systems international consultant (Team Lead) with extensive [15+ years] global experience in Tramway/LRT systems planning and operations in Europe and international. 
A Traffic Engineer/Planner (Turkish), with at least 10 years of experience in urban transit design.
An individual consultant Turkish, with contacts/prior working experience [5+ years] with Turkish Municipalities operating Tramway/LRT systems.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>