<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237773</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-08T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-20T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW
Assignment Title: 1237773 - Short Term Consultant for Waste to Energy Scale up Project in Bangladesh

Assignment Countries:
- Bangladesh

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
IFC is now looking forward to hire one Short Term Consultant (STC) for making a sectoral analysis on the farm waste management scenario in Bangladesh with the primary focus on adoption of waste to electricity generation technology.

SCOPE OF WORK:
The scope of work is designed for procurement of consultancy service for a sectoral analysis of the poultry and dairy waste management scenario in Bangladesh with the primary focus on practicality of adopting waste to energy technology in managing the farm waste. The analysis will be centered on farms that are already using the bio gasification technology and the challenges that the adoption of waste to energy programs present for the farms in the context of Bangladesh. Details responsibilities for the consultant will include but are not limited to the following tasks:

 Make a comprehensive secondary analysis on the biogas based electricity generation status in Bangladesh based on IDCOL, IFC and other programs
 Meet relevant stakeholders to validate data findings on the current status of the sector and potentials of such projects in Bangladesh
 Make adequate visits to poultry and dairy farms (a range of minimum 7 to 10 farms), in particular 100,000 birds or more sized farms or equivalent, to assess waste to energy technologies that are already commissioned in these farms
 Prepare a technology summary based on field findings 
 Compare field findings with the standard technology options that are being used in developed countries
 Validate the enabling environment and regulatory support that are available for promoting this technology in Bangladesh 
 Recommend a way forward for the biogas to electricity sector to grow within Bangladesh

ELIGIBILITY
The responses will be reviewed and short-listed according to the following criteria:
 Advanced degree in engineering, business or applied sciences with at least 8 - 10 years of work experience in similar projects; Preference will be given to candidates with a background in agriculture, renewable energy, technology marketing, and waste management related sectors. 
 Strong private sector and business development understanding is crucial.
 Excellent research, analysis and writing skills.
 Ability to think strategically and rapidly analyze and integrate diverse information from varied sources. 
 Should be able to communicate effectively and be fluent in oral and written English.

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-20T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237773</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Short Term Consultant for Waste to Energy Scale up Project in Bangladesh</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">BD</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Bangladesh</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465547</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237773</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465548</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237773</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF018788</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Waste to Energy Engagement</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>