<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237572</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-03T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-16T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1237572 - Model of Analysis of Energy Demand (MAED) Survey and Analysis of Consumption Patterns in Kenya

Assignment Countries:
  - Kenya

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The main objectives of the proposed assignment are to undertake a survey among households,  industrial, and commercial consumers and collect MAED specific data; and to assess the current energy consumption patterns of households and the commercial/industrial sectors in Kenya in order to have useful primary data for policy and regulatory decision-making.

The World Bank, with support from the Energy Sector Management Assistance Program (ESMAP), is seeking to hire a consulting firm (the Consultant) to assist GOK in conducting a Model of Analysis of Energy Demand (MAED) Survey and in the preparation of a comprehensive study and analysis of consumption patterns in Kenya.

FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - Kenya Geospatial Plan
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:
[Please type list of restrictions]

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW
Technical and Analytical Energy Advisory Services: Conducting a Model of Analysis of Energy Demand (MAED) Survey and Analysis of Consumption Patterns in Kenya
Assignment Countries: Kenya

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION
Kenya has announced an ambitious target of achieving 70% access by 2017 and universal access to electricity by 2020, with due consideration to enhancing shared prosperity, and not leaving behind traditionally underserved rural populations. While access to electricity service in Kenya has increased rapidly from 23 percent in 2009 to an estimated 50 percent today - exceeding the average rate of access to electricity in Sub-Saharan Africa of 35 percent - meeting coverage targets in an efficient and effective manner and within the time frame set by the Government of Kenya (GOK) requires systematic planning for generation and transmission capacity expansion, grid densification and extension, and off-grid electrification.

As such, Kenyas Least Cost Power Development Plan (LCPDP) is updated annually by a technical committee of the Ministry of Energy and Petroleum (MoEP). This activity consists of a load forecast, generation optimizations and transmission simulations for the medium to long term. While various tools have been used to undertake each of these tasks, the committee has been incapacitated by lack of primary data in the format that would make it accurate and reliable, particularly on load forecasting.

In view of the overriding influence demand forecasts have on the output of the planning process of the power industry, including the least-cost geospatial electrification plan and the LCPDP, it is considered imperative to invest in the development of credible and reliable demand forecast datasets in order to generate dependable demand forecast results for sector planning throughout the country  covering both grid and off-grid areas.

The main objectives of the proposed assignment are to undertake a survey among households,  industrial, and commercial consumers and collect MAED specific data; and to assess the current energy consumption patterns of households and the commercial/industrial sectors in Kenya in order to have useful primary data for policy and regulatory decision-making.

The World Bank, with support from the Energy Sector Management Assistance Program (ESMAP), is seeking to hire a consulting firm (the Consultant) to assist GOK in conducting a Model of Analysis of Energy Demand (MAED) Survey and in the preparation of a comprehensive study and analysis of consumption patterns in Kenya.  

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.). Responses must not exceed 20 pages.

Qualification Criteria
1. Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment (mandatory).
2. Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.
3. Provide information on their core business and years in business.
4. Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.

Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. The consultants will be shortlisted and selected in accordance with the procedures set out in the World Banks Guidelines: Selection and Employment of Consultants by World Bank Borrowers, May 2004, Revised October 2006.

The interested firms should submit their EOIs in English to World Bank Groups E-Consult System https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html by March 17, 2017. In case of any difficulty accessing the system or to obtain any clarifications regarding the assignment, the firms can contact Sudeshna Banerjee, Lead Energy Specialist (E-mail: sgbanerjee@worldbank.org) and Rhonda Jordan-Antoine, Energy Specialist (E-mail: rjordan@worldbank.org).</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-16T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237572</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Model of Analysis of Energy Demand (MAED) Survey and Analysis of Consumption Patterns in Kenya</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">KE</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Kenya</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465054</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237572</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A3266</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Kenya Geospatial Plan</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465053</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237572</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59525</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59526</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59527</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59528</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>