<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237489</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-03T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-04-03T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Assignment Description

The World Bank Group (WBG) Local Investment-friendly Environment (LIFE) Project in Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH) is supporting local authorities in strengthening competitiveness and boosting private sector growth by: (1) Reducing the regulatory burden at the local level; (2) Closing the regulatory implementation gap; (3) Advancing the transparency in regulatory service delivery, and (4) Increasing investments through generating, facilitating and retaining investors in the country. The scope of the LIFE Project includes implementation of the Business Registration One-Stop-Shop Information System in BiH. The System will enable online registration of companies in Republika Srpska (RS), Federation BiH (FBiH) entities (Entities hereinafter), and Brcko Disctrict in Bosnia and Herzegovina with harmonized business registration processes.

The purpose of this assignment is to design and implement the Business Registration 
Information System (System hereinafter). The System will support: (1) online business registry at Entity level; (2) online reservation of business name; (3) use of electronic signature in business registration and related infrastructure (4) online submission of application for business registration; (5) electronic payment of administrative fees and tracking application status; (6) issuing unique business identifier and business registration process; (7) publication of registered business entity and delivery of registration certificate to applicant; (8) integration to support the post-registration processes including (but not necessarily mean that all of these will be required) opening bank account, VAT registration, fiscalization of cash register and registering employees.  

The assignment will be phased, it will start with design of the System, followed by the the deployment phases in Entities (Republika Srpska and Federation BiH) and Br?ko District. The deployment phases will include delivery of the hardware, migration of data and documents from already established business registration information source hosted in the cloud and trainings for the end-users and administrators of the System. These phases are not inter-dependent, and they can be treated as separate installations for each of the entities, with separate timeline, resources, and requirements.  The post-implementation maintenance and support phase will last for one year following the acceptance of the System.  

The System shall follow modular design applying Service Level Architecture (SOA), with possibility to be tailored to different level of readiness of Entities and Br?ko District (meaning it can mean two designs  a new system design for Federation BiH and Br?ko, while upgrading existing system in Republika Srpska; for example, Republika Srpska already established support for processing business registration cases, and requires modules to enable online applications and issuing registration certificates in electronic form). Consultants shall support having two separate work streams (one for Republika Srpska and second for Federation BiH and Br?ko District) in meeting project objectives for this assignment.  The System will be integrated into the existing e-Government eco-systems in Entities and Br?ko District, including integration with the Interoperability Information System currently being implemented, towards the integrated service delivery approach at the level of Entities and Br?ko District in Bosnia and Herzegovina. 

Objectives

The following goals of establishing the Business Registration One-Stop-Shop (OSS) in BiH are identified: (1) reduce the time for business registration to within three days in both entities for all types of limited liability companies; (2) reduce number of steps to register a company by 50% in Federation BiH; (3) reduce costs of business registration by 15% in both entities; (4) increase the number of newly registered businesses in BiH by15% in 1.5 years after the implementation; (5) improve Doing Business ranking for starting a business in BiH; and 6) increase transparency of business registration in both entities.


Submission Requirements

The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services. Interested consultants must provide evidence indicating that they are qualified to perform the services according to requested Qualification Criteria. The expressions of interest should include the following information:
1.	Describe your company capabilities and experience, and provide two references for implementing enterprise systems in the area of business registry or business licensing one-stop-shop information systems for governments in Central, Eastern or Southern Europe. Submit a copy of your Business Registration or Certificate of Incorporation.
2.	Describe ability to mobilize appropriate staff for the assignment (provide project manager and other 3-4 key personnel to be involved in the project demonstrating their qualifications and experience, e.g. business analysts, programmers, database expert). Vendor does not need to demonstrate local presence at the EOI stage, but technical proposals will require a description of how the vendor will provide client-facing activities and onsite support. 
3.	Provide copies of ISO 27001 and Quality Management System standard ISO 9001 certificates.
4.	Please provide us with Annual Revenues over the last two fiscal or calendar years. 
Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB. Consultants are encouraged to be concise and limit their EOI submission to 25 pages; not including references.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

Notes
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-04-03T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237489</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Call for Expression of Interest for Business Registration Information System for Bosnia and Herzegovina</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">BA</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Bosnia and Herzegovina</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">464850</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237489</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">464851</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237489</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1818</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">DFID - BiH Sub-National Investment Climate Project</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59441</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must be in business for at least five years and completed two projects in the last five years in implementing enterprise systems in the area of business registry or business licensing one-stop-shop information systems for governments in Central, Eastern or Southern Europe, each of value above US$ 1 million.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59442</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must have financial capability and stability to successfully complete the contract. Firm must prove annual income of at least USD 2.5 million for each year in the period of previous three fiscal years.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59443</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must demonstrate capability to provide key client facing staff with sufficient fluency to conduct client meetings, work and provide deliverables in one of official languages in Bosnia and Herzegovina and English.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59444</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must demonstrate local presence or sub-contract with company in Bosnia and Herzegovina to perform key client-facing activities and provide on-going maintenance and technical support.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59445</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">If Firm is entering into a sub-contracting arrangement, then the Firm must confirm that its sub-contractor will meet the following requirements: (1) Subcontractor must have at least three (3) years experience in designing, and implementing similar projects, for government and non-government agencies; (2) the Prime Firm must meet all the qualification criteria and must be able to perform and complete at least 50% of the value of the Contract using its own resources.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">5</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59446</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Firm must be certified according to the Information Security Management System standard ISO 27001 and Quality Management System standard ISO 9001.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">6</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>