<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1237935</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-09T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-16T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>The World Bank and DFID are partnering with the National Planning Commission of the Government of Nepal (GoN) to conduct a three-year panel survey between 2016 and 2018 on household risk and vulnerability in Nepal. The survey will help the GoN identify gaps in the safety net and develop programs to help households cope with shocks.

The objective of this consultancy is to implement the second round of the proposed three wave panel survey. Conditional on performance, it is expected that the contract would be extended to cover the third and final wave.  High quality quantitative data will be collected on household risk and vulnerability. The survey will include modules on consumption, employment, income, health, shocks (e.g., economic or health shocks, natural disasters) experienced in the past year and coping strategies employed (e.g., taking loans, selling assets or reducing food consumption) in order to address the following research questions:

- What significant adverse events (both anticipated and unanticipated) are faced by households during a given year?

- What strategies do households employ, and what systems of informal support do they rely on (ex-ante and ex-post) to cope with these events?

- How are households short and medium term welfare affected by these events?

- What formal government assistance do households receive? Is it sufficient to help them cope?

The planned survey will be nationwide, re-interviewing a sample of 6,000 households. Fieldwork is expected to take place between May and July 2017. A draft version of the survey will be provided to the consultant. The consultant is expected to undertake all relevant activities to successfully administer the survey, including piloting and refining the questionnaire, recruiting and training enumerators, field mobilization, data collection, entry, and processing, under the overall supervision of a World Bank team. Computer Assisted Personal Interview (CAPI) will be used for data collection using the Survey Solutions platform. Final deliverables will be a cleaned survey dataset and supporting documents. 


QUALIFICATION CRITERIA:

Strong and proven experience in research design, quantitative research methods and conduct of large household surveys in Nepal with diverse populations across all three ecological belts. Past experience conducting panel surveys is a plus.
1.	Demonstrated capacity to train and mobilize high quality enumerators nationwide for field survey/data collection implementation in Nepali.
2.	Proven capacity to use CAPI technology for data collection including GIS information.
3.	Experience and capacity to conduct high quality anthropometric measurements of children.
4.	Previous experience working with government departments, international organizations and donors and evidence delivery of timely, high quality outputs for an international audience.

APPLICATION PROCEDURE:

The World Bank invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services by submitting their Expressions of Interest (EOI) in English, electronically through World Bank Group econsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index/html). 
Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services based (description of similar assignments in implementation of qualitative studies, experience in similar conditions and context, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals to comprise the team). EOIs should be no more than 20 pages including all annexes (but excluding CVs).

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eTendering (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html). Following this invitation for EOI, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit technical &amp; financial proposals based on an expanded Request for Proposals (RFP). Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.


CONTACT INFORMATION:

Thomas Walker twalker@worldbank.org
Jyoti Pandey, jpandey@worldbank.org</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-16T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1237935</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Nepal Household Risk and Vulnerability Survey</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">NP</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Nepal</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465906</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237935</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">465907</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1237935</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BBEFO</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">EXTERNALLY FUNDED OUTPUTS</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59791</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59792</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59793</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59794</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>