<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1238119</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-14T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-29T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1238119 - IFC-Cargill Program in Cote d'Ivoire Endline Study

Assignment Countries:
  - Cote d'Ivoire

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

The primary objective of this evaluation are to assess the development impact of the Cargill-IFC programs (ScopeInsight, Coop Academy, and Doni Doni) and to provide information, lessons, and recommendations that can be used to improve the design of future programs.

Specifically, the endline data collection exercise will help address the following key questions of the evaluation:

ScopeInsight:

	How effective has it been at measuring coop performance and what is the linkage between other metrics and those measured by ScopeInsight?

Coop Academy:

	Effect of program on cooperatives performance and management
	Which factors have greater effects on cooperative performance (e.g. finance, members, profitability, volume sourced etc.)
	How has the Coop Academy enabled the coop to improve and impact perception of farmers of their coops?
	Womens role in the cooperatives leadership and subsequent effect on performance of cooperatives
	How effective has the delivery mechanism of the program been?

Doni Doni

	Effect of program on cooperatives financial performance
	Has the leasing of trucks through Doni Doni changed the perception of farmers of their coops?
	How effective has the delivery mechanism of the program been?


Also, the program hopes to have longer-term, indirect effects (of all three programs: ScopeInsight, Coop Academy and Doni Doni) by enabling Cargill and other stakeholders to better and more effectively deliver other programs.  These changes are not directly targeted by the program, but there may be changes for these which shall be examined:

	Effects on sales and productivity of farmers
	Perception of communities in terms of social support

Furthermore, questions regarding efficiency, sustainability and impact, regarding the ScopeInsight, Coop Academy and Doni Doni programs will be answered within this endline evaluation.

Methodology
The evaluation will employ a mix of qualitative and quantitative methodological approaches to the collection of data needed for analysis including, but not limited to:

(1) Desk review
This will include a review of the relevant project documents including supervision reports.  The selected consultants should also review reports and existing literature from cooperative development programs.  In addition, the consultants must review IFCs previous evaluations (or summaries of evaluations) related to farmer training, including IFCs recently completed agri-related meta-evaluation as well as reports of implementing partners

The consultants will also review the data collected through the ScopeInsight diagnostic tool of the cooperatives.  The consultants will engage, through IFC, with Cargill, TNS, and ScopeInsight representatives for additional insights for developing the survey instrument and questions for interviews and Focus Group Discussions.

(2) Interviews &amp; Focus Group Discussions
Face-to-face interviews and Focus Group Discussions will be conducted with the various stakeholders. Only with explicit IFC approval, specific stakeholders may be reached via telephone when in-person interviews are not feasible.  

The evaluation will solicit opinions and viewpoints from a diverse set of relevant actors, including Cargill management (at least two interviews), local traitant representatives (at least three interviews or one Focus Group Discussion), cooperative management from about 20 different cooperatives in each group (Treatment and Control) (particularly focusing on changed financial performance of coops and the drivers of change), local financial institution engaged or planning to engage in agri-financing (at least 3 interviews or one Focus Group Discussion), farmers in both Treatment and Control groups who are not included in the survey (at least 30 interviews or four Focus Group Discussions), local community leaders including local government representatives (at least 10 interviews or two Focus Group Discussions), and other stakeholders and observers.

The consultants may propose a combination of interviews and Focus Group Discussions for different stakeholder groups.  IFC shall approve the final proposed list of interviews and Focus Group Discussions prior to commencement.  

(3) Surveys
Farmer level: Surveys will be conducted with 1159 farmers who are members of the cooperatives included in the Control and Treatment samples that have been determined at baseline data collection.

The identification of Treatment and Control group followed the logic of separating the survey target group of 1159 farmers in two cohorts according to the date of training of their constituent coops. The first cohort of cooperatives trained through the program forms the Treatment group. The last cohort of cooperatives trained is the Comparison group. 

Cooperative level: Financial data will be collected from cooperatives which have participated in the Doni-Doni (truck leasing) and/or the Coop Academy programs to understand the financial impacts of the programs.  The firm is expected to compare current financial performance with years prior to the start of the Doni-Doni program.



FUNDING SOURCE

The World Bank Group intends to finance the assignment / services described below under the following:
  - BANK BUDGET

ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant will be a firm. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible firms to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested firms must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc. for firms; CV and cover letter for individuals).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  Consultants may associate to enhance their qualifications.

Interested firms are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals. Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.

Only those firms which have been shortlisted will receive notification. No debrief will be provided to firms which have not been shortlisted.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-29T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1238119</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>IFC-Cargill Program in Cote dIvoire Endline Study</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">CI</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Cote d'Ivoire</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">466306</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1238119</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59895</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment, especially with regards to data collection and analysis of agricultural value chains in Cote d'Ivoire.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59896</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm, especially with regards to experience in qualitative and quantitative data collection and program evaluation.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59897</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business, especially with regards to experience in qualitative and quantitative data collection and program evaluation.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59898</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff, especially with regards to data collection and analysis of agricultural value chains in Cote d'Ivoire.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>