<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1238350</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-16T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-25T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>SELECTION FOR CONSULTANTS BY THE WORLD BANK GROUP

REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST

Electronic Submissions through World Bank Group eConsultant2
https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html

ASSIGNMENT OVERVIEW

Assignment Title: 1238350 - Financing of early/growth-stage MSMEs / Start-ups  Deep-dive case studies &amp; Developing a detailed business/financial model

Assignment Countries:
  - India

ASSIGNMENT DESCRIPTION

While the venture debt market in India is slowly evolving, there are not too many FIs who have started looking at this space seriously. In addition to few Venture Funds, and a recent focus from some FIs, it is envisaged that more commercial banks can devise newer products such as venture debt on the lines of SIDBIs Startup Assistance Scheme (SAS) which aims to target early-stage MSMEs with a vintage of 1-5 years.
  
The consultant will be responsible to perform the following activities in two Components as described below, with Component 1 resulting in establishing whether there exists a strong business model that could be viable and defining its broad parameters, and Component 2 comprising the theoretical business model and linked scenario analysis.

The WBG/IFC is looking to work with a consultant (individual') to support on specific activities.


TIMELINE:

The deliverables need to be completed in approx. 40-45 days, and the contract will be from 1st April 2017 to 10th June 2017. The expected deliverables (final) should be submitted by End-May 2017.

Given the specific deliverables and time-frame mentioned, the availability of the Consultant to be largely focused on the Project deliverables will be key.


ELIGIBILITY

Eligibility restrictions apply:

Skill-Set Requirements:
The Consultant(s) will be an Individual.
The Consultant should have a diverse and comprehensive skill set including at a minimum:
- Leadership experience in the banking sector, with at least 5+ years in management positions.
- Proven experience and demonstrated knowledge in ventures and equity as well as banking.
- International exposure in Banking or Financial sector and Knowledge and understanding of Development Banking processes and institution policy, Equity/ Mizanine/Venture Funding would be highly valued
- Having good contacts in the Indian Banking eco-system will be important; and will be an added advantage
- Good understanding of the SME Financing market
- Experience working with startups and the startup ecosystem is important.
- Demonstrated ability to develop new product lines, and proven implementation track record.
- Extensive developed network in both banking and venture sector, as well as the startup ecosystem.
- Demonstrated innovative initiatives, and creative solutions.
- Strong communication skills.
- Consultant based out of India will have an added advantage

INDIVIDUAL / FIRM PROFILE
The consultant should be an individual. 

SUBMISSION REQUIREMENTS
The World Bank Group now invites eligible consultants to indicate their interest in providing the services.  Interested consultants must provide information indicating that they are qualified to perform the services (brochures, description of similar assignments, experience in similar conditions, availability of appropriate skills among staff, etc.).  Please note that the total size of all attachments should be less than 5MB.  

Interested consultants are hereby invited to submit expressions of interest.

Expressions of Interest should be submitted, in English, electronically through World Bank Group eConsultant2 (https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html)

NOTES
Following this invitation for Expression of Interest, a shortlist of qualified firms will be formally invited to submit proposals.  Shortlisting and selection will be subject to the availability of funding.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-25T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1238350</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Financing of early/growth-stage MSMEs / Start-ups  Deep-dive case studies &amp; Developing a detailed business/financial model</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>1</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">IN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">India</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">466745</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1238350</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT/></NOTIFICATION>