<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1238003</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-13T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-20T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>REQUEST FOR EXPRESSIONS OF INTEREST
(CONSULTING SERVICES FROM NGOS)
SOCIAL ACCOUNTABILITY SUBPROJECT IN ULAANBAATAR CITY UNDER MASAM PROJECT
Country: Mongolia
Project Name: Mainstreaming Social accountability in Mongolia (MASAM) project
Assignment title: External Evaluation of National Program Implementation Related with Health Knowledge and Awareness Among Children and Youth

1.      BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE
Jointly funded by The Swiss Agency for Development Cooperation (SDC) and the World Bank (WB), the MASAM project (2015 to 2019) has been implemented in 10 aimags and 3 districts in Ulaanbaatar. The goal of the consultancy service is to increase access of citizens to public decision-making processes and quality services through social accountability conducting external evaluation of national program implementations in collaboration of Ulaanbaatar City and its three districts, Bayanzurkh, Chingeltei and Songinokhairkhan.  According to Development policy and planning law (2015), article 20, as part of monitoring and evaluation framework of policy implementation, external evaluation is to be conducted by civil society, professional associations and academia. However, to date, clear methodology and practice has not been identified yet. In order to strengthen the implementation of this law, this is the one of four (4) MASAM subprojects to be piloted in focus two sectors, health and education in Ulaanbaatar city. 

3. SCOPE OF THE WORK 
The consultancy service has a specific objective to evaluate policy implementation of suggested policy programs, namely National program on Health (2010-2021), National program (2nd phase) prevention and control of disease caused by unhealthy habits (2014-2021), related with priority/cross cutting issue on health: Poor health outcomes related with lack of health knowledge and awareness among children and youth. It is expected to be develop sustainable models for external evaluation on policy implementation. The model should consider elements of capacity building for effective application of the model and the mechanisms through which the findings of the external evaluations will feed into the planning of future policy documents (or the adjustment of the current ones) and their implementation arrangements. External evaluation may include following activities:
o	Preparation and design of external evaluation
o	Field work with various stakeholders with specific focus on bringing voice of citizens 
o	Training and involving communities and government representatives in external evaluations
o	Reporting and management response
o	Dissemination and follow up actions to improve actual implementation of the policy
3. QUALIFICATIONS AND SELECTION CRITERIA 
	The consultancy service is open to interested NGOs which meet following essential criteria: 
o	Has at least two years of current /continues/ operational history particularly promoting good governance, transparency, social accountability and public service improvements 
o	Has project implementation experience at least any 3 aimags or/and districts 
o	Has management board and permanent staff team /at least 3 full time staff and part time staff/ and proven professional capacity and experiences
	Proposal that involve different organizations (partnerships among stakeholders, such as professional associations and academia) are highly encouraged. The budget ceiling is as follows: $18,000 for proposal implemented by one organization; $25,000 for proposal submitted by two or more organizations. 
4. CONTRACT DURATION: 
Expected commencement date of contract is May to Sep 2017. 

Interested NGOs should prepare their Expressions of Interest using the enclosed template in English and Expressions of Interest must be submitted electronically at https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html The submission deadline is 18.00pm (local time, Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia), Mar 20, 2017.
Further information can be obtained via email: adorj@worldbank.org; tel: 976-70078231 and scheduled information session (please register via provided email). 


SOCIAL ACCOUNTABILITY SUBPROJECT FOR ULAANBAATAR CITY 
UNDER MASAM PROJECT 
Expression of Interest 
Please submit it electronically at https://wbgeconsult2.worldbank.org/wbgec/index.html before 18.00pm (local time, Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia), Mar 20, 2017.


1. Title of the subproject

2. Primary organization submitting the EOI 

3. Name of representative 

4. Contact number &amp; email of representative 

5. Is this a collaborative effort among different groups? If so, list names of organizations and representatives
1.	  
2.	  
3.	


6. Please describe briefly proposed technical approach and methodology to conduct external evaluation of the chosen program (250 words max)


7. Please describe briefly, the objectives, the proposed activities and expected results (250 words max)



8. Briefly describe how your organizations mission and objectives align with the proposed subproject. Please include previous and current experience in implementing policy research or advocacy, service delivery monitoring and evaluation projects in the health or education sector. (250 words max)


9. Describe your organizations capacity to undertake this proposed activity (e.g, staffing, financial management, technical) or how you propose to build this expertise (e.g., through collaboration, partnerships). (250 words max)</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-20T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1238003</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>External Evaluation of National Program Implementation Related with Health Knowledge and Awareness Among Children and Youth</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MN</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Mongolia</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">466057</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1238003</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">0</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">466058</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1238003</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">TF0A1335</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">Mainstreaming Social Accountability in Mongolia (MASAM)</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59855</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Has at least two years of current /continues/ operational history particularly promoting good governance, transparency, social accountability and public service improvements</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59856</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Has project implementation experience at least any 3 aimags or/and districts</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59857</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Has management board and permanent staff team /at least 3 full time staff and part time staff/ and proven professional capacity and experiences</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59858</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">0</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>