<NOTIFICATION xmlns:SOAP="http://schemas.xmlsoap.org/soap/envelope/" xmlns:WB="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/BPM_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBN="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0" xmlns:WBC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0" xmlns:WBTF="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0" xmlns:WBNA="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Attachment/1.0" xmlns:WBQC="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0"><SELECTION_NOTIFICATION xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Notification/1.0"><SELECTION_ID>1238322</SELECTION_ID><NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID>3</NOTIFICATION_TYPE_ID><TYPE_NAME>Advertise in Bidding Opportunities page</TYPE_NAME><PUBLICATION_DATE>2017-03-16T00:00:00.0</PUBLICATION_DATE><EOI_DEADLINE>2017-03-27T23:59:59.900000000</EOI_DEADLINE><ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT>Madagascar has received a grant from the Forest Carbon Partnership Facility (FCPF) to implement a Reducing emissions from deforestation and forest degradation (REDD+) Readiness plan. The grant allows Madagascar to support several key outcomes: the development of a national REDD+ strategy and associated social and environmental assessment of the strategy, a national forest reference emissions level, a robust and transparent forest monitoring system, a grievance mechanism as well as a system for providing information for how safeguards are being addressed and respected, and a strategy for engagement of the private sector in its REDD+ Program. 

The government of Madagascar recognizes the important role that the private sector can play in encouraging smarter land use and reducing pressure on forests  and can have a pivotal role in scaling-up sustainable practices in emerging markets. The REDD+ program seeks to maximize private sector engagement and financial leverage. Its objective is to partner with private firms to support sustainable commodities growth and redirect market forces towards more sustainable land management practices.

The REDD+ program in Madagascar seeks to engage a range of private actors in targeted landscapes, from multi-national corporates and large national actors, to emerging small and medium enterprises and smallholders. A specific emphasis is placed on engaging smallholders in sustainable practices through increasing their opportunities and support in sustainable production. The program seeks to explore ways to reduce initial barriers for private sector investment in activities that are consistent with the REDD+ approach, and attract further capital and expertise from the private sector, in a highly targeted approach.

To support Madagascar, the World bank is recruiting a firm to Support the development of sustainable agribusiness framework and the elaboration of project idea notes in Madagascar ER-Program area. 

The firm will develop (i) a Sustainable Agribusiness Blueprint, which will include an overall strategy for engaging private sector actors and increasing private investment in sustainable agribusiness (including Non Timber-Forest Products  NTFP) in the ER Program area, considering local, regional, and international markets; and (ii) 10 specific Project Idea Notes from which 3-5 will be further developed into full project proposals for financing and inclusion in the REDD+ jurisdictional program.

The firm will work in close collaboration with the National REDD+ Coordination Board (BNCR) and the World bank team in charge of the project.</ADVERTISEMENT_TEXT><DRAFT_FLAG>0</DRAFT_FLAG><LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE>English</LANGUAGE_OF_NOTICE><ADVERTISE_UNTIL>2017-03-27T23:59:59.0</ADVERTISE_UNTIL><SELECTION_NUMBER>1238322</SELECTION_NUMBER><SELECTION_TITLE>Madagascar - Support for the development of sustainable agribusiness framework and the elaboration of project idea notes in Madagascar ER-Program area.</SELECTION_TITLE><SELECTION_TYPE_ID>2</SELECTION_TYPE_ID><SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID>8</SELECTION_SUB_STATUS_ID></SELECTION_NOTIFICATION><SELECTION_COUNTRY><_><COUNTRY_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">MG</COUNTRY_ID><COUNTRY_NAME xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Country/1.0">Madagascar</COUNTRY_NAME></_></SELECTION_COUNTRY><SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><_><ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">466698</ID><SELECTION_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">1238322</SELECTION_ID><TRUST_FUND_NUMBER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BB</TRUST_FUND_NUMBER><PERCENT_APPLIES xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">100</PERCENT_APPLIES><TRUST_FUND_DESC xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Selection_Trust_Fund/1.0">BANK BUDGET</TRUST_FUND_DESC></_></SELECTION_TRUST_FUND><NOTIFICATION_ATTACHMENT/><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59942</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the technical and managerial capabilities of the firm.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59941</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information showing that they are qualified in the field of the assignment.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">2</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59943</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on their core business and years in business.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">3</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_><_><NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">59944</NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT_ID><CONTENT xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">Provide information on the qualifications of key staff.</CONTENT><ITEM_ORDER xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">4</ITEM_ORDER><MANDATORY xmlns="http://cordys.com/WBGEC/DBT_Notification_Qual_Crit/1.0">1</MANDATORY></_></NOTIFICATION_QUAL_CRIT></NOTIFICATION>